<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>zerodha-amc on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/zerodha-amc/</link><description>Recent content in zerodha-amc on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/zerodha-amc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One year of Zerodha Fund House</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/one-year-of-zerodha-fund-house/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/one-year-of-zerodha-fund-house/</guid><description>This was our first year as India&amp;rsquo;s direct-only AMC, Zerodha Fund House. Our AUM has grown significantly, all without us actively pushing anything.
The good thing about being passive-only is that it aligns the incentives for both the customers and us. For the customers, it means access to good, low-cost products, and for us, it eliminates the risks that have recently made headlines.
Read this post one year of Zerodha Fund House by Vishal Jain</description></item><item><title>Our Liquidcase surpasses Rs 800 crores in AUM</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/our-liquidcase-surpasses-rs-800-crores-in-aum/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/our-liquidcase-surpasses-rs-800-crores-in-aum/</guid><description>Our Liquid ETF (LIQUIDCASE) just about 3 months old, but it has grown phenomenally. The AUM crossed Rs 800 crores, and the volumes have been consistently picking up.
This is India&amp;rsquo;s first Liquid ETF with a growth NAV. Unlike other liquid ETFs, you don&amp;rsquo;t have to deal with fractional units, figure out what your actual return is, and face issues when filing your taxes.</description></item><item><title>Introducing LIQUIDCASE, India's first ETF with a growth NAV</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-liquidcase-indias-first-etf-with-a-growth-nav/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-liquidcase-indias-first-etf-with-a-growth-nav/</guid><description>LIQUIDCASE, India&amp;rsquo;s first ETF with a growth NAV from ZerodhaAMC just listed today with the same symbol. When we were thinking about the product, we wanted to offer something simple where investors didn&amp;rsquo;t have to bother about dividends, taxes etc.
So, the way LIQUIDCASE works is simple: the returns in the ETF will be added to the NAV just like growth mutual funds, and there are no dividends. This makes it easier for you to track your returns, and there are no hassles with fractional units and figuring out your taxes.</description></item></channel></rss>