<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>economy on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/economy/</link><description>Recent content in economy on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Indian fascination with America and it's investment potential</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-fascination-with-america-and-its-investment-potential/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-fascination-with-america-and-its-investment-potential/</guid><description>Most Americans I know with money want to invest in India because they believe they are plateauing as a nation and that we are the future. But somehow, young Indians are still bitten by the bug to travel to America to build their future. This is such a dichotomy.
Credits: The Ken</description></item><item><title>Pollution's impact on Indian Health and Economy</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/pollutions-impact-on-indian-health-and-economy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/pollutions-impact-on-indian-health-and-economy/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s growing evidence to show that air and water pollution increases the risk of type 2 diabetes among Indians.
If the quality of life deteriorates, there will be a tipping point where people just give up and start moving from large cities to places with better living conditions. If this happens, it will cause serious economic damage from reduced tax revenues, falling land values, and further degradation of civic infrastructure among other issues.</description></item><item><title>Financialization of India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financialization-of-india/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financialization-of-india/</guid><description>NSE just announced that there are 15 crore investors registered, of which 8 crore are unique. Much of this growth has come in the last 3–4 years. The pace of financialization is crazy, and this is in no small part thanks to the exchanges, especially NSE. This is vital for India to grow.
A case in point, this year, total Sovereign Gold Bonds (SGB) issued is ~10% of total gold imports.</description></item><item><title>Empowering women to join the workforce is the easiest way to increase economic growth</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/empowering-women-to-join-the-workforce-is-the-easiest-way-to-increase-economic-growth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/empowering-women-to-join-the-workforce-is-the-easiest-way-to-increase-economic-growth/</guid><description>Empowering women to join the workforce is an obvious way to increase our economic growth. Our female labor force participation rate is among the lowest in the world. One thing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make sense of is why our female labor force participation (FLFP), which was in the ~30% range in the 90s, fell to 20% and rose to 24%. We have been discussing this topic on the Rainmatter Grove and and Ashutosh from IndiaDataHub shared something interesting:</description></item></channel></rss>