<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>economy on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/economy/</link><description>Recent content in economy on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/economy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>India’s $3 trillion in idle gold needs smarter financialization.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</guid><description>Indian households hold ~$3 trillion in gold (World Gold Council estimate), sitting idle in lockers. Meanwhile, equity investments fund companies that need capital to grow. We need better ways to financialize this gold beyond just gold loans.</description></item><item><title>What the Jane Street probe tells us about India’s market oversight</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-the-jane-street-probe-tells-us-about-indias-market-oversight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-the-jane-street-probe-tells-us-about-indias-market-oversight/</guid><description>You’ve got to hand it to SEBI for going after Jane Street. If the allegations are true, it’s blatant market manipulation.
The shocking part? They kept at it even after receiving warnings from the exchanges. Maybe this is what happens when you&amp;rsquo;re used to the lenient U.S. regulatory regime. Think about the structure of U.S. markets: dark pools, payment for order flow, and other loopholes that allow hedge funds to make billions off retail investors.</description></item><item><title>India must bet on research and innovation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-must-bet-on-research-and-innovation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-must-bet-on-research-and-innovation/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s amazing that despite all the challenges, we&amp;rsquo;re now the 4th largest economy in the world. Having said that, at the risk of sounding like a spoilsport, GDP comparisons only tell you so much.
When you look at important metrics like productivity, labor force participation, and perhaps most importantly, R&amp;amp;D spending, we have a long way to go. India spends just 0.7% of GDP on R&amp;amp;D, while China spends 2.4%, South Korea 4.</description></item><item><title>Retail buying spree continues</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/retail-buying-spree-continues/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/retail-buying-spree-continues/</guid><description>One of the crazy things about the last five-odd years is that retail investors have consistently been net buyers of equities. Whether they&amp;rsquo;ll continue to buy the dip is anybody&amp;rsquo;s guess. 😬
By the way, if markets fall sharply, investors might stay out of the market for years—just like they did after 2008.</description></item><item><title>Your simple guide to IndiaDataHub’s economic data</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/your-simple-guide-to-indiadatahubs-economic-data/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/your-simple-guide-to-indiadatahubs-economic-data/</guid><description>The expectation was that we would have a better-than-average monsoon this year. But right now, there&amp;rsquo;s a deficit.
Read more about this and more such data.</description></item><item><title>Growing locally with India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/growing-locally-within-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/growing-locally-within-india/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve said this earlier: for India to grow inclusively, wealth has to be created locally. Today, much of the success of homegrown startups goes to investors outside India.
Staying in India and incorporating at home also saves the future hassle of paying huge taxes to flip back. Also, the growing local pools of capital, ever-improving regulations, and the growth of IPO markets have made India a much more attractive destination than it ever was.</description></item><item><title>A few thoughts on this National Startup Day</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-this-national-startup-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-this-national-startup-day/</guid><description>Today is National Startup Day, which was started in 2016 to highlight the contribution of startups to India&amp;rsquo;s economic growth.
We&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way as a country in recognizing and celebrating the success and contribution of entrepreneurs who, in turn, have inspired more people to startup. For a long time, almost everyone in my life told me to get a real job when I was trading and running a business until Zerodha became popular.</description></item><item><title>Indian fascination with America and it's investment potential</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-fascination-with-america-and-its-investment-potential/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-fascination-with-america-and-its-investment-potential/</guid><description>Most Americans I know with money want to invest in India because they believe they are plateauing as a nation and that we are the future. But somehow, young Indians are still bitten by the bug to travel to America to build their future. This is such a dichotomy.
Credits: The Ken</description></item><item><title>Pollution's impact on Indian Health and Economy</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/pollutions-impact-on-indian-health-and-economy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/pollutions-impact-on-indian-health-and-economy/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s growing evidence to show that air and water pollution increases the risk of type 2 diabetes among Indians.
If the quality of life deteriorates, there will be a tipping point where people just give up and start moving from large cities to places with better living conditions. If this happens, it will cause serious economic damage from reduced tax revenues, falling land values, and further degradation of civic infrastructure among other issues.</description></item><item><title>Financialization of India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financialization-of-india/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financialization-of-india/</guid><description>NSE just announced that there are 15 crore investors registered, of which 8 crore are unique. Much of this growth has come in the last 3–4 years. The pace of financialization is crazy, and this is in no small part thanks to the exchanges, especially NSE. This is vital for India to grow.
A case in point, this year, total Sovereign Gold Bonds (SGB) issued is ~10% of total gold imports.</description></item><item><title>Empowering women to join the workforce is the easiest way to increase economic growth</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/empowering-women-to-join-the-workforce-is-the-easiest-way-to-increase-economic-growth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/empowering-women-to-join-the-workforce-is-the-easiest-way-to-increase-economic-growth/</guid><description>Empowering women to join the workforce is an obvious way to increase our economic growth. Our female labor force participation rate is among the lowest in the world. One thing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make sense of is why our female labor force participation (FLFP), which was in the ~30% range in the 90s, fell to 20% and rose to 24%. We have been discussing this topic on the Rainmatter Grove and and Ashutosh from IndiaDataHub shared something interesting:</description></item></channel></rss>