<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>interesting-articles on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/interesting-articles/</link><description>Recent content in interesting-articles on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/interesting-articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alar’s new update makes the dictionary faster and easier to build on</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alars-new-update-makes-the-dictionary-faster-and-easier-to-build-on/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alars-new-update-makes-the-dictionary-faster-and-easier-to-build-on/</guid><description>In 2020, we did something very odd. Well, K (Kailash, CTO) did. He helped open-source Alar, a Kannada–English dictionary. It&amp;rsquo;s a little absurd, considering we&amp;rsquo;re a stockbroking company, but the project itself is one of monumental importance.
The story of how Alar came to be is even more inspiring. It was essentially the life&amp;rsquo;s work of one man: V. Krishna. Alar is the online version of what he had built over 40 years—researching, writing, and cataloguing more than 150,000 Kannada words and 240,000 English definitions, complete with all their attendant details.</description></item><item><title>Indian companies have reported strong Q2 results</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-companies-have-reported-strong-q2-results/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-companies-have-reported-strong-q2-results/</guid><description>3500+ companies have reported earnings, and there&amp;rsquo;s a broad-based recovery across sectors.
&amp;ldquo;Aggregate revenues have risen 8.2% year-on-year, while EBITDA and PAT climbed 14.1% and 16.0%, respectively. Excluding Financial Services, profit growth accelerated to 22.5%&amp;rdquo;
Perhaps this explains why indices are holding up much better than most bears had expected. Hoping this earnings strength sustains 🤞
Data from IndiaDataHub
Link to the article here.</description></item><item><title>The one thing I wish I’d done differently after my stroke</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-one-thing-i-wish-id-done-differently-after-my-stroke/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-one-thing-i-wish-id-done-differently-after-my-stroke/</guid><description>If there’s one thing I wish I had done differently when I was hit by a stroke last January, it would be to go to the hospital immediately, within the Golden Hour (&amp;lt;4.5 hours), instead of thinking I could just sleep it off.
This “nothing will happen to me” attitude is common, especially among those under 50. But the truth is, strokes are rising sharply, up to nearly 30% of all strokes in the last few years, among 30 to 50-year-olds.</description></item><item><title>1929 by Andrew Ross Sorkin is a must-read for anyone in the markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/1929-by-andrew-ross-sorkin-is-a-must-read-for-anyone-in-the-markets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/1929-by-andrew-ross-sorkin-is-a-must-read-for-anyone-in-the-markets/</guid><description>1929 by Andrew Ross Sorkin is a must-read for anyone in the markets—stocks, commodities, or crypto.
He quotes US President Hoover (1929):
“The only problem with capitalism is capitalists. They’re too damn greedy.”
Every crash, 1907, 1929, 1987, 2001 (Dotcom), 2008 (GFC), and so many more, follows the same script.
Greed drives markets higher, inflating bubbles that draw in even those who don’t understand the risks. As euphoria builds, leverage accumulates quietly somewhere in the system: loans, margins, complex derivatives.</description></item><item><title>One year of the Zerodha FLOSS fund</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/one-year-of-the-zerodha-floss-fund/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/one-year-of-the-zerodha-floss-fund/</guid><description>We started FLOSS/fund in 2024 to give up to $1 million annually to support the development of FOSS (free and open-source) projects globally.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what K said in a post reflecting on the past year, making the case for the Indian government also to fund FOSS for strategic tech sovereignty:
&amp;ldquo;Actually, no amount of material resources can enable governments to develop, nurture, and sustain complex, high-quality FOSS projects themselves in the way a community of passionate maintainers can.</description></item><item><title>Open source for tech sovereignty</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-for-tech-sovereignty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-for-tech-sovereignty/</guid><description>Tech sovereignty and self-sufficiency are national conversations now, the world over. Free and open-source software (FOSS) enables just that—tech sovereignty and, at the same time, mutually assured global collaboration and innovation. IndiaAI Mission&amp;rsquo;s recent push for sovereign open-source LLMs is a great example for this. Without FOSS, there would be no Zerodha or the global digital ecosystem as we know it today.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an article by K (Kailash) on the topic from 2021 that&amp;rsquo;s still relevant now.</description></item><item><title>Crypto F&amp;O thrives without clear regulation in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/crypto-fo-thrives-without-clear-regulation-in-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/crypto-fo-thrives-without-clear-regulation-in-india/</guid><description>I hadn’t realised how popular crypto F&amp;amp;O has become.
These Indian crypto platforms seem to be thriving in a regulatory grey zone, and because of lower taxes and extreme leverage in derivatives.
From the Economic Times</description></item><item><title>When wealth turns into domination</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/when-wealth-turns-into-domination/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/when-wealth-turns-into-domination/</guid><description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t realise that lands from Muscat and Oman, the UAE, all the way to Burma were once part of the British Indian Empire. I&amp;rsquo;d always thought of India&amp;rsquo;s partition as only involving India, Pakistan, and Bangladesh.
Shattered Lands by Sam Dalrymple is a must-read for history buffs. And thanks to good genes, I guess. :)
The Anarchy by William Dalrymple is still one of my favourites. It tells the story of how the East India Company came to India to trade, became immensely wealthy, and, in their pursuit of more, became ruthless.</description></item><item><title>Risk management is the real secret behind trading success</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-is-the-real-secret-behind-trading-success/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-is-the-real-secret-behind-trading-success/</guid><description>Interesting experiment by Elm Wealth: 118 finance students were given tomorrow’s WSJ front page 24 hours before the news broke. You’d expect easy profits. Instead, half lost money and 16% went completely bust.
It wasn’t because their predictions were wrong. They called market direction correctly 51.5% of the time. That’s better than chance.
The problem? Position sizing.
Many students bet huge portions of their portfolio on a single trade. Some used 20x, even 60x leverage.</description></item><item><title>One year of The Daily Brief podcast</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/one-year-of-the-daily-brief-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/one-year-of-the-daily-brief-podcast/</guid><description>We started The Daily Brief podcast and newsletter as a random experiment, and for many people, it&amp;rsquo;s become their daily newspaper. On average, over 60,000 to 1 lakh people watch or read The Daily Brief every day.
Almost all of this is because people genuinely enjoy the content and share it with their friends. Honestly, I didn’t expect this when I first asked the team to start a daily podcast. What began as a small idea has now grown into something bigger.</description></item><item><title>The risks of investing in unlisted shares</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-risks-of-investing-in-unlisted-shares/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-risks-of-investing-in-unlisted-shares/</guid><description>A wealth manager approached us recently to buy one of our unlisted companies so that he could sell it at a 50% markup immediately. The popularity of some of these unlisted companies, like NSE, MSEI, Chennai Super Kings, among retail investors, etc., is crazy.
Most investors think they can make easy money by picking these pre-IPO companies, waiting for the IPO, and making big listing gains. But it&amp;rsquo;s not as easy as it sounds, and there are all sorts of risks.</description></item><item><title>The hidden costs of EV transition</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-hidden-costs-of-ev-transition/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-hidden-costs-of-ev-transition/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m not sure most people truly understand the cost of transitioning from ICE vehicles to electric vehicles. Are we just moving pollution from city streets to biodiversity hotspots?
Indonesia (~50% of the world&amp;rsquo;s nickel) strip mines paradise islands. Congo (~70% of cobalt) destroys communities with child labour. China controls the minerals that make EVs possible: 90% rare earths, 75% lithium, 80% tungsten. All of this is powered by coal plants.</description></item><item><title>Making privacy simple at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-privacy-simple-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-privacy-simple-at-zerodha/</guid><description>In the next release, we won&amp;rsquo;t even ask for storage permission. 😬
More context.</description></item><item><title>Take a break from trading</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-a-break-from-trading/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-a-break-from-trading/</guid><description>Good time to follow this advice. Over the next 10 days, there are only 4 trading days. It’s not a bad idea to take a break from trading and recharge. Judging by what’s happening, you’re going to need it. 😬
&amp;ldquo;Trading profitably requires that you monitor the market moods and your psychological moods. When either one is not conducive to trading, it’s best to stand aside and wait for the situation to change.</description></item><item><title>Effects of GLP-1 drugs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/effects-of-glp1-drugs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/effects-of-glp1-drugs/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been following the developments around Ozempic and GLP-1 drugs with some interest for a while, and last week Eli Lilly launched its variant, Mounjaro, in India. Remember, India has the highest number of diabetics, and if current trends hold, 30%+ of Indians will be obese. I don&amp;rsquo;t think we have a good understanding of the second-order effects of these weight loss drugs, but so far, the effects people are reporting are remarkable.</description></item><item><title>Trade tariffs and Global Power</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trade-tariffs-and-global-power/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trade-tariffs-and-global-power/</guid><description>The way Donald Trump has gone about imposing tariffs and making statements about other countries makes it feel like we are all subjects of the &amp;ldquo;US empire,&amp;rdquo; if it wasn&amp;rsquo;t evident till now.
In terms of trade, China today is the largest trading partner for over 120 countries. In terms of financial and military dominance, the US remains the most powerful nation, for now.
The question is, will the stance of &amp;ldquo;America first&amp;rdquo; backfire or not?</description></item><item><title>India and the need for a long-term vision in AI &amp; Innovation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-and-the-need-for-a-long-term-vision-in-ai-innovation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-and-the-need-for-a-long-term-vision-in-ai-innovation/</guid><description>In the 1960s-1970s, India and China had roughly the same per capita GDP. They started their reforms in the 1980s, and by 1990, they had overtaken our per capita GDP. Say what you will about the differences in our worldviews and economic models, but their scientific and technological progress is undeniable across disciplines—DeepSeek is just the latest example.
I saw this chart in an Economist article. It gives you a quick and dirty idea of the progress China has made despite the fact that papers and citations can be gamed.</description></item><item><title>The Flip Side of Easy Loans in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-flip-side-of-easy-loans-in-india/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-flip-side-of-easy-loans-in-india/</guid><description>After the pandemic, there&amp;rsquo;s been a big increase in personal loans and credit card borrowings. The good side of this is the deepening of credit, but the bad side is some people seem to have borrowed too much or borrowed despite not being able to afford it. A lot of these are small ticket loans under Rs 10,000 from fintech apps. I wonder how much of this is due to the incessant spam from these loan apps nudging people to take &amp;ldquo;instant pre-approved&amp;rdquo; loans.</description></item><item><title>The only longevity advice you need</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-only-longevity-advice-you-need/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-only-longevity-advice-you-need/</guid><description>This is brilliant advice from the legendary Edward Thorp, who at 92 is still going strong. The only longevity expert you need to listen to.</description></item><item><title>SEBIs consultation paper on algo trading</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-consultation-paper-on-algo-trading/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-consultation-paper-on-algo-trading/</guid><description>SEBI recently published a consultation paper on algo trading for retail investors.
My understanding of it is it should be ok for savvy traders using APIs for individual trading with some reasonable order limits. But the APIs have to be accessed through only static IPs, but this isn’t hard to get.
But platforms that offer algos or readymade strategies will need to get them approved through the broker. The broker, in turn, has to register all algos and strategies with the exchanges.</description></item></channel></rss>