<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>interesting-articles on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/interesting-articles/</link><description>Recent content in interesting-articles on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/interesting-articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Corporate growth is hitting a plateau</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/corporate-growth-is-hitting-a-plateau/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/corporate-growth-is-hitting-a-plateau/</guid><description>Corporate growth, in both the public and private markets, seems to be plateauing across most sectors. Even in the private markets, in most cases, valuations in the earlier funding rounds were already far over the fundamental value or expected growth of startups, which is why there&amp;rsquo;s hardly any news about funding for later-stage startups.
Read more on the topic by Markets by Zerodha</description></item><item><title>Your simple guide to IndiaDataHub’s economic data</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/your-simple-guide-to-indiadatahubs-economic-data/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/your-simple-guide-to-indiadatahubs-economic-data/</guid><description>The expectation was that we would have a better-than-average monsoon this year. But right now, there&amp;rsquo;s a deficit.
Read more about this and more such data.</description></item><item><title>Japan’s businesses have continued to survive for ages</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/japans-businesses-have-continued-to-survive-for-ages/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/japans-businesses-have-continued-to-survive-for-ages/</guid><description>The number of natural disasters Japan has endured historically is ridiculous, but despite all the challenges many businesses there have thrived. There are maybe some lessons for all of us. From today’s edition of Finshots</description></item><item><title>Pollution's impact on Indian Health and Economy</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/pollutions-impact-on-indian-health-and-economy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/pollutions-impact-on-indian-health-and-economy/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s growing evidence to show that air and water pollution increases the risk of type 2 diabetes among Indians.
If the quality of life deteriorates, there will be a tipping point where people just give up and start moving from large cities to places with better living conditions. If this happens, it will cause serious economic damage from reduced tax revenues, falling land values, and further degradation of civic infrastructure among other issues.</description></item><item><title>Why Zerodha doesn't have a data team</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-doesnt-have-a-data-team/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-doesnt-have-a-data-team/</guid><description>How useful is collecting &amp;amp; analysing tons of data is a question I ask my peers. We have no data team at Zerodha as we believe it doesn&amp;rsquo;t give useful insights &amp;amp; also since we never upsell.
Article &amp;amp; comments on this topic are interesting 😬</description></item></channel></rss>