<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>life on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/life/</link><description>Recent content in life on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>You'll be missed, Mr Munger</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/youll-be-missed-mr-munger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/youll-be-missed-mr-munger/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;I had written this about Mr. Charlie Munger in last year&amp;rsquo;s business update. His ideas have had a tremendous influence on me professionally. You’ll be missed, Mr. Munger. 🖤&amp;rdquo;
I have been reading and listening to quite a bit of Charlie Munger over the last few days. Every time I go down this rabbit hole, I tend to discover more about myself and what I think Zerodha should be. If I had to summarise, I could use some of his quotes (link to full post in comments)</description></item><item><title>Benefits of playing a sport</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/benefits-of-playing-a-sport/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/benefits-of-playing-a-sport/</guid><description>The one thing that has helped me remain sane and deal with the volatility of life is playing a sport regularly. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t just helped me reduce stress and anxiety, but I think it has also improved my cognitive abilities. Also, I&amp;rsquo;m almost forced to make healthier lifestyle choices when playing a sport regularly.
Given the benefits of playing a sport, picking up one If you can is a no-brainer, especially for kids.</description></item><item><title>Age is just a number</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/age-is-just-a-number/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/age-is-just-a-number/</guid><description>Turned 44 today at 14.3% body fat, the lowest I have been. Sharing publicly for accountability, so I don’t slack and revert back to the mean, 🥶and maybe inspire a few folks and remind that age is just a number. 😬
And thanks everyone for the birthday wishes.</description></item><item><title>The downsides of social media</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-downsides-of-social-media/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-downsides-of-social-media/</guid><description>This desire to build large social media followings can be a slippery slope.
People are generally curious about successful &amp;amp; famous people, so it&amp;rsquo;s easier for celebs from movies, sports, etc., maybe even some businessmen 😀, to build a social media presence quickly.
For everyone else, there is always an incentive to be loud, controversial or oversell because that&amp;rsquo;s what gets the attention. The exception to this is people who write and share high-quality things, but this is very hard.</description></item><item><title>Trading advice from Ramesh Damani</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trading-advice-from-ramesh-damani/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trading-advice-from-ramesh-damani/</guid><description>A Tradingqna user pointed to a video of Ramesh Damani where he says, Trading is always done by slip book &amp;amp; not chequebook &amp;amp; asked what it meant. Ramesh explains this other version of maybe the most important rule in trading &amp;amp; life, Cut your losers &amp;amp; Hold on to the winners.
Thanks, Ramesh, for taking the time to share the response to my cold email. 😃 Here is the link to the full post.</description></item><item><title>Beware of crypto and other online scams</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-crypto-and-other-online-scams/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-crypto-and-other-online-scams/</guid><description>Someone I know got scammed &amp;amp; lost money.
It started with a response to a part-time job offer on WhatsApp. The first few tasks were about leaving fake reviews for resorts &amp;amp; restaurants in random places like Peru. ~Rs 30k was transferred to the bank for the tasks completed. A Telegram group was created with others who claimed to do these tasks.
The next task for the group was to trade on a mock crypto platform, following a bunch of rules.</description></item><item><title>No amount of money can buy good health. A few transformational stories from my life</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/no-amount-of-money-can-buy-good-health-a-few-transformational-stories-from-my-life/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/no-amount-of-money-can-buy-good-health-a-few-transformational-stories-from-my-life/</guid><description>Today is World Health Day. Not that we need a day to remind us, but no amount of money can buy good health. Being healthy needn&amp;rsquo;t be complicated; small lifestyle changes can make a huge difference.
I&amp;rsquo;m highlighting some people who&amp;rsquo;ve transformed with such changes in my life.
Venu is the man behind all operations &amp;amp; compliance at Zerodha. From chubby to the hottest compliance head in the world. ;)</description></item><item><title>Fun workout session with the team at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fun-workout-session-with-the-team-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fun-workout-session-with-the-team-at-zerodha/</guid><description>Thanks to all the internal health initiatives, my gut says that Zerodha might be among India&amp;rsquo;s fittest companies. 🙈Putting it here to nudge my peers to also think about it. 😬
Today, some of us from Zerodha &amp;amp; Rainmatter health did an as many rounds as possible (AMRAP) in 25 mins workout with Adnan from Devils Circuit
Here is the workout if you want to attempt this with your team sometime:</description></item><item><title>Meeting our PM Narendra Modi</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/meeting-our-pm-narendra-modi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/meeting-our-pm-narendra-modi/</guid><description>It was an honour to meet our PM Narendra Modi
My new health &amp;amp; fitness goal is to be able to operate at his intensity when I am 72. He spent almost 30 mins late in the night interacting with Nikhil &amp;amp; me, despite all his meetings &amp;amp; travels through the day.</description></item><item><title>Mom ensuring Carnatic music in the family</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mom-ensuring-carnatic-music-in-the-family/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mom-ensuring-carnatic-music-in-the-family/</guid><description>Ajji on the Veena performing with grandson Kiaan on the Mridungam. Ajji ensuring Carnatic music in the family continues to the next generation.</description></item><item><title>Why you should focus on your health</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-you-should-focus-on-your-health/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-you-should-focus-on-your-health/</guid><description>I have spent the last couple of years thinking quite a bit about health. Experimenting with myself and our team, and supporting startups that are trying to help Indians make healthier choices.
A few thoughts on how and why you should focus on your health.
In chasing money goals, it is easy to forget that all the money in the world can’t buy good health. As we grow older, our health determines the quality of life, not money.</description></item><item><title>Cheerful pessimist</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cheerful-pessimist/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cheerful-pessimist/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Is there such a thing as a cheerful pessimist? That’s what I am.&amp;rdquo;
Charlie Munger is one of my favourite businessmen for his brutal honesty. Sharing a few good quotes that I got as a forward. There are learnings for those investing &amp;amp; building a business.</description></item><item><title>Not letting social media consume you</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/not-letting-social-media-consume-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/not-letting-social-media-consume-you/</guid><description>Not getting consumed by social media while trying to build an audience has been one of the toughest things I have done in my life. The dopamine hit from likes &amp;amp; shares is extremely addictive. Social media platforms have done an amazing job of engineering us to feel this way.
I keep reminding myself that if the quality of content goes down, so will that of the audience. To keep in check the need to say something even when there isn&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>The symbolism behind Goddess Lakshmi sitting on a lotus and Goddess Saraswati sitting on a stone</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/symbolism-behind-lakshmi-and-saraswati/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/symbolism-behind-lakshmi-and-saraswati/</guid><description>As we celebrate Laksmi Puja this Deepavali, here&amp;rsquo;s an interesting anecdote.
Lakshmi, the goddess of wealth, sits on a lotus. Saraswati, the goddess of knowledge, sits on a rock.
The symbolism is that money, like a lotus floats &amp;amp; knowledge, like a rock once gained stays forever</description></item><item><title>Importance of health insurance and regular health checkups</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/importance-of-health-insurance-and-regular-health-checkups/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/importance-of-health-insurance-and-regular-health-checkups/</guid><description>Have been getting a lot of questions on selecting health insurance &amp;amp; regular health checkups. It&amp;rsquo;s super important to have adequate health &amp;amp; term insurance. So I asked Shrehith at Ditto, an expert on insurance, to share a few pointers and also answer questions.</description></item><item><title>My wife Seema's cancer journey</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-wife-seemas-cancer-journey/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-wife-seemas-cancer-journey/</guid><description>Seema, my wife, was diagnosed with breast cancer last Nov. She decided to share her journey &amp;amp; learnings till now to create awareness on cancer &amp;amp; the importance of regular health checkups, health insurance &amp;amp; overall health &amp;amp; well being. Happy Women&amp;rsquo;s Day.</description></item><item><title>The benchmark for success the-benchmark-for-success.md</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-benchmark-for-success/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-benchmark-for-success/</guid><description>Maybe it has nothing to do with being founders, &amp;amp; it&amp;rsquo;s just human nature that absolute success isn’t as satisfying as relative success. As you do or make more, you get into bubbles where you benchmark yourself to those who have more, and you want it. So that chase never ends?
It&amp;rsquo;s accentuated with famous folks &amp;amp; successful founders seeking constant validation. It&amp;rsquo;s crazy how people around me think I have answers to all life&amp;rsquo;s problems just because of whatever little success I&amp;rsquo;ve had.</description></item><item><title>Importance of sleep on overall health &amp; well-being</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/importance-of-sleep-on-overall-health-and-well-being/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/importance-of-sleep-on-overall-health-and-well-being/</guid><description>The number of people having severe heart issues in my extended circle is terrifying. The common thread seems to be sleep deprivation, and not nearly enough is spoken about the importance of sleep on overall health &amp;amp; well-being. The problem has gotten worse post-COVID &amp;amp; WFH.
If you, like me, have trouble sleeping because of constant work distractions, triggers from email, news apps, social media, and chats, disconnecting completely—I mean full cold turkey—a few hours before sleep helps significantly.</description></item><item><title>A must watch interview of Rakesh Jhunjhunwala</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/must-watch-interview-of-rakesh-jhunjhunwala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/must-watch-interview-of-rakesh-jhunjhunwala/</guid><description>This RJ chat is a must-watch
The common thing among successful traders &amp;amp; entrepreneurs is to always think in terms of risk to reward. They take a trade—buy a stock or take a business bet—only if they&amp;rsquo;ve made peace with the worst possible outcome
An understanding that leverage (debt) is merciless &amp;amp; a double-edged sword. If at all they need to use leverage, it&amp;rsquo;s only a small portion of their networth.</description></item><item><title>Nature Shows How This All Works</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-things-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-things-work/</guid><description>Nature shows how this all works (markets too) Extreme events in one direction increase the odds of extreme events in the other Small changes compounded for long periods of time are indistinguishable from magic A beautiful read by Morgan Housel</description></item><item><title>In-Principle approval for our AMC</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/made-in-india-cars/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/made-in-india-cars/</guid><description>The new cars from M&amp;amp;M &amp;amp; Tata have to be making each one of us feeling proudFlag of India Finally feels like we can not only beat international cars in the same segment in pricing but also in terms of the look &amp;amp; feel. Just like with apps from new-age Indian technology first businesses.</description></item><item><title>Financial freedom.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-freedom/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-freedom/</guid><description>Financial freedom isn’t X amount. Luxuries soon become necessities, X constantly grows. In a world where everyone is triggering you to borrow &amp;amp; buy what you don’t need, being content &amp;amp; debt-free is true financial freedom. Common sense stuff, rarely said.</description></item><item><title>My favorite song</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-favourite-song/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-favourite-song/</guid><description>I got asked what my favourite song of all time was. So I decided to sing &amp;amp; share it. Peak WFH!</description></item><item><title>Helping people take care of mental health during</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/taking-care-of-yourself/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/taking-care-of-yourself/</guid><description>While we figure ways to help those directly affected by Corona, I think it is also super important that all of us take care of ourselves. We thought we should do something to nudge as many as possible to take some action.</description></item><item><title>Why you shouldn't raise money just because you can</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stupidest-time-for-fintech-firms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stupidest-time-for-fintech-firms/</guid><description>Right now, is probably the stupidest time for fintech firms like @zerodhaonline to be raising money. It is quite crazy the number of folks reaching out &amp;amp; the different deals. We might regret it in the future, but we are not raising &amp;amp; here are the counterintuitive reasons why.
We don’t need the money, so there’s no point in raising money just because someone is ready to give it to you.</description></item><item><title>a career highpoint</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-career-highpoint/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-career-highpoint/</guid><description>Dad&amp;rsquo;s first time on screen. Seeing him so proud is a career highpoint. Super lucky to have parents who stood by through all my stupidity regardless of what people told them, that&amp;rsquo;s how I survived. Until Zerodha, I was always told to go get a real job.</description></item><item><title>Is trading the markets gambling?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-trading-the-markets-gambling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-trading-the-markets-gambling/</guid><description>Is trading the markets gambling? I get asked often. My answer is that yes, you can gamble when trading, just like you can gamble with everything else in life.</description></item><item><title>Downside of working from home</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/downside-of-working-from-home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/downside-of-working-from-home/</guid><description>This year has been ridiculous, I now have &amp;ldquo;spending time with my 5-year-old son&amp;rdquo; scheduled on my calendar. WTF! I was wondering if I was the only insane one until I read this article. https://moretothat.com/the-omnipresence-of-work &amp;ldquo;We are now living amidst the omnipresence of work. Even if we aren’t sitting down working, we are prone to continue thinking about it since the physical environment no longer reminds us to shift our mind state.</description></item><item><title>The real hockey stick growth worth chasing</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-real-hockey-stick-growth-worth-chasing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-real-hockey-stick-growth-worth-chasing/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The real hockey curve growth we all need to be chasing - seeds (maybe not companies)&amp;quot;. @zenx said while handing over these 50 odd seeds. Seeds that can turn into trees, and in turn result in many more seeds and trees, providing for food and helping the planet for 100&amp;rsquo;s of years.</description></item><item><title>CRED curious: Nithin Kamath in conversation with Kunal Shah</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cred-curious-nithin-kamath-in-conversation-with/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cred-curious-nithin-kamath-in-conversation-with/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Generalists vs specialists</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/generalists-vs-specialists/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/generalists-vs-specialists/</guid><description>My view on Generalist vs Specialist? Being a jack of all trades helps you grow intellectually &amp;amp; increases odds of finding what you love. But as a business, I think going after one problem(What u love &amp;amp; Core competency) has a much higher chance of success than to spray &amp;amp; hope.</description></item><item><title>Sense of time post-COVID</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sense-of-time-post-covid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sense-of-time-post-covid/</guid><description>https://behavioralscientist.org/time-confetti-and-the-broken-promise-of-leisure Have been wondering why the post-COVID world seems more Busy-ness than Business. This article explains why beautifully - &amp;ldquo;We have more time for leisure than we did fifty years ago. But leisure has never been less relaxing&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Nikhil and Me on SNFConversations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nikhil-and-me-on-snfconversations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nikhil-and-me-on-snfconversations/</guid><description>They say it is tough to be in business with family. @kamath_nikhil &amp;amp; I have been doing stuff together forever, never a fight &amp;amp; couldn&amp;rsquo;t have had a better partner. Btw, it helps when you are like the role modelWinking face. Weirdly first time together on an interview https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oiC-CuyUAK4&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be</description></item><item><title>The Success Story Of Zerodha's SMART Business Journey ft. Nithin Kamath | The Ranveer Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-success-story-of-zerodhas-smart-business-ft/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-success-story-of-zerodhas-smart-business-ft/</guid><description>An interaction with Ranveer from Beer Biceps talking about building Zerodha, how to do business, and life.</description></item><item><title>The Success Story Of Zerodha's SMART Business Journey ft. Nithin Kamath | The Ranveer Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beer-biceps-zerodha-interview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beer-biceps-zerodha-interview/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Learning Sessions: Unfiltered deep dive with Nithin Kamath, Founder and CEO, Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/learning-sessions-unfiltered-deep-dive-with-nithin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/learning-sessions-unfiltered-deep-dive-with-nithin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Zerodha story: Nithin Kamath shares his bootstrapped entrepreneurial journey</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-zerodha-story-nithin-kamath-shares-his-journey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-zerodha-story-nithin-kamath-shares-his-journey/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>