<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>life on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/life/</link><description>Recent content in life on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Some moments from Hyrox event</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/some-moments-from-the-hyrox-event/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/some-moments-from-the-hyrox-event/</guid><description>Turns out being old at HYROX has an advantage. #3 in my age category. 😬
Seema the cancer survivor killing the circuit as well. 😶
And Nikhil’s birthday party followed by a killer WTF offline event hosted by Nik.
Tagging Dilip Kumar and peakst8</description></item><item><title>At the EY's World Entrepreneur event</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/at-the-eys-world-entrepreneur-event/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/at-the-eys-world-entrepreneur-event/</guid><description>Spent the last week in Monaco at the EY World Entrepreneur of the Year event — the first time I’ve ever been part of something like this. And yes, I was “judged” for the first time since school — group discussions and all. 😬
I didn’t win. As Zerodha, we’re building only for India, with a single source of revenue. I guess the judges were looking for something more global, more diversified.</description></item><item><title>My Recovery Journey</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-recovery-journey/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-recovery-journey/</guid><description>So, yeah, fourteen months after the stroke, my body is almost back to normal 😬, and my mind is at about 85%.
My writing hasn’t improved at all. Maybe because I don’t practice enough. My speech is, well… about 85%.</description></item><item><title>EY Entrepreneur of the Year 2024</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ey-entrepreneur-of-the-year-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ey-entrepreneur-of-the-year-2024/</guid><description>This is what the top of the bull market looks like with a lag 😬. A broker winning the EY entrepreneur of the year 2024.
And there can&amp;rsquo;t be a more apt song than Zindagi Kaisi Yeh Paheli in the background.</description></item><item><title>A year of remembrance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-year-of-remembrance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-year-of-remembrance/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a year since my dad passed away. On this occasion, my mom, Nikhil, Seema, and all of us at Zerodhaare proud to help set up the upcoming IISc Medical School/Bagchi-Parthasarathy Hospital in his memory.</description></item><item><title>India's diversity feels unmatched globally</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-diversity-feels-unmatched-globally/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-diversity-feels-unmatched-globally/</guid><description>I recently returned from visiting several countries in Europe. Everything feels like a cut, copy, and paste with very small differences.
In contrast, India is more like a continent than a country. The diversity in terms of languages, food, culture, etc., between the 28 states and within each state is nuts.
Every time I think of this, I am amazed at how the country actually came together.</description></item><item><title>Impromptu AMRAP workout</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impromptu-amrap-workout/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impromptu-amrap-workout/</guid><description>Impromptu AMRAP workout when Sisters in Sweat were at work 😀 1 min x pushups.</description></item><item><title>Telemarketing these days</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/telemarketing-these-days/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/telemarketing-these-days/</guid><description>My phone has become unusable due to telemarketing and is always silent. Guess what goes around comes around.
I spent four years at a call center, making unsolicited calls to people in the US. I guess Karma has a way of biting back. 😬</description></item><item><title>Recovering from a minor health scare</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recovering-from-a-minor-health-scare/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recovering-from-a-minor-health-scare/</guid><description>Around 6 weeks ago, I had a mild stroke out of the blue. Dad passing away, poor sleep, exhaustion, dehydration, and overworking out —any of these could be possible reasons.
I&amp;rsquo;ve gone from having a big droop in the face and not being able to read or write to having a slight droop but being able to read and write more. From being absent-minded to more present-minded. So, 3 to 6 months for full recovery.</description></item><item><title>Importance of having a steady relationship</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/importance-of-having-a-steady-relationship/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/importance-of-having-a-steady-relationship/</guid><description>Here is a counter-argument in an age of short-term relationships: A steady relationship is underrated. Not having a volatile personal life makes life better. It also improves the odds of doing well personally and professionally.
We humans are social creatures, and we are hardwired to seek partners. But I don’t think a perfect partner exists. We all have our strengths and weaknesses, and relationships are about compromises. Having said that, sometimes people aren&amp;rsquo;t compatible, and in such cases, ending the relationship makes sense.</description></item><item><title>You'll be missed, Mr Munger</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/youll-be-missed-mr-munger/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/youll-be-missed-mr-munger/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;I had written this about Mr. Charlie Munger in last year&amp;rsquo;s business update. His ideas have had a tremendous influence on me professionally. You’ll be missed, Mr. Munger. 🖤&amp;rdquo;
I have been reading and listening to quite a bit of Charlie Munger over the last few days. Every time I go down this rabbit hole, I tend to discover more about myself and what I think Zerodha should be. If I had to summarise, I could use some of his quotes (link to full post in comments)</description></item><item><title>Benefits of playing a sport</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/benefits-of-playing-a-sport/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/benefits-of-playing-a-sport/</guid><description>The one thing that has helped me remain sane and deal with the volatility of life is playing a sport regularly. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t just helped me reduce stress and anxiety, but I think it has also improved my cognitive abilities. Also, I&amp;rsquo;m almost forced to make healthier lifestyle choices when playing a sport regularly.
Given the benefits of playing a sport, picking up one If you can is a no-brainer, especially for kids.</description></item><item><title>Age is just a number</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/age-is-just-a-number/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/age-is-just-a-number/</guid><description>Turned 44 today at 14.3% body fat, the lowest I have been. Sharing publicly for accountability, so I don’t slack and revert back to the mean, 🥶and maybe inspire a few folks and remind that age is just a number. 😬
And thanks everyone for the birthday wishes.</description></item><item><title>The downsides of social media</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-downsides-of-social-media/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-downsides-of-social-media/</guid><description>This desire to build large social media followings can be a slippery slope.
People are generally curious about successful &amp;amp; famous people, so it&amp;rsquo;s easier for celebs from movies, sports, etc., maybe even some businessmen 😀, to build a social media presence quickly.
For everyone else, there is always an incentive to be loud, controversial or oversell because that&amp;rsquo;s what gets the attention. The exception to this is people who write and share high-quality things, but this is very hard.</description></item><item><title>Trading advice from Ramesh Damani</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trading-advice-from-ramesh-damani/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trading-advice-from-ramesh-damani/</guid><description>A Tradingqna user pointed to a video of Ramesh Damani where he says, Trading is always done by slip book &amp;amp; not chequebook &amp;amp; asked what it meant. Ramesh explains this other version of maybe the most important rule in trading &amp;amp; life, Cut your losers &amp;amp; Hold on to the winners.
Thanks, Ramesh, for taking the time to share the response to my cold email. 😃 Here is the link to the full post.</description></item><item><title>Beware of crypto and other online scams</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-crypto-and-other-online-scams/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-crypto-and-other-online-scams/</guid><description>Someone I know got scammed &amp;amp; lost money.
It started with a response to a part-time job offer on WhatsApp. The first few tasks were about leaving fake reviews for resorts &amp;amp; restaurants in random places like Peru. ~Rs 30k was transferred to the bank for the tasks completed. A Telegram group was created with others who claimed to do these tasks.
The next task for the group was to trade on a mock crypto platform, following a bunch of rules.</description></item><item><title>No amount of money can buy good health. A few transformational stories from my life</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/no-amount-of-money-can-buy-good-health-a-few-transformational-stories-from-my-life/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/no-amount-of-money-can-buy-good-health-a-few-transformational-stories-from-my-life/</guid><description>Today is World Health Day. Not that we need a day to remind us, but no amount of money can buy good health. Being healthy needn&amp;rsquo;t be complicated; small lifestyle changes can make a huge difference.
I&amp;rsquo;m highlighting some people who&amp;rsquo;ve transformed with such changes in my life.
Venu is the man behind all operations &amp;amp; compliance at Zerodha. From chubby to the hottest compliance head in the world. ;)</description></item><item><title>Fun workout session with the team at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fun-workout-session-with-the-team-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fun-workout-session-with-the-team-at-zerodha/</guid><description>Thanks to all the internal health initiatives, my gut says that Zerodha might be among India&amp;rsquo;s fittest companies. 🙈Putting it here to nudge my peers to also think about it. 😬
Today, some of us from Zerodha &amp;amp; Rainmatter health did an as many rounds as possible (AMRAP) in 25 mins workout with Adnan from Devils Circuit
Here is the workout if you want to attempt this with your team sometime:</description></item><item><title>Meeting our PM Narendra Modi</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/meeting-our-pm-narendra-modi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/meeting-our-pm-narendra-modi/</guid><description>It was an honour to meet our PM Narendra Modi
My new health &amp;amp; fitness goal is to be able to operate at his intensity when I am 72. He spent almost 30 mins late in the night interacting with Nikhil &amp;amp; me, despite all his meetings &amp;amp; travels through the day.</description></item><item><title>Mom ensuring Carnatic music in the family</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mom-ensuring-carnatic-music-in-the-family/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mom-ensuring-carnatic-music-in-the-family/</guid><description>Ajji on the Veena performing with grandson Kiaan on the Mridungam. Ajji ensuring Carnatic music in the family continues to the next generation.</description></item></channel></rss>