<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>health on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/health/</link><description>Recent content in health on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Real estate economics could drive environmental change</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-estate-economics-could-drive-environmental-change/</link><pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-estate-economics-could-drive-environmental-change/</guid><description>You have to wonder what it will take for us to take air pollution more seriously. By the way, this data only covers until 2019, and things have only gotten worse in the last five years.
Maybe a property price discount for the quality of air and water is the solution. If economics accounted for this, maybe we would all figure this out. Essentially the air and water quality determines the rate for the property.</description></item><item><title>Diabetes a ticking time bomb for India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/diabetes-a-ticking-time-bomb-for-india/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/diabetes-a-ticking-time-bomb-for-india/</guid><description>Diabetes is a ticking time bomb for India. We have the largest number of people with diabetes in the world.
There was a time when people used to call diabetes a rich person&amp;rsquo;s disease. But that&amp;rsquo;s no longer the case. According to a recent study, 21 crore Indians are living with diabetes.
The scary part is the rate at which it&amp;rsquo;s affecting young Indians. If you&amp;rsquo;re a 20-year-old woman living in a city today, you have a 64.</description></item><item><title>Air pollution is deadlier than smoking</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/air-pollution-is-deadlier-than-smoking/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/air-pollution-is-deadlier-than-smoking/</guid><description>Air pollution is deadlier than smoking, drinking, or AIDS (you only have to read this report from Down to Earth to figure that out) and right now, it appears countries like China, US, and others in Europe are doing a far better job than India in reining it in. Read the Ken article.</description></item><item><title>All you need to know to select the right health insurance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/all-you-need-to-know-to-select-the-right-health-insurance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/all-you-need-to-know-to-select-the-right-health-insurance/</guid><description>Most Indians are just 1 hospitalisation away from bankruptcy. A good health insurance plan is mandatory.</description></item><item><title>Why showing percentages on menus could help us eat better</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-showing-percentages-on-menus-could-help-us-eat-better/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-showing-percentages-on-menus-could-help-us-eat-better/</guid><description>Seeing calories, protein, carbs, etc., on a menu is a good start. Ideally, we need to see calories as a percentage of daily calories, proteins, etc.
One large chocolate milkshake has 1000+ calories, or 40% of an average person&amp;rsquo;s calorie intake, which is about 2500 calories.
But showing that a food contains 40% of the total calories that a person consumes in a day might reduce the sales of a lot of things.</description></item><item><title>The Rainmatter Health story</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-rainmatter-health-story/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-rainmatter-health-story/</guid><description>Many of us inside Zerodha are conscious of our health, and we keep having discussions about food, fitness, nutrition, health gadgets, etc. Inevitably, these discussions would lead to questions like &amp;ldquo;Is the atta we consume safe?&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Does milk have harmful antibiotics?&amp;rdquo; etc. To get answers, we would try to find domain experts and entrepreneurs, and some of the answers we often got weren&amp;rsquo;t pretty, as I alluded to in a previous tweet.</description></item><item><title>Awareness can improve our food choices</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/awareness-can-improve-our-food-choices/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/awareness-can-improve-our-food-choices/</guid><description>We Indians need to question what goes into the food we consume. The more we ask, the better choices we will have. The sugar content in most of our food is ridiculous. Adulteration in food items like masalas, milk and protein. And then there are substandard chemicals used in food coloring and preservatives in fruits and vegetables.
They are all slowly killing us. This applies to both packaged foods and food from many restaurants.</description></item><item><title>Recovering from a minor health scare</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recovering-from-a-minor-health-scare/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recovering-from-a-minor-health-scare/</guid><description>Around 6 weeks ago, I had a mild stroke out of the blue. Dad passing away, poor sleep, exhaustion, dehydration, and overworking out —any of these could be possible reasons.
I&amp;rsquo;ve gone from having a big droop in the face and not being able to read or write to having a slight droop but being able to read and write more. From being absent-minded to more present-minded. So, 3 to 6 months for full recovery.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Fittr</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-fittr/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-fittr/</guid><description>When a popular coffee chain started displaying that their large milkshake had a whopping 1000 calories, I thought the sales would drop off a cliff, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t budge. This is maybe an indication of a low understanding of things that can affect people’s health.
Through Rainmatter Health, we have been looking to support people helping Indians make healthier choices. We are super excited to partner with FITTR as they attempt to solve this challenge from multiple angles:</description></item><item><title>The Otherside podcast with Rohan Bopanna</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-otherside-podcast-with-rohan-bopanna/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-otherside-podcast-with-rohan-bopanna/</guid><description>Playing a sport you enjoy is one of the most accessible ways to be physically and mentally fit. Doing well in sports is also a great way to build on national identity and pride. If more Indians have to play a sport &amp;amp; be healthier, maybe those who have played sports at the highest levels are best placed to popularize sports.
It is fantastic to see sportsmen like Rohan Bopanna sponsoring other athletes, running academies and investing in sports businesses.</description></item><item><title>Benefits of playing a sport</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/benefits-of-playing-a-sport/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/benefits-of-playing-a-sport/</guid><description>The one thing that has helped me remain sane and deal with the volatility of life is playing a sport regularly. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t just helped me reduce stress and anxiety, but I think it has also improved my cognitive abilities. Also, I&amp;rsquo;m almost forced to make healthier lifestyle choices when playing a sport regularly.
Given the benefits of playing a sport, picking up one If you can is a no-brainer, especially for kids.</description></item><item><title>Pollution's impact on Indian Health and Economy</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/pollutions-impact-on-indian-health-and-economy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/pollutions-impact-on-indian-health-and-economy/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s growing evidence to show that air and water pollution increases the risk of type 2 diabetes among Indians.
If the quality of life deteriorates, there will be a tipping point where people just give up and start moving from large cities to places with better living conditions. If this happens, it will cause serious economic damage from reduced tax revenues, falling land values, and further degradation of civic infrastructure among other issues.</description></item><item><title>Companies should help employees become healthier</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/companies-should-help-employees-become-healthier/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/companies-should-help-employees-become-healthier/</guid><description>We came first in the corporate team category at the half at IRONMAN Triathlon in Goa today. Dilip running the half marathon, Vishnucycling 90km, and me swimming 1.9km.
Ridiculous that we came first with a total time of whopping 6.2 hours. 😬 An indicator of how maybe more needs to be done at corporates in India to focus on health and fitness, and participating in events like this is a good nudge.</description></item><item><title>Age is just a number</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/age-is-just-a-number/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/age-is-just-a-number/</guid><description>Turned 44 today at 14.3% body fat, the lowest I have been. Sharing publicly for accountability, so I don’t slack and revert back to the mean, 🥶and maybe inspire a few folks and remind that age is just a number. 😬
And thanks everyone for the birthday wishes.</description></item><item><title>A few things I learned about food and sustainability</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-things-i-learned-about-food-and-sustainability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-things-i-learned-about-food-and-sustainability/</guid><description>Every time I speak or listen to Shashi from Akshayakalpa, I learn something new about food, health, and sustainability. A few things I learned recently:
Antibiotic resistance is a global health threat. Due to overuse, germs have become resistant to antibiotics, leading to health complications and deaths. The non-obvious way in which we ingest antibiotics is through dairy and meat. For example, cows that are always tied down tend to catch diseases quickly, and the use of antibiotics becomes necessary to treat them.</description></item><item><title>Preparing for some fitness challnge is a good hack to stay motivated</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/preparing-for-some-fitness-challnge-is-a-good-hack-to-stay-motivated/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/preparing-for-some-fitness-challnge-is-a-good-hack-to-stay-motivated/</guid><description>Preparing for events like marathons, obstacle and fitness races, triathlons, etc., is an incredible hack to stay motivated on your health journey. If you are starting your journey, then signing up for such events is also a good way to push yourself to start.
Adnan Adeeb and I just ran the super challenging Hyrox fitness race, having spent the last couple of months preparing for it. Adnan has to be one of the fittest 50+ senior citizens 😜 I know.</description></item><item><title>Physical and mental health are among the most important aspects in life</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/physical-and-mental-health-are-among-the-most-important-aspects-in-life/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/physical-and-mental-health-are-among-the-most-important-aspects-in-life/</guid><description>Life is like a marathon, and you need to be able to finish strong. Physical and mental health are among the most important aspects in life. You can&amp;rsquo;t buy good health with all the money in the world.
I try to get a workout first thing in the morning with Seema; it also acts like our bonding exercise. 😀 A workout first thing also means I make better choices with food throughout the day.</description></item><item><title>The importance of strength training for Indians</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-strength-training-for-indians/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-strength-training-for-indians/</guid><description>Only about 50 lakhs or 0.3% of Indians go to a gym. Strength training is integral to increasing healthspan &amp;amp; we need more to focus on this. There is enough research to prove that exercise delays death &amp;amp; prevents cognitive &amp;amp; physical decline better than any other intervention.
Most Indians think that you don&amp;rsquo;t need strength training as you age. The truth is strength training becomes even more critical as we get older, especially after our 40s.</description></item><item><title>No amount of money can buy good health. A few transformational stories from my life</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/no-amount-of-money-can-buy-good-health-a-few-transformational-stories-from-my-life/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/no-amount-of-money-can-buy-good-health-a-few-transformational-stories-from-my-life/</guid><description>Today is World Health Day. Not that we need a day to remind us, but no amount of money can buy good health. Being healthy needn&amp;rsquo;t be complicated; small lifestyle changes can make a huge difference.
I&amp;rsquo;m highlighting some people who&amp;rsquo;ve transformed with such changes in my life.
Venu is the man behind all operations &amp;amp; compliance at Zerodha. From chubby to the hottest compliance head in the world. ;)</description></item><item><title>Fun workout session with the team at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fun-workout-session-with-the-team-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fun-workout-session-with-the-team-at-zerodha/</guid><description>Thanks to all the internal health initiatives, my gut says that Zerodha might be among India&amp;rsquo;s fittest companies. 🙈Putting it here to nudge my peers to also think about it. 😬
Today, some of us from Zerodha &amp;amp; Rainmatter health did an as many rounds as possible (AMRAP) in 25 mins workout with Adnan from Devils Circuit
Here is the workout if you want to attempt this with your team sometime:</description></item><item><title>The best way to reduce screen time</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-to-reduce-screen-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-to-reduce-screen-time/</guid><description>The best strategy with diet is to eat healthier foods first; you&amp;rsquo;ll automatically reduce eating the bad stuff. Similarly, best way to limit screen time is to add non-screen experiences. For me, the only true digital detox is playing a physical sport.
&amp;ldquo;As with any bad habit, perhaps the best way to break it isn’t to put our energy into resisting the siren song, but into singing a different tune. In a self-regulation society, that might be the best we can do.</description></item></channel></rss>