<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>health on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/health/</link><description>Recent content in health on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Physical and mental health are among the most important aspects in life</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/physical-and-mental-health-are-among-the-most-important-aspects-in-life/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/physical-and-mental-health-are-among-the-most-important-aspects-in-life/</guid><description>Life is like a marathon, and you need to be able to finish strong. Physical and mental health are among the most important aspects in life. You can&amp;rsquo;t buy good health with all the money in the world.
I try to get a workout first thing in the morning with Seema; it also acts like our bonding exercise. 😀 A workout first thing also means I make better choices with food throughout the day.</description></item><item><title>The importance of strength training for Indians</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-strength-training-for-indians/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-strength-training-for-indians/</guid><description>Only about 50 lakhs or 0.3% of Indians go to a gym. Strength training is integral to increasing healthspan &amp;amp; we need more to focus on this. There is enough research to prove that exercise delays death &amp;amp; prevents cognitive &amp;amp; physical decline better than any other intervention.
Most Indians think that you don&amp;rsquo;t need strength training as you age. The truth is strength training becomes even more critical as we get older, especially after our 40s.</description></item><item><title>No amount of money can buy good health. A few transformational stories from my life</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/no-amount-of-money-can-buy-good-health-a-few-transformational-stories-from-my-life/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/no-amount-of-money-can-buy-good-health-a-few-transformational-stories-from-my-life/</guid><description>Today is World Health Day. Not that we need a day to remind us, but no amount of money can buy good health. Being healthy needn&amp;rsquo;t be complicated; small lifestyle changes can make a huge difference.
I&amp;rsquo;m highlighting some people who&amp;rsquo;ve transformed with such changes in my life.
Venu is the man behind all operations &amp;amp; compliance at Zerodha. From chubby to the hottest compliance head in the world. ;)</description></item><item><title>Fun workout session with the team at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fun-workout-session-with-the-team-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fun-workout-session-with-the-team-at-zerodha/</guid><description>Thanks to all the internal health initiatives, my gut says that Zerodha might be among India&amp;rsquo;s fittest companies. 🙈Putting it here to nudge my peers to also think about it. 😬
Today, some of us from Zerodha &amp;amp; Rainmatter health did an as many rounds as possible (AMRAP) in 25 mins workout with Adnan from Devils Circuit
Here is the workout if you want to attempt this with your team sometime:</description></item><item><title>The best way to reduce screen time</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-to-reduce-screen-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-to-reduce-screen-time/</guid><description>The best strategy with diet is to eat healthier foods first; you&amp;rsquo;ll automatically reduce eating the bad stuff. Similarly, best way to limit screen time is to add non-screen experiences. For me, the only true digital detox is playing a physical sport.
&amp;ldquo;As with any bad habit, perhaps the best way to break it isn’t to put our energy into resisting the siren song, but into singing a different tune. In a self-regulation society, that might be the best we can do.</description></item></channel></rss>