<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/</link><description>Recent content on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I have my first AI agent running</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/i-have-my-first-ai-agent-running/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/i-have-my-first-ai-agent-running/</guid><description>Dang! I have my first AI agent running. I built a small workflow for myself to identify spam emails using Google Studio. The best part about the tool is that you can define the rules. For example, this is one of the rules (image):
Spam emails are my biggest personal problem. I was wasting at least 30 minutes a day marking emails as spam, even with different filters. And I’m addicted to seeing my inbox empty.</description></item><item><title>The rapid evolution of LLMs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-rapid-evolution-of-llms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-rapid-evolution-of-llms/</guid><description>2023: LLMs generate random strings of text and &amp;ldquo;hallucinate.&amp;rdquo;
2026: Linus Torvalds, creator of Linux, says LLMs can generate code better than he can write.
It&amp;rsquo;s remarkable how good these large language models have become in such a short span of time, to the point where they&amp;rsquo;re on par with, or better than, humans across numerous domains.
K (Kailash) recently wrote a brilliant post about how software development, as we&amp;rsquo;ve known it for decades, is over.</description></item><item><title>Brokerage on MTF can add up faster than you think</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/brokerage-on-mtf-can-add-up-faster-than-you-think/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/brokerage-on-mtf-can-add-up-faster-than-you-think/</guid><description>MTF is booming, but here’s the catch: many traders track the interest rate and ignore brokerage. Brokerage on MTF can add up faster than you think 😬
MTF is a leveraged product, so you are already taking a significant risk. If you don’t pay attention to costs while using leverage, the math gets worse because your breakeven point moves higher for the trade.
Rule of thumb: on shorter holding periods and smaller price moves, brokerage can be the difference between breakeven and a loss.</description></item><item><title>RBI's new lending rules for brokers</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-new-lending-rules-brokers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-new-lending-rules-brokers/</guid><description>We’ve been trying to understand RBI’s new lending rules for brokers. Spoke to a few industry folks to figure out what’s actually changing. TL;DR: quite a bit. Here’s my understanding—things are still evolving
Firstly, nothing changes for any of our customers. We have 0 external financing, and are a self-clearing member, so our charges for clients will also remain unaffected.
The big change: Banks can no longer fund proprietary trading. This was never actually allowed, but banks had found workarounds.</description></item><item><title>Fostering love for reading among children</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fostering-love-for-reading-children/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fostering-love-for-reading-children/</guid><description>Seema and I recently took part in India Reads Aloud, an initiative by Turning Pages to foster a love for reading in children.
Reading is foundational to curiosity, but given the structure of our lives, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to hand kids devices. Once they&amp;rsquo;re on them, the kids lose themselves and can remain endlessly distracted. Even I, as an adult, have a hard time not falling into the trap of endlessly consuming digital content.</description></item><item><title>RBI's mis-selling regulation is a welcome move</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-misselling-regulations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-misselling-regulations/</guid><description>RBI&amp;rsquo;s mis-selling regulation is a welcome move. Customers walking into banks often get sold all sorts of financial products they don&amp;rsquo;t need or understand. Products like insurance and mutual funds are bundled with other products like loans. Then there are all sorts of dark patterns.
So now banks have to ask for your feedback on the products they sell within 30 days, and if you think you&amp;rsquo;ve been mis-sold, you can file a complaint within that period and get a full refund.</description></item><item><title>Speculation in US markets makes Indian markets look sane</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/speculation-in-us-markets-makes-indian-markets-look-sane/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/speculation-in-us-markets-makes-indian-markets-look-sane/</guid><description>If you think the Indian markets are speculative, the US markets will blow your mind. It&amp;rsquo;s pure speculative mania there - you can bet on literally anything. Options on every asset imaginable, crypto markets 24/7, sports betting, weather derivatives, and political outcomes through platforms like Kalshi and Polymarket. In a sense, every aspect of American life has been gamified and turned into something you can bet on.
This is probably why the government increased STT?</description></item><item><title>Case for building India’s own deep tech stack</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/case-for-building-indias-own-deep-tech-stack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/case-for-building-indias-own-deep-tech-stack/</guid><description>Tech seems to be getting effectively nationalized. Starting from around 2020, we’ve seen an increase in export controls on things like chips, critical minerals, restrictions on advanced manufacturing equipment, and various other trade restrictions. Supply chains have become a security issue for countries.
We’re no longer in a world where India can be okay with just exporting IT services. If we don’t build domestic deep tech capabilities, we’ll be locked out when it matters most.</description></item><item><title>Technical issue at a depository disrupting settlement</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/technical-issue-at-a-depository-disrupting-settlement/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/technical-issue-at-a-depository-disrupting-settlement/</guid><description>There was a technical issue at one of the depositories this week that disrupted settlement and had a cascading effect on the market. Since many people may not fully understand how settlement works, let me explain what happened.
When you buy or sell stocks, the trade settles on T+1. The Clearing Corporation (CC) determines the net obligations. Meaning who owes shares and who owes money and instructs the depositories (NSDL/CDSL) to move shares between sellers’ and buyers’ demat accounts via their brokers (Depository Participants).</description></item><item><title>Kite Terminal Mode is now live on beta</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kite-terminal-mode-is-now-live-on-beta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kite-terminal-mode-is-now-live-on-beta/</guid><description>Kite Terminal Mode is now live on beta!
We are quite excited about this. 😬
Check out the Kite Beta, and you can provide feedback here.</description></item><item><title>Simplifying Corporate NPS with PensionBox</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/simplifying-corporate-nps-with-pensionbox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/simplifying-corporate-nps-with-pensionbox/</guid><description>In FY25, around 72% of taxpayers chose the New Tax Regime. At Zerodha, that number was over 90%.
This shift makes sense. The new tax regime trades deductions for simpler filing and lower tax rates. For many—especially younger salaried taxpayers, avoiding paperwork-heavy exemptions matters more than maximising deductions.
With most deductions removed, salaried employees are left with the ₹75,000 standard deduction and one meaningful tax-saving option: the employer contribution to NPS, commonly called Corporate NPS.</description></item><item><title>Raising STT won’t curb speculation in F&amp;O</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/raising-stt-wont-curb-speculation-in-fo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/raising-stt-wont-curb-speculation-in-fo/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know the exact reasoning behind the increase in STT. Having said that, if the goal was to reduce speculative activity in F&amp;amp;O, then I&amp;rsquo;m not sure this will do anything.
95% of trading is already in options, and this STT increase will only push that share higher. Why? Because the impact falls mostly on futures, while options are far more speculative than futures.
If the govt wants to reduce speculation, then establishing product suitability (who can trade) criteria is the way to go.</description></item><item><title>Every budget, I hope STT comes down</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/every-budget-i-hope-stt-comes-down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/every-budget-i-hope-stt-comes-down/</guid><description>As a market participant, I always hope the budget will reduce STT, but it keeps going up. STT was introduced when LTCG was made 0, but now that LTCG is back&amp;hellip; 😬
The 60% F&amp;amp;O STT increase from Budget 2024 (0.0125% → 0.02% on futures and 0.0625% → 0.1% on options) didn’t impact volumes much at first, the bull market continued with surging participation. But markets don’t always have bull runs; the impact showed up in the year we just had.</description></item><item><title>Women in Koraput, Odisha document the slow disappearance of the commons</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/women-in-koraput/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/women-in-koraput/</guid><description>Women from indigenous communities in Odisha’s Koraput district are mapping their commons — forests, streams, grazing land, and other shared resources they depend on daily.
They’re doing this because these commons are disappearing. Water sources are drying up, forest cover is thinning, and there’s no clear record of what existed, what’s already lost, or how the change happened.
So they went looking for answers. They pulled government records from the 1960s and walked the land, documenting what exists today.</description></item><item><title>Recent updates to make investing easier for NRIs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recent-updates-to-make-investing-easier-for-nris/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recent-updates-to-make-investing-easier-for-nris/</guid><description>We at Zerodha , have ~40k NRI customers with an average account value of ₹40L, nearly 10x our overall average of ₹3.6L for resident accounts. Most of them opened accounts the hard way, with physical paperwork. If onboarding were fully online, this base would be much larger.
SEBI recently made changes that have allowed us to significantly simplify Non-PIS NRI accounts: they now work like resident accounts, with fully online Aadhaar-based onboarding (when visiting India) and intraday, BTST, and F&amp;amp;O access with no need for a CP code.</description></item><item><title>Get realtime company updates on WhatsApp with Tijori Alerts</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/get-realtime-company-updates-on-whatsapp-with-tijori-alerts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/get-realtime-company-updates-on-whatsapp-with-tijori-alerts/</guid><description>Access to information is what drives prices in markets. While there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of information today, the real challenge is figuring out what actually matters and getting it in time.
Exchange filings, earnings, management commentary, and conference calls. When something material comes out, prices react almost instantly. The faster you get the information, the better your odds of reacting sensibly.
Institutions and high-frequency trading desks scan exchange filings the moment they&amp;rsquo;re published and act within milliseconds.</description></item><item><title>MTF has grown 5x, but broker risk models haven’t</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mtf-has-grown-5x-but-broker-risk-models-havent/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mtf-has-grown-5x-but-broker-risk-models-havent/</guid><description>MTF (margin funding) has grown ~5X in 4 years to ₹110k+ crores, especially after F&amp;amp;O margins and STT increases. But there&amp;rsquo;s something nobody&amp;rsquo;s talking about: there is no real risk model in play for brokers. 😬
Regulations allow up to 5X leverage (20% margin) on many stocks. Competition forces every broker to offer maximum permissible leverage. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, you lose business. Classic race to the bottom.
Unlike F&amp;amp;O, MTF has several risk multipliers: Clients hold positions for months vs days 1,300 stocks (many illiquid) allowed vs only the top 200 in F&amp;amp;O All buy positions vs two-way flow in F&amp;amp;O, making risk management much harder Much harder to manage risk, given all the above.</description></item><item><title>Commodity markets look very different today</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/commodity-markets-look-very-different-today/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/commodity-markets-look-very-different-today/</guid><description>Up until a few years ago, commodity trading was more or less an afterthought. Most traders didn&amp;rsquo;t bother with it because liquidity was thin relative to NSE F&amp;amp;O.
But that&amp;rsquo;s changed dramatically, thanks to the spectacular rally in gold and silver. If you look at gold and silver as a percentage of total MCX trading volumes today, the numbers are kind of crazy. A lot of this increase has come at the expense of other commodities like crude.</description></item><item><title>Inspiration from Tata Mumbai Marathon</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/inspiration-from-tata-mumbai-marathon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/inspiration-from-tata-mumbai-marathon/</guid><description>The excitement and enthusiasm among people with disabilities running the Tata Mumbai Marathon today were beyond words. Makes you think about what right you have to complain about anything in life.
On a personal note, Seema ran 10km in ~57 minutes, about 2.5 years after surviving cancer. 😃</description></item><item><title>If you want to build something, India has never offered better odds</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/if-you-want-to-build-something-india-has-never-offered-better-odds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/if-you-want-to-build-something-india-has-never-offered-better-odds/</guid><description>There’s a lot of pessimism about India’s growth prospects right now, amplified by the sheer amount of geopolitical drama we’re living through. But if we aren’t hopeful that India will do better, then everything becomes moot.
This isn’t to say we don’t have real problems. We do. But every successful country has had to deal with its own share of thorny challenges along its development path. What matters is how we respond.</description></item></channel></rss>