<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/</link><description>Recent content on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Volatility in silver prices shows why position sizing matters more than direction</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/volatility-in-silver-prices-shows-why-position-sizing-matters-more-than-direction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/volatility-in-silver-prices-shows-why-position-sizing-matters-more-than-direction/</guid><description>This is the chart of MCX Silver Futures. This type of move is what every trader dreams of capturing, but it can also be a nightmare to manage without a good understanding of how to size your positions. Especially when something moves ~10% intraday.
On a side note, there seems to be a sharp increase in commodity trading volumes.</description></item><item><title>Creating experiences centered on health with Peakst8</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/creating-experiences-centered-on-health-with-peakst8/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/creating-experiences-centered-on-health-with-peakst8/</guid><description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve grown older, I&amp;rsquo;ve become increasingly health-conscious. If I could go back in time and change one thing, I would&amp;rsquo;ve started focusing on diet, nutrition and sleep much earlier.
With each passing year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking more about health and fitness, and I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to encourage those around me, both personally and at work, to prioritise their health.
I&amp;rsquo;ve also realised that simple and repeatable behaviours make the biggest difference.</description></item><item><title>Drawing regulatory boundaries between trading and lending</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/drawing-regulatory-boundaries-between-trading-and-lending/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/drawing-regulatory-boundaries-between-trading-and-lending/</guid><description>The exchanges reiterated last night that stock brokers cannot distribute any lending products other than those explicitly tied to trading (MTF). This applies even if the broker is registered as a research analyst. However, despite yesterday&amp;rsquo;s circular, brokers&amp;rsquo; parent companies are allowed to create a &amp;ldquo;super-app&amp;rdquo; where broking and lending happens side-by-side. This is permissible today because there are no restrictions on the parent entity.
The core concern is that any type of lending or inducement to borrow on a trading platform could lead to borrowed money flowing back into the markets.</description></item><item><title>Why most brokers don’t build their own OMS/RMS</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-most-brokers-dont-build/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-most-brokers-dont-build/</guid><description>One of the lesser-known things about stock brokers is that most brokers don&amp;rsquo;t actually own their entire tech stack. There&amp;rsquo;s usually a third-party vendor providing the core order management system (OMS) and risk management system (RMS). Think of OMS/RMS as being similar to the core banking systems that Infosys or Oracle provides for banks.
The OMS/RMS is basically the heart of a broking operation. If this breaks, trading stops. Vendors in our business include Omennest, Kambala, 63 Moons, Rupeeseed, etc.</description></item><item><title>Planting trees is not enough if they aren’t native</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/planting-trees-is-not-enough-if-they-arent-native/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/planting-trees-is-not-enough-if-they-arent-native/</guid><description>When we discuss rewilding and land restoration, ensuring that native trees are used is equally important. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t aware of this when I planted Conocarpus trees at home almost 10 years ago. No birds or animals have ever come to the tree.
I also realised much later that these trees aren&amp;rsquo;t good for humans either. They cause allergic reactions in many people. It&amp;rsquo;s been so many years now that I feel bad about cutting them down, but maybe I should.</description></item><item><title>Risk management lessons from Tom Basso</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-lessons-from-tom-basso/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-lessons-from-tom-basso/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been noticing many recent IPOs continue running up for 2-3 days after listing. While demand and supply factors (limited free float) are obvious reasons, there may also be technical factors at play.
One common reason why traders blow up is because of poor position sizing. In other words, how much do you bet on a trade.
You can be right on direction 60% of the time and still lose everything if you size your positions poorly.</description></item><item><title>Why some IPOs keep rising even after listing day</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-some-ipos-keep-rising-even-after-listing-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-some-ipos-keep-rising-even-after-listing-day/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been noticing many recent IPOs continue running up for 2-3 days after listing. While demand and supply factors (limited free float) are obvious reasons, there may also be technical factors at play.
Let me explain the technical factor.
Many traders attempt to short these stocks intraday, expecting a fall, but if the stock hits the upper circuit, they get trapped with no buyers to sell to. This leads to what’s called a short delivery.</description></item><item><title>What cleaning up pollution looks like when it’s done properly</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-cleaning-up-pollution-looks-like-when-its-done-properly/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-cleaning-up-pollution-looks-like-when-its-done-properly/</guid><description>I was watching this video by Rainmatter Foundation about how Chhatrapati Sambhajinagar (Aurangabad) cleaned up the Kham river in 5 years. It had become a sewage drain, and they turned it back into a flowing river. Made me think about especially of Delhi&amp;rsquo;s air quality problem.
They mapped 249 waste entry points with drones and installed traps. Rerouted sewage to treatment plants and built new ones. Set up a facility for textile waste from factories.</description></item><item><title>Why we don't provide personal and credit card loans through Zerodha Capital</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-we-dont-provide-personal-and-credit-card-loans-through-zerodha-capital/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-we-dont-provide-personal-and-credit-card-loans-through-zerodha-capital/</guid><description>Someone on our team recently asked, &amp;ldquo;Why do we only offer Loan Against Securities on Zerodha Capital?&amp;rdquo; Why not personal loans or credit cards with their higher interest rates?
The simple answer is we can&amp;rsquo;t do anything different there. And our cost of funds doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. We&amp;rsquo;re at ~8.5%, while banks raise money at ~3.5%, and large NBFCs around ~7%.
Can&amp;rsquo;t compete on rates, and usually the best borrowers go where the rates are the lowest.</description></item><item><title>Protect your assets by adding a nominee</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/protect-your-assets-by-adding-a-nominee/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/protect-your-assets-by-adding-a-nominee/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s ₹104,000 crores worth of money and investments lying unclaimed across banks, insurance companies, and mutual funds. The number is from a post by our PM Narendra Modi.
Despite the nomination process being fully online and despite repeated nudges, 62% of Zerodha users with holdings don&amp;rsquo;t have a nominee. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t added any nominees, it takes barely a couple of minutes.
While adding nominees is a good first step, you still have to inform the nominees.</description></item><item><title>Making food packaging plastic-free with Zerocircle</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-food-packaging-plastic-free-with-zerocircle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-food-packaging-plastic-free-with-zerocircle/</guid><description>Almost all food packaging that resembles paper or cardboard, such as coffee cups, takeout boxes, and food wrappers, has a thin plastic coating. This plastic isn&amp;rsquo;t just bad for the planet; it leaches microplastics directly into your food and body.
Zerocircle (a Rainmatter Climate investment) makes coatings from 100% natural compounds. No plastic, no microplastics.
Solutions like this can only go mainstream with public awareness. Most people are unaware that a &amp;ldquo;paper&amp;rdquo; cup isn&amp;rsquo;t entirely made of paper.</description></item><item><title>Why encouraging less trading leads to better outcomes for everyone</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-encouraging-less-trading-leads-to-better-outcomes-for-everyone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-encouraging-less-trading-leads-to-better-outcomes-for-everyone/</guid><description>As a % of client funds, our brokerage revenue is 20-25% of our listed peers. That means our clients trade a lot less (75% lesser) as a proportion of their capital.
Here&amp;rsquo;s something counterintuitive but true: With few exceptions, the more frequently people trade, the lower their odds of being profitable. More activity doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean better returns; it usually means a higher chance of blowing out your account.
So it&amp;rsquo;s actually in a platform&amp;rsquo;s best interest to get customers to trade less, not more.</description></item><item><title>Make social security accessible for those who need it most</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/make-social-security-accessible-for-those-who-need-it-most/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/make-social-security-accessible-for-those-who-need-it-most/</guid><description>Most people from economically weaker sections aren’t aware of government schemes like PMSBY (₹20/year for ₹2 lakh accident cover) or PMJAY / Ayushman Bharat (₹5 lakh health cover).
We recently invited Haqdarshak to run an enrollment camp at our office for housekeeping, admin, and security staff. If you employ people, consider doing this. It removes all the usual barriers to enrollment. The schemes are well-designed; the real problem is awareness and access.</description></item><item><title>On today’s issue caused by the Cloudflare outage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-today-issue-caused-by-the-cloudflare-outage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-today-issue-caused-by-the-cloudflare-outage/</guid><description>Cloudflare powers approximately 20-25% of all internet traffic globally. It&amp;rsquo;s the infrastructure behind millions of websites and apps—from content delivery and DDoS protection to DNS services. When Cloudflare has an outage, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just affect one company; it impacts a significant chunk of the internet simultaneously.
Today, they had a brief outage that affected Kite along with numerous other brokers, fintech platforms, and online services worldwide.
This is why we built Kite Backup on WhatsApp.</description></item><item><title>Big reasons why term insurance applications get rejected</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/big-reasons-why-term-insurance-applications-get-rejected/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/big-reasons-why-term-insurance-applications-get-rejected/</guid><description>Getting adequate life insurance if you have dependents is the first thing you should do before you save, invest, etc. Having said that, not all life insurance policy applications are approved.
The Ditto team was telling me that 30% of term life insurance applications get rejected. Apparently, one of their biggest teams internally helps customers navigate policy rejections.
Big reasons why applications get rejected.
If you need assistance with insurance, you can schedule a call with an insurance advisor at Ditto</description></item><item><title>Alar’s new update makes the dictionary faster and easier to build on</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alars-new-update-makes-the-dictionary-faster-and-easier-to-build-on/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alars-new-update-makes-the-dictionary-faster-and-easier-to-build-on/</guid><description>In 2020, we did something very odd. Well, K (Kailash, CTO) did. He helped open-source Alar, a Kannada–English dictionary. It&amp;rsquo;s a little absurd, considering we&amp;rsquo;re a stockbroking company, but the project itself is one of monumental importance.
The story of how Alar came to be is even more inspiring. It was essentially the life&amp;rsquo;s work of one man: V. Krishna. Alar is the online version of what he had built over 40 years—researching, writing, and cataloguing more than 150,000 Kannada words and 240,000 English definitions, complete with all their attendant details.</description></item><item><title>10 years of zero brokerage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/10-years-of-zero-brokerage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/10-years-of-zero-brokerage/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 10 years since we went zero brokerage on stocks, ETFs, and more. Back in 2015, if you had asked whether Zerodha would keep brokerage on investing at zero in 2025, I would&amp;rsquo;ve probably said no.
The backstory of how we decided to go zero is a bit funny. K(Kailash, CTO) and I were sitting at Bengaluru airport on our way to Kochi, talking about the need to change Zerodha&amp;rsquo;s image of being meant only for traders.</description></item><item><title>Unlisted market hype is blinding people to basic risks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/unlisted-market-hype-is-blinding-people-to-basic-risks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/unlisted-market-hype-is-blinding-people-to-basic-risks/</guid><description>Given how hot the IPO market is, I&amp;rsquo;m hearing some phenomenally stupid stories from the unlisted market. People are blindly punting on so-called &amp;ldquo;pre-IPO&amp;rdquo; companies hoping they&amp;rsquo;ll make bigger gains than during the actual IPO.
The greed is causing people to ignore some hard realities: these shares already come with 100–500% markups, ridiculous commissions, and terrible pricing. The biggest risk? There have been numerous cases where the IPO price ended up lower than the price at which people bought shares in the unlisted market.</description></item><item><title>The growing risks of trading crypto derivatives without clear rules</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-growing-risks-of-trading-crypto-derivatives-without-clear-rules/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-growing-risks-of-trading-crypto-derivatives-without-clear-rules/</guid><description>Crypto derivative exchanges exist in regulatory limbo. A bit like Schrödinger&amp;rsquo;s cat—neither fully regulated nor unregulated. This ambiguity is being exploited in dangerous ways. By the way, I am not referring to the actual buying and selling of Cryptocurrency.
The first risk with unregulated platforms is, of course, that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing you can do if something goes wrong.
The other big problem with crypto F&amp;amp;O is that you have no idea who&amp;rsquo;s on the other side of your order.</description></item><item><title>Take break from trading using Kill Switch</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-break-from-trading-using-kill-switch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-break-from-trading-using-kill-switch/</guid><description>The other common trading mistake I have seen over and over again in all my years of being a trader and running a brokerage is over-trading and revenge trading.
Sometimes, the best trade is the one you don&amp;rsquo;t take.
This is why we launched Kill Switch. If you get the urge to keep trading, you can enable it, and you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to place trades for the rest of the day.</description></item></channel></rss>