<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/</link><description>Recent content on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SEBI cautions against investing in digital gold</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cautions-against-investing-in-digital-gold/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cautions-against-investing-in-digital-gold/</guid><description>Digital gold is unregulated. A timely reminder from SEBI.
Most people don’t realize that nobody regulates digital gold, and if something were to happen to the platforms or companies selling it, there’s not much you can do.
It’s also a subpar way to get exposure to gold. You pay 3% GST the moment you buy. Then there are spreads of another 2–3%, which means as soon as you purchase digital gold, you’re already down about 6%, and that’s before even factoring in regulatory risk.</description></item><item><title>Robinhood makes $150 million a year just from instant withdrawal fee</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-makes-150-million-a-year-just-from-instant-withdrawal-fee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-makes-150-million-a-year-just-from-instant-withdrawal-fee/</guid><description>I just discovered that Robinhood will generate approximately $150 million (~₹1,300 crores) in revenue from the fees it charges for processing instant client withdrawals. Their cost to process these is around $35–40 million, which means a clean $100 million to the bottom line, and that’s just from instant withdrawals. 😬
As an Indian startup with some scale, founders dream of generating revenue like this from non-core products. Hence the rush to introduce everything: loans, insurance, payments, and other financial services.</description></item><item><title>Discussion with Adnan from Devils Circuit on fitness and health</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/discussion-with-adnan-from-devils-circuit-on-fitness-and-health/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/discussion-with-adnan-from-devils-circuit-on-fitness-and-health/</guid><description>Of everyone I’ve met, Adnan has to be one of the most passionate advocates for fitness and getting Indians to participate in active sports. His company, Devils Circuit, has faced its fair share of obstacles and ups and downs — but the mission remains strong: inspiring Indians to take a greater interest in their health and fitness.
And my gut tells me, the time when we truly start caring more about our health is coming soon.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha LIQUIDCASE grows to ₹6,000 crore AUM in under two years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-liquidcase-grows-to-6000-crore-aum-in-under-two-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-liquidcase-grows-to-6000-crore-aum-in-under-two-years/</guid><description>Zerodha LIQUIDCASE is India&amp;rsquo;s first liquid ETF with a growth NAV, and we launched it in January 2024. In just under two years, it&amp;rsquo;s incredible that the AUM has reached almost ₹6,000 crores.
All of this growth is organic, from traders and investors discovering the ETF and investing in it. We haven&amp;rsquo;t really spoken about it much, and you can&amp;rsquo;t pay commissions on an ETF anyway.
The innovation here was simple: no dividends, because they were tax-inefficient and a pain to redeem and track.</description></item><item><title>Congrats to the Groww team on the IPO</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/congrats-to-the-groww-team-on-their-ipo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/congrats-to-the-groww-team-on-their-ipo/</guid><description>Congrats on the IPO Lalit Keshre &amp;amp; team, and best of luck.
Btw, about 20% of all Groww IPO applications are from Zerodha customers. 😛</description></item><item><title>How India’s tax structure rewards growth over profits</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-indias-tax-structure-rewards-growth-over-profits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-indias-tax-structure-rewards-growth-over-profits/</guid><description>If you take money out of a business as dividends, the effective tax rate is 52% (25% corporate tax + 35.5% on personal income). Through capital gains, it’s just 14.95% (with cess).
Why does this matter? Here’s what you should know if you invest in IPOs.
If you’re an investor (especially a VC), the math is simple: reduce corporate tax by showing minimal profits or losses. Spend (Burn) on acquiring users, build a growth narrative, and then sell shares at a higher valuation while paying much lower tax.</description></item><item><title>Didn’t expect our support for FFmpeg to get this much love</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/didnt-expect-our-support-for-ffmpeg-to-get-this-much-love/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/didnt-expect-our-support-for-ffmpeg-to-get-this-much-love/</guid><description>The amount of love this has gotten is quite crazy. I was just asking K, &amp;lsquo;How does it make sense that there are tech companies worth billions and trillions of dollars who use these pieces of open source software without which they could not exist, and yet are unwilling to fund them?&amp;rsquo;
We’ve been funding open source projects from ~2018 on and off before setting up FLOSS/fund in 2024. We run on open source, so supporting is a no-brainer.</description></item><item><title>The one thing I wish I’d done differently after my stroke</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-one-thing-i-wish-id-done-differently-after-my-stroke/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-one-thing-i-wish-id-done-differently-after-my-stroke/</guid><description>If there’s one thing I wish I had done differently when I was hit by a stroke last January, it would be to go to the hospital immediately, within the Golden Hour (&amp;lt;4.5 hours), instead of thinking I could just sleep it off.
This “nothing will happen to me” attitude is common, especially among those under 50. But the truth is, strokes are rising sharply, up to nearly 30% of all strokes in the last few years, among 30 to 50-year-olds.</description></item><item><title>AMA with Zerodha's core team</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ama-with-zerodhas-core-team/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ama-with-zerodhas-core-team/</guid><description>A bunch of you asked us questions about our revenues, regulations, international investing, AI, and more. Nikhil, Kailash, Karthik Rangappa, Venu, and I answered a lot of those questions in this AMA.
Since there were several questions about US investing: we didn&amp;rsquo;t offer it until now because the regulations were unclear, but now there&amp;rsquo;s clarity. In May, SEBI and IFSCA allowed brokers to operate in GIFT City, and in June, the exchanges allowed brokers to offer third-party products.</description></item><item><title>Indian VC ecosystem has changed quite a bit in 15 years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-vc-ecosystem-has-changed-quite-a-bit-in-15-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-vc-ecosystem-has-changed-quite-a-bit-in-15-years/</guid><description>The Indian VC ecosystem has changed quite a bit in 15 years. When we started Zerodha in 2010, &amp;ldquo;VC&amp;rdquo; was an exotic term, and there was barely any startup activity. The most popular VCs were dads, uncles and aunts.
Starting around 2010, we began seeing interest driven by India&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;opportunity size.&amp;rdquo; India&amp;rsquo;s population has done more to attract VC money than anything else 😛 &amp;ldquo;India has 120 crore people, and even if 1% buy X&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>1929 by Andrew Ross Sorkin is a must-read for anyone in the markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/1929-by-andrew-ross-sorkin-is-a-must-read-for-anyone-in-the-markets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/1929-by-andrew-ross-sorkin-is-a-must-read-for-anyone-in-the-markets/</guid><description>1929 by Andrew Ross Sorkin is a must-read for anyone in the markets—stocks, commodities, or crypto.
He quotes US President Hoover (1929):
“The only problem with capitalism is capitalists. They’re too damn greedy.”
Every crash, 1907, 1929, 1987, 2001 (Dotcom), 2008 (GFC), and so many more, follows the same script.
Greed drives markets higher, inflating bubbles that draw in even those who don’t understand the risks. As euphoria builds, leverage accumulates quietly somewhere in the system: loans, margins, complex derivatives.</description></item><item><title>One year of the Zerodha FLOSS fund</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/one-year-of-the-zerodha-floss-fund/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/one-year-of-the-zerodha-floss-fund/</guid><description>We started FLOSS/fund in 2024 to give up to $1 million annually to support the development of FOSS (free and open-source) projects globally.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what K said in a post reflecting on the past year, making the case for the Indian government also to fund FOSS for strategic tech sovereignty:
&amp;ldquo;Actually, no amount of material resources can enable governments to develop, nurture, and sustain complex, high-quality FOSS projects themselves in the way a community of passionate maintainers can.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity is as human as it is technical</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cybersecurity-is-as-human-as-it-is-technical/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cybersecurity-is-as-human-as-it-is-technical/</guid><description>So, my personal Twitter account was compromised yesterday because I fell for a phishing e-mail early in the morning while at home when browsing on my personal device.
A momentary lapse in attention. The e-mail got through all spam and phishing filters. I clicked on the &amp;lsquo;Change Your Password&amp;rsquo; link and entered the password. The attackers gained access to a single login session, using it to tweet a few scammy cryptocurrency links.</description></item><item><title>The love we get for all the content is crazy</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-love-we-get-for-all-the-content-is-crazy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-love-we-get-for-all-the-content-is-crazy/</guid><description>The love we get for all the content on Varsity, Markets by Zerodha etc. is crazy. 😀What we&amp;rsquo;ve done from day 1 is focus on sharing quality insights rather than chasing engagement, pointless optimizations, and gimmicks. The trust we&amp;rsquo;ve built over almost a decade is a direct result of that—people reading and watching us and then sharing it with their friends and family.</description></item><item><title>Open source for tech sovereignty</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-for-tech-sovereignty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-for-tech-sovereignty/</guid><description>Tech sovereignty and self-sufficiency are national conversations now, the world over. Free and open-source software (FOSS) enables just that—tech sovereignty and, at the same time, mutually assured global collaboration and innovation. IndiaAI Mission&amp;rsquo;s recent push for sovereign open-source LLMs is a great example for this. Without FOSS, there would be no Zerodha or the global digital ecosystem as we know it today.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an article by K (Kailash) on the topic from 2021 that&amp;rsquo;s still relevant now.</description></item><item><title>Financial inclusion needs more than just digital access</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-inclusion-needs-more-than-just-digital-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-inclusion-needs-more-than-just-digital-access/</guid><description>The entire Indian financial services industry, including Zerodha, has been a massive beneficiary of the ease of digital onboarding via Aadhaar e-Sign, eKYC, etc. It has been a big reason for the increase in financial inclusion among Tier 2 and 3 cities and rural parts of the country; people who had not previously interacted with the formal financial system.
While many of us take the benefits of these digital systems for granted, being in a city like Bengaluru (and a position of privilege), I was surprised by the extent of challenges with OTP verification and the physical/biometric side of these systems until I read articles like these in The Times of India and elsewhere.</description></item><item><title>Real stories from parents investing through Zerodha minor accounts.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-stories-from-parents-investing-through-zerodha-minor-accounts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-stories-from-parents-investing-through-zerodha-minor-accounts/</guid><description>I can keep giving gyan about starting to invest early for your kids, but nothing beats hearing it from parents who are actually doing it. Here are some first-hand takes from people using a Zerodha minor account to invest for their children.
P.S. Our youngest account holder is just 64 days old. 😀</description></item><item><title>India’s $3 trillion in idle gold needs smarter financialization.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</guid><description>Indian households hold ~$3 trillion in gold (World Gold Council estimate), sitting idle in lockers. Meanwhile, equity investments fund companies that need capital to grow. We need better ways to financialize this gold beyond just gold loans.</description></item><item><title>RBI move could make LAS more popular</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-move-could-make-las-more-popular/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-move-could-make-las-more-popular/</guid><description>One good change from RBI yesterday: banks can now lend up to ₹1 crore against shares, up from the earlier ₹20 lakhs. Hopefully, this makes loan against securities (LAS) more popular.
It’s ridiculous how many people holding stocks continue taking personal loans or using credit cards at much higher rates—credit cards can go up to 40%+. Even at Zerodha Capital, we see this constantly. People just aren’t aware they can replace high-interest debt with LAS, which is one reason our book is still only ₹450 crores.</description></item><item><title>Why short-term growth is the wrong metric</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-short-term-growth-is-the-wrong-metric/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-short-term-growth-is-the-wrong-metric/</guid><description>On the question of what would we do if weekly options were removed, I suppose we&amp;rsquo;ll see another hit to our revenues in the short-term.
Having said that, when you&amp;rsquo;re building a business for the long term, focusing on quarterly or even annual growth is a poor metric. The more you focus on them, the higher the odds that you&amp;rsquo;ll do things that are bad for your customers.</description></item></channel></rss>