<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/</link><description>Recent content on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Gamestop saga and lessons for retail investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</guid><description>In the Gamestop saga, the media has loved telling the story of how Retail made a lot of money from Hedge funds. The reality is entirely different, almost everyone apart from retail has probably made money or benefited from this. Firstly, yes, a couple of Hedge funds were sitting on large losses on Gamestop shorts. Now that stock is at $50, the losses also would be a fraction, if the shorts still held.</description></item><item><title>Rising financial awareness among Indians</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</guid><description>Financial awareness about the importance of saving and investing in India is increasing at the fastest rate ever, especially among millennials. Of course, stock markets doing well and lower bank FD rates are helping. But there are also a few structural changes afoot here. Historically financial products have been sold hard &amp;amp; mostly in person. Products mostly sold based on promises of high returns (sales pitches in person leave no audit trail).</description></item><item><title>Free &amp; open-source software (FOSS) — one of the reasons behind Zerodha's success</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/foss-the-reason-for-zerodhas-success/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/foss-the-reason-for-zerodhas-success/</guid><description>Free &amp;amp; open-source software (FOSS) is the main reason for the success of Zerodha as K writes.
https://nadh.in/blog/the-atmanirbhartha-of-open-source-software</description></item><item><title>Shorting and Indian Capital Markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</guid><description>Can retail traders are cause a “short squeeze” in India like they did in stocks like GameStop and AMC entertainment in the US? It cannot, and I explain why in this post. Join the discussion here.</description></item><item><title>Beyond misleading trading turnover numbers — the actual size of Indian capital markets?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beyond-misleading-trading-turnover-numbers-the-actual-size-of-indian-capital-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beyond-misleading-trading-turnover-numbers-the-actual-size-of-indian-capital-markets/</guid><description>Looking at trading turnover to estimate capital market size is misleading. Most trades are leveraged &amp;amp; ideally we should look at the margins being traded, not the trade value. Turnover this way will be less than 10% of the trading turnover declared.
The best way to estimate the size of the Indian capital markets is by checking the revenue pool. This I think, is less than Rs 50k crores across 1500+ brokers, exchanges, &amp;amp; depositories.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-rainmatter-foundation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-rainmatter-foundation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The fallacy of predictions</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-fallacy-of-predictions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-fallacy-of-predictions/</guid><description>Even after all my years of experience, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more wrong in predicting the direction of our business in 2020. These expert predictions should be taken with a pinch of salt, most of times the odds are equal to tossing a coin.</description></item><item><title>Is trading the markets gambling?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-trading-the-markets-gambling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-trading-the-markets-gambling/</guid><description>Is trading the markets gambling? I get asked often. My answer is that yes, you can gamble when trading, just like you can gamble with everything else in life.</description></item><item><title>The twisted world of illegal CFDs &amp; binary options</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Total addressable market for brokers</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/total-addressable-market-for-brokers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/total-addressable-market-for-brokers/</guid><description>Since broking is hot post-COVID, inspite of all the spike in trading volumes and activtity, the total addressable market is just ~1.5 million users. I had shared this pre-Covid. Broking is super hot now, but this TAM (Total addressable market) hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed, if anything it has reduced. Btw, the revenue-generating active day traders + F&amp;amp;O crowd is not more than ~1.5mil in spite of the spike in trading activity/volumes. This active crowd is unlikely to go up because most day and F&amp;amp;O traders stop within 6 months.</description></item><item><title>Robinhood pays $65M to settle SEC charges on payment for order flow disclosures</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-pays-65m-to-settle-sec-charges-on-for/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-pays-65m-to-settle-sec-charges-on-for/</guid><description>The Robinhood SEC settlement over order flow disclosures grabbed some headlines even in India. Since people might be wondering if this happens here, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. Unlike the US, all order in India are matched and executed on the exchanges. We have no concept of order flow here.</description></item><item><title>Why advertising doesn't work</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-advertising-doesnt-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-advertising-doesnt-work/</guid><description>https://freakonomics.com/podcast/advertising-part-2/ This is a great listen from Freakonomics on whether advertising works. The reason we could bootstrap was that we never spent on ads. With no ads, a business is forced to constantly think &amp;amp; do things to get customer love and organic growth. The only time we experimented with ads was for our brand keyword, show our website if you search &amp;ldquo;Zerodha&amp;rdquo;. We stopped immediately when we realized that it made no difference to the traffic and the ad was essentially cannibalizing our organic traffic while costing us money.</description></item><item><title>Podcast: Sandeep Parekh on the evolution of the Indian market and securities regulations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-sandeep-parekh-on-the-evolution-of-the-and/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-sandeep-parekh-on-the-evolution-of-the-and/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EihRbTTLLy0&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be This is a must-watch for those interested in the Indian securities market. @SandeepParekh we need to find a way to get you to do more of this. :)</description></item><item><title>A product to get more Indians to save and invest</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</guid><description>To get the next 10 crore Indians, the traditional financial product might not work. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I think is needed to get these people to start saving and investing.</description></item><item><title>Does Illiquidty like in private markets lead to good investor behavior?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-illiquidty-like-in-private-markets-lead-to/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-illiquidty-like-in-private-markets-lead-to/</guid><description>A question I have been asking institutional investors in both private and public markets is - if they could enter and exit their holdings at will like retail investors(which they cannot today), would they have actually sat through the ride of their best-performing holdings? The answer usually is no. As counterintuitive as it sounds, maybe the inability to easily enter/exit large public or illiquid private holdings forces fund managers to sit tight, which is also why they can outperform retail investors who are always trying to time the market.</description></item><item><title>The flipside of effecient companies</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-flipside-of-effecient-companies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-flipside-of-effecient-companies/</guid><description>https://zenx.medium.com/the-six-dots-problem-re-imagining-india-b7d81b223827 The flip side of tech-first businesses like ours is that we don&amp;rsquo;t create as many jobs. We are around the same number of employees today at 3.8mn clients as we were when we had 1mn clients. As @kunalb11 says, inefficiency is the biggest employer in the world. A way to solve this employment problem is to enable jobs(economy) not just in the top 6 cities, but maybe 600 towns/villages. The only +ve this year has been that maybe some it is happening.</description></item><item><title>Why Zerodha with Nithin</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-with-nithin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-with-nithin/</guid><description>Me answering the most frequently asked question aroung why Zerodha is the broker for you.</description></item><item><title>Downside of working from home</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/downside-of-working-from-home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/downside-of-working-from-home/</guid><description>This year has been ridiculous, I now have &amp;ldquo;spending time with my 5-year-old son&amp;rdquo; scheduled on my calendar. WTF! I was wondering if I was the only insane one until I read this article. https://moretothat.com/the-omnipresence-of-work &amp;ldquo;We are now living amidst the omnipresence of work. Even if we aren’t sitting down working, we are prone to continue thinking about it since the physical environment no longer reminds us to shift our mind state.</description></item><item><title>Forbes cover</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/forbes-cover/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/forbes-cover/</guid><description>https://tradingqna.com/t/personal-lessons-from-20-years-of-trading-broking-working/94600
Almost unreal that we could represent Zerodha on the cover of Forbes. Some personal lessons from the many highs &amp;amp; many lows in this 20-year journey working, trading, trying to build different types of businesses, &amp;amp; more.
Businesses can be built in multiple ways. Don&amp;rsquo;t try to cut-copy-paste what others are doing - it mostly won’t work. Do what feels right to you. Your instincts on what is right will work better when you build a business/career around what you love.</description></item><item><title>The real hockey stick growth worth chasing</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-real-hockey-stick-growth-worth-chasing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-real-hockey-stick-growth-worth-chasing/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The real hockey curve growth we all need to be chasing - seeds (maybe not companies)&amp;quot;. @zenx said while handing over these 50 odd seeds. Seeds that can turn into trees, and in turn result in many more seeds and trees, providing for food and helping the planet for 100&amp;rsquo;s of years.</description></item><item><title>Does technical analysis work?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-technical-analysis-work/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-technical-analysis-work/</guid><description>Am often asked if Technical Analysis actually works. Firstly, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing that just &amp;ldquo;works&amp;rdquo; in trading. But TA works well for retail as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t let you trade against the trend &amp;amp; defines stoploss every trade - main reasons for retail traders&amp;rsquo; losses.</description></item><item><title>CRED curious: Nithin Kamath in conversation with Kunal Shah</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cred-curious-nithin-kamath-in-conversation-with/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cred-curious-nithin-kamath-in-conversation-with/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nudging people towards doing the right things</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-people-towards-doing-the-right-things/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-people-towards-doing-the-right-things/</guid><description>The penny stock Nudge introduced in March on Kite has helped us reduce penny stock trading volume significantly. It has given us hope that the bunch of new nudges we are working on will help our customers stay away from bad trading behavior.</description></item><item><title>The best way of investing in gold</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-of-investing-in-gold/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-of-investing-in-gold/</guid><description>https://tradingqna.com/t/whats-the-best-option-to-invest-in-gold/93314 Seems like everyone is selling digital gold. On digital gold, you lose 3% as GST, upto 2% in commissions, &amp;amp; a spread &amp;gt;5% (buy-sell difference). If you are looking at gold as an investment, Sovereign gold bonds followed by Gold ETF/MFs are the best option.</description></item><item><title>Sitting on a profitable trade is harder than sitting on a loss making trade</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sitting-on-a-profitable-trade-is-harder-than-on-a/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sitting-on-a-profitable-trade-is-harder-than-on-a/</guid><description>Contrary to what most people think, it is much tougher to sit on a profitable trade vs loss-making. All decent traders have a defined stop to handle losing trades. When on profit, we all know we have to let our winners run, but all our biases constantly push us to book profits.</description></item><item><title>Evolution of the Indian stock broking industry since the Harshad Mehta scam - Scam92 TV Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/evolution-of-the-indian-stock-broking-industry-the/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/evolution-of-the-indian-stock-broking-industry-the/</guid><description>#Scam1992TheHarshadMehtaStory - a thread on everything that has changed since then in the world of Indian stockbroking.
Today the settlement cycle is 2 days &amp;amp; SEBI is hinting at a 1-day cycle soon (first few countries in the world). Back then, it was 14 days (the time within which you have to pay full money and take delivery of stocks or deliver stocks if sold).
Today, a customer can’t buy stocks without the minimum money in the account or sell without stocks in Demat.</description></item><item><title>Generalists vs specialists</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/generalists-vs-specialists/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/generalists-vs-specialists/</guid><description>My view on Generalist vs Specialist? Being a jack of all trades helps you grow intellectually &amp;amp; increases odds of finding what you love. But as a business, I think going after one problem(What u love &amp;amp; Core competency) has a much higher chance of success than to spray &amp;amp; hope.</description></item><item><title>Sense of time post-COVID</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sense-of-time-post-covid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sense-of-time-post-covid/</guid><description>https://behavioralscientist.org/time-confetti-and-the-broken-promise-of-leisure Have been wondering why the post-COVID world seems more Busy-ness than Business. This article explains why beautifully - &amp;ldquo;We have more time for leisure than we did fifty years ago. But leisure has never been less relaxing&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Nikhil and Me on SNFConversations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nikhil-and-me-on-snfconversations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nikhil-and-me-on-snfconversations/</guid><description>They say it is tough to be in business with family. @kamath_nikhil &amp;amp; I have been doing stuff together forever, never a fight &amp;amp; couldn&amp;rsquo;t have had a better partner. Btw, it helps when you are like the role modelWinking face. Weirdly first time together on an interview https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oiC-CuyUAK4&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be</description></item><item><title>Nikhil Kamath &amp; Nithin Kamath, Founders of Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nikhil-kamath-nithin-kamath-founders-of-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nikhil-kamath-nithin-kamath-founders-of-zerodha/</guid><description/></item><item><title>ESOP buyback - one of the highlights of the Zerodha journey</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/esop-buyback-one-of-the-highlights-of-the-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/esop-buyback-one-of-the-highlights-of-the-zerodha/</guid><description>We just provided liquidity to everyone on the team through an ESOP buyback. My most satisfying day as CEO of @zerodhaonline .</description></item><item><title>Has there been a surge in investors from tier 2 and 3 cities?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/has-there-been-a-surge-in-investors-from-tier-2-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/has-there-been-a-surge-in-investors-from-tier-2-3/</guid><description>The reason for the noise around markets growing in tier 2/3 cities is because everyone tracks users based on address proof. Lot of people migrate from small towns to cities for jobs but address proof remains the same, hence misleading. By IP address for us: 75% from top 20 cities. Everyone = Financial services firms Map= Google analytics</description></item><item><title>On Zerodha IPO</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-zerodha-ipo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-zerodha-ipo/</guid><description>Thanks for the love @rajeshsawhney , our edge as a business is the agility, it helps us compete against those with deep pockets. IPO invariably will mean losing some of that agility. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if we&amp;rsquo;d want to IPO especially in times like now when everyone seems deep pockets.Grimacing face</description></item><item><title>The Success Story Of Zerodha's SMART Business Journey ft. Nithin Kamath | The Ranveer Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-success-story-of-zerodhas-smart-business-ft/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-success-story-of-zerodhas-smart-business-ft/</guid><description>An interaction with Ranveer from Beer Biceps talking about building Zerodha, how to do business, and life.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping vs Funding – a tax arbitrage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</guid><description>Promoters of businesses to professional investors, now chase “growth” and increase valuations to sell their stake in the business instead of trying to earn profits and taking the earnings out through dividends — to save on taxes and earn more efficiently.</description></item><item><title>Direct Market Access (DMA) for retail investors?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/direct-market-access-dma-for-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/direct-market-access-dma-for-retail-investors/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Stock trading games &amp; copy trading platforms in India?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-trading-games-copy-trading-platforms-in/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-trading-games-copy-trading-platforms-in/</guid><description>My thoughts on copy-trading and social trading platforms and why they aren&amp;rsquo;t feasible in India right now.</description></item><item><title>The Success Story Of Zerodha's SMART Business Journey ft. Nithin Kamath | The Ranveer Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beer-biceps-zerodha-interview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beer-biceps-zerodha-interview/</guid><description/></item><item><title>What does it take to win at trading?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</guid><description>Learnings from interactions with thousands of traders and my own successes and failures.</description></item><item><title>Learning Sessions: Unfiltered deep dive with Nithin Kamath, Founder and CEO, Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/learning-sessions-unfiltered-deep-dive-with-nithin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/learning-sessions-unfiltered-deep-dive-with-nithin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introducing ‘Innerworth – Mind over markets’</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The race to Zero – Can the Indian brokerage industry survive?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-race-to-zero-can-the-indian-brokerage-industry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-race-to-zero-can-the-indian-brokerage-industry/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Zerodha story: Nithin Kamath shares his bootstrapped entrepreneurial journey</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-zerodha-story-nithin-kamath-shares-his-journey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-zerodha-story-nithin-kamath-shares-his-journey/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>