<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>taxation on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/taxation/</link><description>Recent content in taxation on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/taxation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tax filing simplified with Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/tax-filing-simplified-with-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/tax-filing-simplified-with-zerodha/</guid><description>Just about 10 days left to file your taxes. While figuring out taxation for trading and investments is usually a nightmare, we&amp;rsquo;ve made it super easy. I think our tax statements are easily the best in the industry by a mile.
On Console, you’ll find all the statements you need to file taxes for your trades and investments:
Tax P&amp;amp;L statement with trade-wise charges, turnover across all segments, equity and non-equity segregation, capital gains split for pre- and post-July 23, 2024, and more.</description></item><item><title>Bringing down STT in cash market and futures could rebalance market activity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bringing-down-stt-in-cash-market-and-futures-could-rebalance-market-activity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bringing-down-stt-in-cash-market-and-futures-could-rebalance-market-activity/</guid><description>Securities Transaction Tax (STT) is the biggest tax that traders pay, and it&amp;rsquo;s much higher than brokerage fees. At Zerodha, the STT we collect and pass on to the government is higher than the brokerage we earn.
Trading volumes are highly sensitive to the STT. The level of STT also affects whether traders trade more in cash equities, futures, or options. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of concern that Indian options volumes have exploded; I don&amp;rsquo;t think it would be a stretch to say that STT is a big factor in this.</description></item><item><title>What changes for investors after Budget 2024?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-changes-for-investors-after-budget-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-changes-for-investors-after-budget-2024/</guid><description>The change in capital gains in the budget affects all your investments, from stocks, mutual funds, and ETFs to unlisted bonds. Here is a quick snapshot of how the taxation change affects your investments by @Quicko_official. Read more.</description></item><item><title>Saving taxes with HUF</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/saving-taxes-with-huf/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/saving-taxes-with-huf/</guid><description>A friend was asking me about taxation for Hindu Undivided Families (HUF).
If you&amp;rsquo;re married and a Hindu, you can use a HUF to plan and save your taxes. HUF is treated as a separate entity, so all these deductions will apply separately to HUF along with the individual deductions.
So, transferring any property yielding rental income to the HUF, opening a Demat account in the HUF name, transferring money to the HUF bank account, accepting gifts, etc.</description></item><item><title>A quick guide to advance taxes for traders</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-quick-guide-to-advance-tax-for-traders/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-quick-guide-to-advance-tax-for-traders/</guid><description>An important aspect of being an active trader is ensuring you file your taxes on time. But most traders ignore this and end up with notices.
March 15th is the deadline for filing advanced taxes, and many traders think that it may be applicable to them. If you have an estimated tax liability of Rs 10,000 in the form of capital gains, then you have to pay advance taxes.
Profits from F&amp;amp;O and intraday are considered business income, and you will have to estimate their profits for the entire financial year and pay the applicable advance taxes as per the four installments.</description></item><item><title>Addressing tax evasion</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/addressing-tax-evasion/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/addressing-tax-evasion/</guid><description>Govt has to do whatever to curb underreporting of income &amp;amp; tax evasion. Easier said than done, but maybe the better way is to deter people by increasing penalties &amp;amp; acting quickly on financial violations. Those that want to evade taxes or break rules will always find loopholes.</description></item><item><title>Adverse impact of budget on international investing platforms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/adverse-impact-of-the-budget-on-international-investing-platforms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/adverse-impact-of-the-budget-on-international-investing-platforms/</guid><description>For retail investors, I guess the only material change in the budget is for people who invest in international stocks. Money sent out using LRS now has a Tax Collection at Source (TCS) of 20% with no upper or lower threshold, compared to 5% over Rs 7lks earlier.
TCS can be claimed after filing income tax returns at the end of the year, but it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that many will be okay with having 20% of capital blocked until then.</description></item><item><title>Why our financial year start in April</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-our-financial-year-start-in-april/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-our-financial-year-start-in-april/</guid><description>Hmm&amp;hellip;so this is why our financial year starts in April and not Jan, from my 6-year-old son&amp;rsquo;s history factbook. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how I didn&amp;rsquo;t know until now.</description></item><item><title>My reading of crypto post the budget</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-reading-of-crypto-post-budget/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-reading-of-crypto-post-budget/</guid><description>The good news for crypto is that it was finally acknowledged in the budget. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s legal—it will only be after the crypto bill. Until then, regulated entities in India can&amp;rsquo;t offer trading in crypto. Here&amp;rsquo;s my reading of crypto post the budget.
The 30% tax without the option to set-off of losses against other tokens or deductions can lead to a drop in turnover. Market markers &amp;amp; active traders are usually 80%+ of turnover in most trading businesses.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping vs Funding – a tax arbitrage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</guid><description>Promoters of businesses to professional investors, now chase “growth” and increase valuations to sell their stake in the business instead of trying to earn profits and taking the earnings out through dividends — to save on taxes and earn more efficiently.</description></item></channel></rss>