<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>education on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/education/</link><description>Recent content in education on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Financial Literacy Summer Camp for children</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-literacy-summer-camp-for-children/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-literacy-summer-camp-for-children/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s crazy the number of times friends, family, and customers have mentioned that they wish finance was taught when they were in school. Unfortunately, it&amp;rsquo;s too late to fix that - that ship has sailed 😬
We can, however, make sure our kids learn about money. We&amp;rsquo;re doing a Financial Literacy Summer Camp for children via Varsity Live to do just that. Registration link in the comment.
Registration link.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Money Mindful series</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-money-mindful-series/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-money-mindful-series/</guid><description>Despite all the interest in the stock market after COVID, there are still only 5 crore unique mutual fund investors. I&amp;rsquo;ve said this earlier as well—one of the biggest challenges for the Indian markets is the lack of an advisory ecosystem with just about 900 RIAs.
If you consider mutual fund distributors, there are about 2.7 lakh+ plus, but still not enough. For a broad comparison, there are over 27 lakh+ insurance agents.</description></item><item><title>Money mistakes are the best form of financial literacy</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/money-mistakes-are-best-form-of-financial-literacy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/money-mistakes-are-best-form-of-financial-literacy/</guid><description>One good thing about all the post-pandemic excess in the stock market is that the Indian stock market has become a lot younger.
Of course, many of these young investors are doing a lot of things they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be doing. But they are better off making all the mistakes when they are young and have very little to lose, than later in life when they have more money and responsibilities.</description></item><item><title>Update on all our educational content initiatives</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/update-on-all-our-educational-content-initiatives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/update-on-all-our-educational-content-initiatives/</guid><description>Some people, jokingly perhaps, say, &amp;ldquo;Zerodha is a content company.&amp;rdquo; But this isn&amp;rsquo;t something we are doing now. We&amp;rsquo;ve been sharing everything we know about finance, markets, and investing since day 1 of Zerodha in text form—even before &amp;ldquo;content&amp;rdquo; was a thing. In fact, Z-Connect is one of the oldest finance blogs in India.
It&amp;rsquo;s just that now we are publishing a lot more video content across @ZerodhaVarsity, @zerodhamarkets, @zerodhaonline, @Rainmatterin, Zero1 and there&amp;rsquo;s @nikhilkamathcio&amp;rsquo;s WTF and @kmr_dilip&amp;rsquo;s The Other Side as well.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Varsity Live</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-varsity-live/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-varsity-live/</guid><description>If you want to learn anything about trading, investing, and personal finance, I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s a better place than @ZerodhaVarsity. The idea of Varsity began with a random email I sent to @karthikrangappa in 2014, and today, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the most popular free and open resources for all things stock markets, not just in India but maybe globally.
The website has over 15 comprehensive modules and gets millions of hits.</description></item></channel></rss>