<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>personal-finance on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/personal-finance/</link><description>Recent content in personal-finance on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/personal-finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Protect your assets by adding a nominee</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/protect-your-assets-by-adding-a-nominee/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/protect-your-assets-by-adding-a-nominee/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s ₹104,000 crores worth of money and investments lying unclaimed across banks, insurance companies, and mutual funds. The number is from a post by our PM Narendra Modi.
Despite the nomination process being fully online and despite repeated nudges, 62% of Zerodha users with holdings don&amp;rsquo;t have a nominee. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t added any nominees, it takes barely a couple of minutes.
While adding nominees is a good first step, you still have to inform the nominees.</description></item><item><title>Big reasons why term insurance applications get rejected</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/big-reasons-why-term-insurance-applications-get-rejected/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/big-reasons-why-term-insurance-applications-get-rejected/</guid><description>Getting adequate life insurance if you have dependents is the first thing you should do before you save, invest, etc. Having said that, not all life insurance policy applications are approved.
The Ditto team was telling me that 30% of term life insurance applications get rejected. Apparently, one of their biggest teams internally helps customers navigate policy rejections.
Big reasons why applications get rejected.
If you need assistance with insurance, you can schedule a call with an insurance advisor at Ditto</description></item><item><title>Teaching finance and markets online with Varsity Live</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/teaching-finance-and-markets-online-with-varsity-live/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/teaching-finance-and-markets-online-with-varsity-live/</guid><description>I think we&amp;rsquo;ve finally found a way to teach finance and markets online with both quality and scale with Varsity Live.
We&amp;rsquo;ve had 2.3 lakh registrations so far, with about 3,000 new people signing up every week. By the way, this Sunday, the 23rd, we&amp;rsquo;re hosting a finance boot camp for kids. Most of this is a result of people discovering Varsity Live and sharing it with their friends and family.</description></item><item><title>If you spend on what is not necessary, you won't have money for what is necessary</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/if-you-spend-on-what-is-not-necessary-you-wont-have-money-for-what-is-necessary/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/if-you-spend-on-what-is-not-necessary-you-wont-have-money-for-what-is-necessary/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Every time you ask your parents to spend money on things that are not necessary, they have less for what is necessary.&amp;rdquo; A beautiful lesson by @karthikrangappa on the value of money from the 2nd episode of @ZerodhaVarsity Junior. This lesson isn&amp;rsquo;t just for kids but for adults as well. For everyone with kids, this is a fantastic family watch this weekend..</description></item></channel></rss>