<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fitness on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/fitness/</link><description>Recent content in fitness on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/fitness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Shaping healthier habits through participatory sport</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shaping-healthier-habits-through-participatory-sport/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shaping-healthier-habits-through-participatory-sport/</guid><description>At Rainmatter Health, we&amp;rsquo;re experimenting with something beyond just writing checks.
We&amp;rsquo;re creating participatory sports events through an initiative called Peakst8 Club. We&amp;rsquo;ve been going around the country with Founders Peak—getting health founders (and others) to participate, not just network over coffee.
Last weekend was our first grand event: &amp;ldquo;No Parking.&amp;rdquo; Booked the entire basement at Brigade, Orion Mall (thanks, Nirupa Shankar!), Bengaluru. Around 1,000 runners representing 38 corporates, 45 communities, and 43 run clubs were participating in various activities, including running, rowing, cycling, and more.</description></item><item><title>Discussion with Adnan from Devils Circuit on fitness and health</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/discussion-with-adnan-from-devils-circuit-on-fitness-and-health/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/discussion-with-adnan-from-devils-circuit-on-fitness-and-health/</guid><description>Of everyone I’ve met, Adnan has to be one of the most passionate advocates for fitness and getting Indians to participate in active sports. His company, Devils Circuit, has faced its fair share of obstacles and ups and downs — but the mission remains strong: inspiring Indians to take a greater interest in their health and fitness.
And my gut tells me, the time when we truly start caring more about our health is coming soon.</description></item><item><title>Impromptu AMRAP workout</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impromptu-amrap-workout/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impromptu-amrap-workout/</guid><description>Impromptu AMRAP workout when Sisters in Sweat were at work 😀 1 min x pushups.</description></item></channel></rss>