<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>insurance on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/insurance/</link><description>Recent content in insurance on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/insurance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Coin's AUM in the Indian mutual fund industry</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/coins-aum-in-the-indian-mutual-fund-industry/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/coins-aum-in-the-indian-mutual-fund-industry/</guid><description>I just heard this story of a 40-year-old woman mis-sold by a bank. She visited her bank branch and asked to invest in mutual funds, but the manager kept pushing her to invest in an insurance product. She went back and did her homework, and this time she insisted on index mutual funds, but the manager was rude and said she couldn&amp;rsquo;t invest in them through the bank.
After much back and forth, the manager got her to invest in a regular plan of index funds.</description></item><item><title>Top reasons why Insurance companies deny your claim and what you can do about it</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/top-reasons-why-insurance-companies-deny-your-claim-and-what-you-can-do-about-it/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/top-reasons-why-insurance-companies-deny-your-claim-and-what-you-can-do-about-it/</guid><description>Having adequate health insurance for yourself and your family is the most important financial investment you can make. Most Indians are just one serious health incident away from financial ruin. But having insurance alone isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. Just because you have insurance doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean all your claims will be processed. Insurance companies use numerous reasons to either not pay fully or flat-out reject the claims.
It&amp;rsquo;s important to know the common reasons why claims get rejected and what you can do about it.</description></item><item><title>Health insurance should be the biggest priority of your personal finances</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/health-insurance-should-be-the-biggest-priority-of-your-personal-finances/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/health-insurance-should-be-the-biggest-priority-of-your-personal-finances/</guid><description>Buying a health insurance plan for the family is the most important financial investment you can make, given the costs of serious health incidents. Even before you do anything else in your personal finance journey, get health cover to the extent you can afford.
`In 2014, the last year for which data is available, the Avg cost of inpatient care per hospitalisation was Rs 26,475 in urban areas &amp;amp; Rs 16,676 in rural.</description></item><item><title>Making insurance simple</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-insurance-simple/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-insurance-simple/</guid><description>Insurance unfortunately needs to be hard sold today. The issue is that most don’t understand why they need insurance. Even if they do, it&amp;rsquo;s tough to find unbiased advice. There&amp;rsquo;s just too much choice, complexity, mis-selling, &amp;amp; not to mention spam. Scares away most people.
Even at home, dad has bought a lot of horrible policies as investments vs insurance over the years. We have always wanted to do something about this problem.</description></item></channel></rss>