<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>insurance on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/insurance/</link><description>Recent content in insurance on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/insurance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Big reasons why term insurance applications get rejected</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/big-reasons-why-term-insurance-applications-get-rejected/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/big-reasons-why-term-insurance-applications-get-rejected/</guid><description>Getting adequate life insurance if you have dependents is the first thing you should do before you save, invest, etc. Having said that, not all life insurance policy applications are approved.
The Ditto team was telling me that 30% of term life insurance applications get rejected. Apparently, one of their biggest teams internally helps customers navigate policy rejections.
Big reasons why applications get rejected.
If you need assistance with insurance, you can schedule a call with an insurance advisor at Ditto</description></item><item><title>Ditto rebuilding trust in insurance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ditto-rebuilding-trust-in-insurance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ditto-rebuilding-trust-in-insurance/</guid><description>Historically, people haven&amp;rsquo;t bought life and health insurance because of all the scams and spam. The trust deficit in insurance is way too high. People simply don&amp;rsquo;t trust people who sell insurance.
I&amp;rsquo;m really happy that Ditto is doing whatever it can to fix this.</description></item><item><title>Not having life insurance is a bad idea</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/not-having-life-insurance-is-a-bad-idea/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/not-having-life-insurance-is-a-bad-idea/</guid><description>The first thing you should do when you are starting your personal finance journey is to ensure you have sufficient life and health insurance. If you have dependents, not having life insurance is a bad idea.
Based on my interactions with folks, perhaps the biggest reason why they don&amp;rsquo;t have life insurance is because the policies are a nightmare to understand with all sorts of jargon and hidden clauses.
Then there&amp;rsquo;s the fact that insurers keep changing things.</description></item><item><title>Common reasons for claim rejections and how to prevent them</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/common-reasons-for-claim-rejections-and-how-to-prevent-them/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/common-reasons-for-claim-rejections-and-how-to-prevent-them/</guid><description>Having insurance alone isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. Just because you have insurance doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean all your claims will be processed. Insurance companies often don&amp;rsquo;t pay claims in full or flat-out reject the claims.
It&amp;rsquo;s important to know the common reasons why claims get rejected and what you can do about it.
Here are the insurers with the best claim settlement ratio.
Infographics by Ditto</description></item><item><title>All you need to know to select the right health insurance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/all-you-need-to-know-to-select-the-right-health-insurance/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/all-you-need-to-know-to-select-the-right-health-insurance/</guid><description>Most Indians are just 1 hospitalisation away from bankruptcy. A good health insurance plan is mandatory.</description></item><item><title>Misselling of ULIPs and what you can do to avoid being a victim</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/misselling-of-ulips-and-what-you-can-do-to-avoid-falling-victim/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/misselling-of-ulips-and-what-you-can-do-to-avoid-falling-victim/</guid><description>ULIP sales have gone up quite a bit over the last year. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing most ULIPs are sold by banks because of the high commissions on these products.
While ULIPs promise the best of both worlds, that is, both investments and insurance, the reality is that they offer the worst of both worlds. They have high commissions, and most importantly, the insurance cover you get is not enough.
You are better off separating insurance and investments by investing in direct mutual funds and buying a term insurance policy.</description></item><item><title>50% of the policy holders don't pay premiums beyond 5 years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/50-of-the-policy-holders-dont-pay-premiums-beyond-5-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/50-of-the-policy-holders-dont-pay-premiums-beyond-5-years/</guid><description>The persistency ratio of life insurance policies is nearly 50% after five years, which means that only half of those who purchase life insurance keep it active for over five years. Also, if you surrender your policy within this time, you might only get back up to 50% of what you&amp;rsquo;ve paid.
How is that an investment?
Source: @TheKenWeb
We had done a session with @ShrehithK on questions about insurance you might be embarrassed to ask.</description></item><item><title>The basics you need to know when buying health and life insurance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-basics-you-need-to-know-when-buying-health-and-life-insurance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-basics-you-need-to-know-when-buying-health-and-life-insurance/</guid><description>Insurance is the biggest aspect of personal finance that the vast majority of Indians struggle with. One big reason is a lack of awareness about insurance, rampant misselling complexity, spam, etc.
Health insurance and life insurance (term insurance) are the only two products most people need. But the products that are sold the most are ULIPs and other traditional products that promise both insurance and investments but offer the worst of both worlds, not to mention the ridiculous commissions.</description></item><item><title>Coin's AUM in the Indian mutual fund industry</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/coins-aum-in-the-indian-mutual-fund-industry/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/coins-aum-in-the-indian-mutual-fund-industry/</guid><description>I just heard this story of a 40-year-old woman mis-sold by a bank. She visited her bank branch and asked to invest in mutual funds, but the manager kept pushing her to invest in an insurance product. She went back and did her homework, and this time she insisted on index mutual funds, but the manager was rude and said she couldn&amp;rsquo;t invest in them through the bank.
After much back and forth, the manager got her to invest in a regular plan of index funds.</description></item><item><title>Top reasons why Insurance companies deny your claim and what you can do about it</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/top-reasons-why-insurance-companies-deny-your-claim-and-what-you-can-do-about-it/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/top-reasons-why-insurance-companies-deny-your-claim-and-what-you-can-do-about-it/</guid><description>Having adequate health insurance for yourself and your family is the most important financial investment you can make. Most Indians are just one serious health incident away from financial ruin. But having insurance alone isn&amp;rsquo;t enough. Just because you have insurance doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean all your claims will be processed. Insurance companies use numerous reasons to either not pay fully or flat-out reject the claims.
It&amp;rsquo;s important to know the common reasons why claims get rejected and what you can do about it.</description></item><item><title>Health insurance should be the biggest priority of your personal finances</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/health-insurance-should-be-the-biggest-priority-of-your-personal-finances/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/health-insurance-should-be-the-biggest-priority-of-your-personal-finances/</guid><description>Buying a health insurance plan for the family is the most important financial investment you can make, given the costs of serious health incidents. Even before you do anything else in your personal finance journey, get health cover to the extent you can afford.
`In 2014, the last year for which data is available, the Avg cost of inpatient care per hospitalisation was Rs 26,475 in urban areas &amp;amp; Rs 16,676 in rural.</description></item><item><title>Making insurance simple</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-insurance-simple/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-insurance-simple/</guid><description>Insurance unfortunately needs to be hard sold today. The issue is that most don’t understand why they need insurance. Even if they do, it&amp;rsquo;s tough to find unbiased advice. There&amp;rsquo;s just too much choice, complexity, mis-selling, &amp;amp; not to mention spam. Scares away most people.
Even at home, dad has bought a lot of horrible policies as investments vs insurance over the years. We have always wanted to do something about this problem.</description></item></channel></rss>