<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>nris on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/nris/</link><description>Recent content in nris on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/nris/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recent updates to make investing easier for NRIs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recent-updates-to-make-investing-easier-for-nris/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recent-updates-to-make-investing-easier-for-nris/</guid><description>We at Zerodha , have ~40k NRI customers with an average account value of ₹40L, nearly 10x our overall average of ₹3.6L for resident accounts. Most of them opened accounts the hard way, with physical paperwork. If onboarding were fully online, this base would be much larger.
SEBI recently made changes that have allowed us to significantly simplify Non-PIS NRI accounts: they now work like resident accounts, with fully online Aadhaar-based onboarding (when visiting India) and intraday, BTST, and F&amp;amp;O access with no need for a CP code.</description></item><item><title>Easier account opening and lower brokerage for NRI clients</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/easier-account-opening-and-lower-brokerage-for-nri-clients/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/easier-account-opening-and-lower-brokerage-for-nri-clients/</guid><description>The number of NRIs who want to invest in India but don&amp;rsquo;t because of the complex account opening process is quite high. NRI accounts are also much higher in value compared to resident Indian accounts, by at least 10 times.
Hardly a day goes by without emails or messages from NRIs asking us to make account opening easier at Zerodha. The paperwork today is onerous, especially the need to visit an embassy.</description></item><item><title>Simplifying NRI investments at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/simplifying-nri-investments-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/simplifying-nri-investments-at-zerodha/</guid><description>NRI account opening reminds me of how retail broking worked before it became digital, thanks to Aadhaar, e-Sign, and Digilocker. Physical applications, couriers back &amp;amp; forth, ~30+ signatures, &amp;amp; more reasons to drop off. Many NRIs want to invest in India but don&amp;rsquo;t because of the onerous account opening process and the added notarizing &amp;amp; international courier costs.
To open an NRI account, you must fill out physical forms and notarize the documents by visiting banks or embassies.</description></item><item><title>Attracting NRIs by making it easy for them to invest at GIFT City</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/attracting-nris-by-making-it-easy-for-them-to-invest-at-gift-city/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/attracting-nris-by-making-it-easy-for-them-to-invest-at-gift-city/</guid><description>SGXNifty turning to GIFTNifty and moving to India will add momentum for GIFT City to become a true International financial centre. Congrats NSE India and Ashish Chauhan
If we could find a way to allow NRIs to easily invest in India through GIFT, I think we can attract a lot of capital. Due to the cumbersome processes, many NRIs are sitting on the fence and not investing in India.
The NRI account opening process today involves attestation of documents from the embassy, opening PIS bank accounts, and tax deduction at source (TDS) is applicable after every sale transaction.</description></item></channel></rss>