<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>climate change on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/climate-change/</link><description>Recent content in climate change on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/climate-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Women in Koraput, Odisha document the slow disappearance of the commons</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/women-in-koraput/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/women-in-koraput/</guid><description>Women from indigenous communities in Odisha’s Koraput district are mapping their commons — forests, streams, grazing land, and other shared resources they depend on daily.
They’re doing this because these commons are disappearing. Water sources are drying up, forest cover is thinning, and there’s no clear record of what existed, what’s already lost, or how the change happened.
So they went looking for answers. They pulled government records from the 1960s and walked the land, documenting what exists today.</description></item><item><title>What cleaning up pollution looks like when it’s done properly</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-cleaning-up-pollution-looks-like-when-its-done-properly/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-cleaning-up-pollution-looks-like-when-its-done-properly/</guid><description>I was watching this video by Rainmatter Foundation about how Chhatrapati Sambhajinagar (Aurangabad) cleaned up the Kham river in 5 years. It had become a sewage drain, and they turned it back into a flowing river. Made me think about especially of Delhi&amp;rsquo;s air quality problem.
They mapped 249 waste entry points with drones and installed traps. Rerouted sewage to treatment plants and built new ones. Set up a facility for textile waste from factories.</description></item><item><title>Three years of climate action - Rainmatter reflections</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/three-years-of-climate-action-rainmtter-reflections/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/three-years-of-climate-action-rainmtter-reflections/</guid><description>The prelude to starting @RainmatterOrg in 2021, was that we decided to first get our hands dirty and took on a restoration project in 2020. As luck would have it, @zenx was running a campsite on the land, and that&amp;rsquo;s where we met. We hit it off almost immediately, and the Foundation was born.
Three years since we have a solid theme: chasing various intersections of things that impact the climate and the people and lives that it has an effect on.</description></item><item><title>Rainmatter investment in Amwoodo</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-amwoodo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-amwoodo/</guid><description>I thought one of the biggest use case for bamboo was to replace plastic in everyday items like toothbrushes, combs, etc. But when I met Agni from @Amwoodo, I was surprised to learn that bamboo has a higher tensile strength than steel.
Of course, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean, you can replace steel with bamboo, but a lot of use cases open up where you can reduce the use of steel and augment it with bamboo.</description></item></channel></rss>