<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>investing on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/investing/</link><description>Recent content in investing on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/investing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Retail buying spree continues</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/retail-buying-spree-continues/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/retail-buying-spree-continues/</guid><description>One of the crazy things about the last five-odd years is that retail investors have consistently been net buyers of equities. Whether they&amp;rsquo;ll continue to buy the dip is anybody&amp;rsquo;s guess. 😬
By the way, if markets fall sharply, investors might stay out of the market for years—just like they did after 2008.</description></item><item><title>Why ETFs are more popular than mutual funds in the U.S</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-etfs-are-more-popular-than-mutual-funds-in-the-u.s/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-etfs-are-more-popular-than-mutual-funds-in-the-u.s/</guid><description>Something I learned recently on why ETFs in the US are preferred over MFs. 😬
US mutual funds are pass-through vehicles—if they generate capital gains, these must be distributed to unit holders who pay the taxes on the gains which makes MFs less tax-efficient. ETFs avoid this through &amp;lsquo;in-kind&amp;rsquo; creation/redemption that washes away gains. This tax advantage is significant. This is one underrated reason for the popularity of index funds, especially ETFs in the US.</description></item><item><title>India's trading hubs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-trading-hubs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-trading-hubs/</guid><description>Ahmedabad and Mumbai account for 80% of equity delivery trades. Let that sink in. Essentially, the real money is with Gujjus 😬
Btw, Gujarat accounts for just 8% of the total registered investors, and the share has been falling.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Money Mindful series</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-money-mindful-series/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-money-mindful-series/</guid><description>Despite all the interest in the stock market after COVID, there are still only 5 crore unique mutual fund investors. I&amp;rsquo;ve said this earlier as well—one of the biggest challenges for the Indian markets is the lack of an advisory ecosystem with just about 900 RIAs.
If you consider mutual fund distributors, there are about 2.7 lakh+ plus, but still not enough. For a broad comparison, there are over 27 lakh+ insurance agents.</description></item><item><title>New investor demographics in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/new-investor-demographics-in-india/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/new-investor-demographics-in-india/</guid><description>For the longest time, most of the investors in the Indian markets were more or less from the major metro cities. But this has changed dramatically after COVID. The bulk of new investors are from North India, and we&amp;rsquo;ve kinda missed out on getting them to invest with us.
This was something interesting that came up when I was catching up withAshish Chauhan as he shared the NSE India coffee table book.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha's growing AUM and investor profits</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodhas-growing-aum-and-investor-profits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodhas-growing-aum-and-investor-profits/</guid><description>Equity investors at Zerodha have realized a profit of Rs 50,000 crores over the last 4+ years and are sitting on unrealized profits of Rs 1,00,000 crores on an AUM of Rs 4,50,000 crores.
By the way, most of the AUM was added in the last four years.</description></item><item><title>Companies can now issue bonds with face value of Rs.10,000</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/companies-can-now-issue-bonds-with-face-value-of-rs-10000/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/companies-can-now-issue-bonds-with-face-value-of-rs-10000/</guid><description>Companies can now issue bonds with face value of Rs.10,000. This is a great move that can help attract retail participation in the bonds. With all the changes in the last few years, SEBI has done an amazing job of making bonds accessible to small investors.
Read more.</description></item><item><title>Social Stock Exchange for social organizations to raise funds</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/social-stock-exchange-for-social-organizations-to-raise-funds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/social-stock-exchange-for-social-organizations-to-raise-funds/</guid><description>The Social Stock Exchange (SSE) is a platform for social organizations to raise funds from the public. So far, 6 non-profit organizations have raised money, and we are happy to have supported them.
There&amp;rsquo;s no online mechanism to donate to these organizations like we have for regular IPOs but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this will soon be possible. We will then make it possible for all @zerodhaonline customers to support social sector organizations working on important issues.</description></item><item><title>Using passive funds to build the core of your portfolio</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/using-passive-funds-to-build-the-core-of-your-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/using-passive-funds-to-build-the-core-of-your-portfolio/</guid><description>I have a vested interest in saying this 😬 being part of @ZerodhaAMC, but it&amp;rsquo;s a no-brainer to use low-cost index funds for your core portfolio. You can complement that with other funds, but the core should be passive funds.
The data shows it&amp;rsquo;s getting increasingly harder for active funds to outperform their benchmarks.
Link.</description></item><item><title>Why adding a nominee for your demat account is important</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-adding-a-nominee-for-your-demat-account-is-important/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-adding-a-nominee-for-your-demat-account-is-important/</guid><description>Between 50,000 and 80,000 crores of assets are unclaimed across demat accounts, mutual funds, insurance, etc. This is because most investors don&amp;rsquo;t add nominees to their investors. In fact, 72% of Individual investors don&amp;rsquo;t have a nominee for their demat accounts and mutual fund folios. Even if investors do add nominees, they don&amp;rsquo;t tell their nominees.
Life is unpredictable, and anything can happen. It&amp;rsquo;s not a pleasant thought, but making sure life is as comfortable as possible for your loved ones in your absence is a key part of life.</description></item><item><title>Open a Zerodha account for your kids and invest together</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-a-zerodha-a-count-for-your-kids-and-invest-together/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-a-zerodha-a-count-for-your-kids-and-invest-together/</guid><description>You need to know how to manage your money to do well in life. The things you need to know to manage your money well apply to other aspects of life as well. One of the best ways to learn about money is to start early, because the things we learn when we&amp;rsquo;re young tend to stick with us for the rest of our lives. One thing that has been on our to-do list for a long time is to make it as easy for parents to invest for their kids as they teach them about money.</description></item><item><title>Introducing LIQUIDCASE, India's first ETF with a growth NAV</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-liquidcase-indias-first-etf-with-a-growth-nav/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-liquidcase-indias-first-etf-with-a-growth-nav/</guid><description>LIQUIDCASE, India&amp;rsquo;s first ETF with a growth NAV from ZerodhaAMC just listed today with the same symbol. When we were thinking about the product, we wanted to offer something simple where investors didn&amp;rsquo;t have to bother about dividends, taxes etc.
So, the way LIQUIDCASE works is simple: the returns in the ETF will be added to the NAV just like growth mutual funds, and there are no dividends. This makes it easier for you to track your returns, and there are no hassles with fractional units and figuring out your taxes.</description></item><item><title>SEBI's proposal to offer affordable corporate bonds and increase retail investor participation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-proposal-to-offer-affordable-corporate-bonds-and-increase-retail-investor-participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-proposal-to-offer-affordable-corporate-bonds-and-increase-retail-investor-participation/</guid><description>The latest consultation proposal by SEBI to reduce corporate bonds&amp;rsquo; face value to Rs 10,000 can lead to greater retail participation in the bond markets.
I think for the majority of our country, i.e. beyond the top 5 to 10% of the country yet to start investing, equities may not be the right instruments because they can be scary because of the volatility. A bad market phase or losses when they start will end with investors permanently leaving the markets.</description></item><item><title>Performance of equity investors and mutual fund investors at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/performance-of-equity-investors-and-mutual-fund-investors-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/performance-of-equity-investors-and-mutual-fund-investors-at-zerodha/</guid><description>As strange as it sounds, our equity investors are sitting on higher overall notional gains than equity mutual fund investors.
Maybe the popular narrative that retail investors are clueless and “gambling” isn’t fully accurate. That’s because you would expect direct equity investors to do worse than mutual fund investors.
Disclaimer: Most of our AUM was added post-2020, which is one of the biggest bull markets India has seen.</description></item><item><title>Indian fascination with America and it's investment potential</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-fascination-with-america-and-its-investment-potential/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-fascination-with-america-and-its-investment-potential/</guid><description>Most Americans I know with money want to invest in India because they believe they are plateauing as a nation and that we are the future. But somehow, young Indians are still bitten by the bug to travel to America to build their future. This is such a dichotomy.
Credits: The Ken</description></item><item><title>Simplifying NRI investments at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/simplifying-nri-investments-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/simplifying-nri-investments-at-zerodha/</guid><description>NRI account opening reminds me of how retail broking worked before it became digital, thanks to Aadhaar, e-Sign, and Digilocker. Physical applications, couriers back &amp;amp; forth, ~30+ signatures, &amp;amp; more reasons to drop off. Many NRIs want to invest in India but don&amp;rsquo;t because of the onerous account opening process and the added notarizing &amp;amp; international courier costs.
To open an NRI account, you must fill out physical forms and notarize the documents by visiting banks or embassies.</description></item><item><title>Indian startups will do well despite the negativity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-startups-will-do-well-despite-the-negativity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-startups-will-do-well-despite-the-negativity/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Investment is the discipline of relative selection” - Sid Cottle.
Indian startups will most likely continue to attract foreign capital even if all the news might make it seem otherwise. This is mainly because we are the fastest-growing country in the world, and investing is about selecting the best from all the existing options. It is a relative decision, and global investors have to invest.
By the way, anecdotally talking to some international investors, Indian startups seem to be faring better in the last year or so, where the focus has been more on reducing burn &amp;amp; getting on the path to profitability.</description></item><item><title>Financialization of India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financialization-of-india/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financialization-of-india/</guid><description>NSE just announced that there are 15 crore investors registered, of which 8 crore are unique. Much of this growth has come in the last 3–4 years. The pace of financialization is crazy, and this is in no small part thanks to the exchanges, especially NSE. This is vital for India to grow.
A case in point, this year, total Sovereign Gold Bonds (SGB) issued is ~10% of total gold imports.</description></item><item><title>If you spend on what is not necessary, you won't have money for what is necessary</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/if-you-spend-on-what-is-not-necessary-you-wont-have-money-for-what-is-necessary/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/if-you-spend-on-what-is-not-necessary-you-wont-have-money-for-what-is-necessary/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Every time you ask your parents to spend money on things that are not necessary, they have less for what is necessary.&amp;rdquo; A beautiful lesson by @karthikrangappa on the value of money from the 2nd episode of @ZerodhaVarsity Junior. This lesson isn&amp;rsquo;t just for kids but for adults as well. For everyone with kids, this is a fantastic family watch this weekend..</description></item><item><title>Attracting NRIs by making it easy for them to invest at GIFT City</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/attracting-nris-by-making-it-easy-for-them-to-invest-at-gift-city/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/attracting-nris-by-making-it-easy-for-them-to-invest-at-gift-city/</guid><description>SGXNifty turning to GIFTNifty and moving to India will add momentum for GIFT City to become a true International financial centre. Congrats NSE India and Ashish Chauhan
If we could find a way to allow NRIs to easily invest in India through GIFT, I think we can attract a lot of capital. Due to the cumbersome processes, many NRIs are sitting on the fence and not investing in India.
The NRI account opening process today involves attestation of documents from the embassy, opening PIS bank accounts, and tax deduction at source (TDS) is applicable after every sale transaction.</description></item><item><title>Encouraging wealthy Indian investors to invest in Indian entrepreneurs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/encouraging-wealthy-indian-investors-to-invest-in-indian-entrepreneurs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/encouraging-wealthy-indian-investors-to-invest-in-indian-entrepreneurs/</guid><description>UK offers 50% tax relief &amp;amp; capital gains exemption for startup investments. This seems a great way to incentivize wealthy to invest in startups. We maybe need similar schemes to reduce our dependency on foreign VCs &amp;amp; better use our local wealth stuck in Gold, Real estate &amp;amp; FDs.
The biggest problem to solve in India is to spread wealth inclusively &amp;amp; not just in the top 1%.
This is possible only when wealth creation can be captured by a large subset of Indians when Indian businesses do well.</description></item><item><title>Earning higher returns than savings bank accounts and fixed deposits with treasury bills (T-bills)</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/earning-higher-returns-than-savings-bank-accounts-and-fixed-deposits-with-treasury-bills/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/earning-higher-returns-than-savings-bank-accounts-and-fixed-deposits-with-treasury-bills/</guid><description>We all behave irrationally when it comes to money. For, e.g. Rs 60 lakh crores Src: @IndiaDataHub in savings bank accounts earn sub-par returns. Not all of it is for investing, but still. This status-quo bias could mean over Rs 1 lakh crores annually, if 3% more on SB rate.
Many startups keep idle funds they don&amp;rsquo;t need for the short term in their current bank accounts that generate no interest income.</description></item><item><title>SEBI cracks down on pump and dump scams on social media</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cracks-down-on-pump-and-dump-scams-on-social-media/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cracks-down-on-pump-and-dump-scams-on-social-media/</guid><description>SEBI is killing it with these enforcement orders 🔥
Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s against the pump &amp;amp; dump schemes peddled by selling greed &amp;amp; unrealistic returns through social media &amp;amp; YouTube should serve as a powerful deterrent. These scams had become the easiest game in town for manipulators.
These elaborate orders should hopefully put some fear amongst unauthorized tipsters and people offering unauthorized portfolio management services. Such actors damage the sanctity of capital markets in India.</description></item><item><title>Digitising onboarding to attract NRI investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/digitising-onboarding-to-attract-nri-investors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/digitising-onboarding-to-attract-nri-investors/</guid><description>Allowing NRIs to open demat accounts online is the low-hanging fruit to attract money to India. The process today is physical and cumbersome.
With Indian markets doing well, there&amp;rsquo;s a great interest to invest here, but the tough onboard process leads to massive dropoffs.
Since NRIs send and receive funds from bank accounts with KYC, we can make onboarding fully digital and make it as easy as it is for a resident Indian to open a trading account.</description></item><item><title>Regulatory measures to improve retail participation in corprate bonds</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/regulatory-measures-to-improve-retail-participation-in-corprate-bonds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/regulatory-measures-to-improve-retail-participation-in-corprate-bonds/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve always believed that bonds and maybe not stocks are the right stepping stone for most Indians—better than FD returns but lower risk than stocks.
But bonds have been an HNI product, and no one sold them to retail. But SEBI has just made some important changes recently.
There were two big issues:
Availability of bonds with small face values. Most bonds are issued through private placements and have face values of Rs 10lakh+.</description></item><item><title>The Netflix series on Bernie Madoff is must watch for investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-netflix-series-on-bernie-madoff-is-must-watch-for-investors/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-netflix-series-on-bernie-madoff-is-must-watch-for-investors/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;No matter how much information and context you have, nothing is more persuasive than what you desperately want or need to be true.&amp;rdquo; - @morganhousel
People want double the returns with half the risk, which isn&amp;rsquo;t possible.
Must watch for investors.</description></item><item><title>The importance of financial literacy in schools</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-financial-literacy-in-schools/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-financial-literacy-in-schools/</guid><description>I still remember the formula for the area of a circle or that CH3OH is Methanol from school. Similarly, If we taught finance basics in school, like why start investing early, inflation, insurance, retirement planning, etc. These lessons will be helpful throughout life.
Thanks, Tejasvi Surya, for bringing this up at the parliament. We have the experience of running Zerodha Varsity, amongst the largest free educational platforms on financial education. Karthik Rangappa and I would love to help the Ministry of Eduction in any way.</description></item><item><title>Slow growth vs debt fuelled fast growth</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/slow-growth-vs-debt-fuelled-fast-growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/slow-growth-vs-debt-fuelled-fast-growth/</guid><description>A saving mindset is what will help us in times like now when countries that have borrowed heavily are getting screwed? In a world of rising interest rates, this will probably get much worse before it gets better for them.
Isn&amp;rsquo;t slow &amp;amp; steady growth much better (like compounding in investing) than debt-fuelled explosive growth where people borrow to buy depreciating assets? Neither good for customers nor for businesses in the long run.</description></item><item><title>Basics of Government bonds</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/basics-of-government-bonds/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/basics-of-government-bonds/</guid><description>The yields on Govt bonds have risen substantially this year and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of interest from investors. But we also get a lot of questions from investors about how Govt bonds work.
Let&amp;rsquo;s understand the basics in this thread
The Govt needs money to finance various activities such as health, infrastructure, defence &amp;amp; other obligations.
So, the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) issues bonds on behalf of the central and state governments to raise money to fund these activities.</description></item><item><title>T-bills &amp; G-secs are much better than a bank fixed deposits</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/tbills-and-gsecs-are-much-better-than-a-bank-fixed-deposits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/tbills-and-gsecs-are-much-better-than-a-bank-fixed-deposits/</guid><description>At current rates, T-bills &amp;amp; G-secs are much better than a bank FD.
Most people still don&amp;rsquo;t know that you can easily buy T-bills &amp;amp; G-Secs on exchanges/your trading a/c without CSGL etc.
Btw, they&amp;rsquo;re open for investing every Monday on @CoinByZerodha https://coin.zerodha.com/gsec</description></item><item><title>A few basics of retirement planning</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-basics-of-retirement-planning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-basics-of-retirement-planning/</guid><description>What Gen Z &amp;amp; even millennials don&amp;rsquo;t think about enough is that the retirement age is dropping fast due to technological progress &amp;amp; life expectancy going up due to medical progress. In 20 years, retirement could be at 50 &amp;amp; life expectancy at 80. How do you fund the 30 years?
If climate change doesn&amp;rsquo;t kill us all, retirement crisis will probably be the biggest problem for most countries 25 years from now.</description></item><item><title>Things to keep in mind when investing in stocks that have seen big price drops</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/things-to-keep-in-mind-when-investing-in-stocks-that-have-seen-big-price-drops/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/things-to-keep-in-mind-when-investing-in-stocks-that-have-seen-big-price-drops/</guid><description>Every time the prices of retail favorite stocks fall, the number of investors who buy the stock goes up dramatically. We saw this with Yes bank, Reliance ADAG stocks, and now with Zomato. Investing is risky &amp;amp; here are some important things retail investors should keep in mind
In the business of investing, if a stock price is down and it seems like it is a cheap buy, odds are, it will continue to become cheaper.</description></item><item><title>Cybercrime risks when trading</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cybercrime-risks-when-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cybercrime-risks-when-trading/</guid><description>Thanks to Anil Singhvi and Zee Business for highlighting the cybercrime risks when trading the markets. Cybercrime has gone up across banking to broking to social media. We must be extra vigilant. Here&amp;rsquo;s everything we&amp;rsquo;re doing at Zerodha.
Money cannot be withdrawn from trading accounts to 3rd party bank accounts. To move money, fraudsters create artificial losses by trading illiquid options (buy high, sell low) or buying scammy penny stocks. Our best bet is to find ways to block such suspicious trades.</description></item><item><title>Follow up on thoughts on real estate performance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/follow-up-thoughts-on-real-estate-performance/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/follow-up-thoughts-on-real-estate-performance/</guid><description>The question to ask when investing in real estate: Is the property yield greater than inflation?
Yield = ((Rent – interest - maintenance)/Total cost)%
If yield -ve, the price has to go up by at least 10% per yr to beat inflation, or the price has to double every ~7 years.
For the price of the property to double every 7 yrs, the rents also have to go up as much.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on real estate performance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/thoughts-on-real-estate-performance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/thoughts-on-real-estate-performance/</guid><description>Being overexposed to real estate worked well for the current &amp;gt; 50-year-olds, as returns beat inflation+interest costs by a fair bit until the early 2010s. But that isn&amp;rsquo;t the case anymore &amp;amp; reason why the current &amp;lt; 50-year-olds have to think twice about how much real estate.
At today&amp;rsquo;s prices, real estate is unlikely to beat inflation + interest costs in the long run. A house will provide financial &amp;amp; emotional security, but financial returns as an investment won&amp;rsquo;t be enough to cover for retirement as in the past.</description></item><item><title>Why I stopped trading</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-i-stopped-trading/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-i-stopped-trading/</guid><description>I get asked often, why stop trading? Trading isn&amp;rsquo;t just trading stocks, It&amp;rsquo;s trading your time and efforts to do things, where the risk to reward is most in your favour. While I have stopped trading stocks actively, Zerodha is by far the biggest trade of my life.
Nikhil Kamath is a much better trader than me. When we started, idea was he would trade &amp;amp; I attempt to build Zerodha.</description></item><item><title>Impressive yields on Government Securities</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impressive.yields.on.government.securities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impressive.yields.on.government.securities/</guid><description>One of those times when Govt T-Bills are yielding more than most 1-year fixed deposit rates of banks. G-Sec yields are far higher.
Btw, you can invest in T-Bills, G-Secs and SDLs on Coin.</description></item><item><title>NSE reintroduces Do Not Excersise (DNE)</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nse-reintroduces-do-not-excersise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nse-reintroduces-do-not-excersise/</guid><description>The Do Not Exercise (DNE) facility for stock options is reintroduced from this expiry onwards. The removal of DNE had increased the risk of losses for traders if OTM options suddendly became ITM.</description></item><item><title>A nudge to stop people from buying stocks that are going to zero</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-nudge-to-stop-people-from-buying-stocks-that-are-going-to-zero/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-nudge-to-stop-people-from-buying-stocks-that-are-going-to-zero/</guid><description>It is concerning that we have a few customers still buying Sintex shares even after this nudge that the stock price will go to 0 and mandating a TOTP. There are so many who decide to buy just because a stock is at 52 week or all-time lows without caring about the reason.</description></item><item><title>Impact of STT on traders, exchanges and brokerages</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-stt-on-traders-exchanges-brokers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-stt-on-traders-exchanges-brokers/</guid><description>Every budget day for the last 15+ years, I&amp;rsquo;ve woken up hoping that STT is reduced. Zerodha customers alone pay ~₹2500 cores in STT, stamp duty, &amp;amp; GST annually. Overall, traders lose more money in transaction costs &amp;amp; impact costs than to the markets.
Lower txn costs improve liquidity, hence decrease impact costs. But on flip side, you could argue that people may speculate more, which isn&amp;rsquo;t good—one reason for Nudges on Kite.</description></item><item><title>Advisory is one the biggest Indian fintech opportunity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-biggest-fintech-opportunity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-biggest-fintech-opportunity/</guid><description>One of the biggest Indian fintech opportunities is advisory to help Indians manage their personal finances better—investments, insurance etc. For this to happen, Account aggregator will have to do what UPI did for payments. Hoping all banks, depositories, &amp;amp; RTAs will be on AA.</description></item><item><title>India is addicted to gold</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indians-and-gold/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indians-and-gold/</guid><description>Over $400billion went out of India to import gold vs $600 billion+ that came in through FPI, FDI &amp;amp; VC. Imagine, instead of gold, some of that money was invested in Indian startups &amp;amp; listed companies. There could&amp;rsquo;ve been immense and inclusive local wealth creation.
I think the goal of every Indian fintech firm focusing on savings and investing should be to nudge people to back Indian entrepreneurs and think long term.</description></item><item><title>A must watch interview of Rakesh Jhunjhunwala</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/must-watch-interview-of-rakesh-jhunjhunwala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/must-watch-interview-of-rakesh-jhunjhunwala/</guid><description>This RJ chat is a must-watch
The common thing among successful traders &amp;amp; entrepreneurs is to always think in terms of risk to reward. They take a trade—buy a stock or take a business bet—only if they&amp;rsquo;ve made peace with the worst possible outcome
An understanding that leverage (debt) is merciless &amp;amp; a double-edged sword. If at all they need to use leverage, it&amp;rsquo;s only a small portion of their networth.</description></item><item><title>Illiquidity premium</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/illquidity-and-the-temptation-of-selling-quick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/illquidity-and-the-temptation-of-selling-quick/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve asked a lot of successful MF, PE &amp;amp; VC managers if they would be able to resist the temptation to time the market and hold on to profitable investments if they could easily exit &amp;amp; enter investments like retail investors. The answer is almost always &amp;ldquo;hmm&amp;hellip; probably, not&amp;rdquo;.
The inability to time the market due to size constraints &amp;amp; illiquidity—especially in private markets forces fund managers to follow the fundamental investing rule—letting your winners run.</description></item><item><title>Nudging users to help them avoid mistakes</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-users-to-help-them-avoid-mistakes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-users-to-help-them-avoid-mistakes/</guid><description>Most people don&amp;rsquo;t spend time learning trading or forget what they&amp;rsquo;ve learnt when placing an order. The order placement step is also when users pay maximum attention. With &amp;ldquo;Nudge&amp;rdquo; we are now able to leverage that fraction of a second to educate users &amp;amp; help them avoid mistakes.
This Nudge on DHFL warning customers that the investment may go to 0 discouraged over 50% of our users from taking a trade.</description></item><item><title>The biggest wealth destroyer when investing</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/biggest-wealth-destroyer-when-investing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/biggest-wealth-destroyer-when-investing/</guid><description>What is the biggest wealth destroyer when investing?
Averaging down or buying more of an asset, be it stock or crypto, as the price keeps going down and hoping that the price bounces to recover losses or make profits faster. Common behaviour among retail investors.
While it is tempting to average down, the odds of this strategy working are significantly low in the long run. All it takes is one large move on the other side for things to go wrong.</description></item><item><title>The risk of offering high leverages</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-of-offering-high-leverages/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-of-offering-high-leverages/</guid><description>When a platform offers leverage or funds the customer to buy for more than the money in the account, the platform takes a credit risk. With Crypto exchanges offering 10 to 100x leverage (futures), on days like today, I wonder who monitors liquidity position of these platforms.
In regulated space, even with all checks &amp;amp; balances, brokerage firms once in a while on days of extreme volatility go bust. If exchange offers 50x leverage &amp;amp; say Bitcoin goes down 4% in one tick, a customer with $1K, can lose $2K.</description></item><item><title>On the Panic With Friends podcast with Howard Lindzon</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/panic-with-friends-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/panic-with-friends-podcast/</guid><description>This was a really fun conversation with Howard.</description></item><item><title>The pandemic has shown us it's the right time to move away from cities</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/moving-away-from-large-cities/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/moving-away-from-large-cities/</guid><description>While we all work together to figure out what we can do to help in the current situation, I think the only long-term fix is for as many of us to move away from large cities. This is the answer to many of India’s problems. And now is probably the right time to work towards it.
Large cities are choking &amp;amp; will continue to break down every time we&amp;rsquo;re tested, COVID today, could be water shortages, pollution, floods, etc.</description></item><item><title>Mis-selling is a systemic issue.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/misselling-is-a-systemic-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/misselling-is-a-systemic-issues/</guid><description>This is a more systemic issue, not with one bank but across the board, banks to ed-tech to fintech. As long as you give revenue targets &amp;amp; push employees to get there, products that generate more revenue for the business over what is right for the customer will be mis-sold.
Easier for employees of banks, brokerages, wealth management firms to mis-sell as relationships are already established &amp;amp; there is trust with the brand, which is why the customer has allowed them to be custodians of their assets.</description></item><item><title>A nudge to stop people from losing money in Rights Entitlements</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudge-to-stop-people-from-losing-money-in-rights-entitlements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudge-to-stop-people-from-losing-money-in-rights-entitlements/</guid><description>Many retail investors buy Rights Entitlements (REs) without knowing that the value of REs will be zero if they don&amp;rsquo;t apply. Since May 2020 our clients have lost ~Rs 10cr by buying Rights entitlements &amp;amp; not applying. We now have a nudge to warn customers. Read about it here.</description></item><item><title>Enabling women to start making financial decisions</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/enabling-women-to-start-making-financial-decisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/enabling-women-to-start-making-financial-decisions/</guid><description>This video from Paytm captures what we need to do most as a country - educate &amp;amp; enable as many women as possible to start making financial decisions. In my personal experience, women manage risk better than men, so they&amp;rsquo;ll probably take better financial decisions #womensday2021</description></item><item><title>The best way of investing in gold</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-of-investing-in-gold/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-of-investing-in-gold/</guid><description>https://tradingqna.com/t/whats-the-best-option-to-invest-in-gold/93314 Seems like everyone is selling digital gold. On digital gold, you lose 3% as GST, upto 2% in commissions, &amp;amp; a spread &amp;gt;5% (buy-sell difference). If you are looking at gold as an investment, Sovereign gold bonds followed by Gold ETF/MFs are the best option.</description></item></channel></rss>