<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>investing on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/investing/</link><description>Recent content in investing on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/investing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>NSE reintroduces Do Not Excersise (DNE)</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nse-reintroduces-do-not-excersise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nse-reintroduces-do-not-excersise/</guid><description>The Do Not Exercise (DNE) facility for stock options is reintroduced from this expiry onwards. The removal of DNE had increased the risk of losses for traders if OTM options suddendly became ITM.</description></item><item><title>A nudge to stop people from buying stocks that are going to zero</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-nudge-to-stop-people-from-buying-stocks-that-are-going-to-zero/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-nudge-to-stop-people-from-buying-stocks-that-are-going-to-zero/</guid><description>It is concerning that we have a few customers still buying Sintex shares even after this nudge that the stock price will go to 0 and mandating a TOTP. There are so many who decide to buy just because a stock is at 52 week or all-time lows without caring about the reason.</description></item><item><title>Impact of STT on traders, exchanges and brokerages</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-stt-on-traders-exchanges-brokers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-stt-on-traders-exchanges-brokers/</guid><description>Every budget day for the last 15+ years, I&amp;rsquo;ve woken up hoping that STT is reduced. Zerodha customers alone pay ~₹2500 cores in STT, stamp duty, &amp;amp; GST annually. Overall, traders lose more money in transaction costs &amp;amp; impact costs than to the markets.
Lower txn costs improve liquidity, hence decrease impact costs. But on flip side, you could argue that people may speculate more, which isn&amp;rsquo;t good—one reason for Nudges on Kite.</description></item><item><title>Advisory is one the biggest Indian fintech opportunity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-biggest-fintech-opportunity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-biggest-fintech-opportunity/</guid><description>One of the biggest Indian fintech opportunities is advisory to help Indians manage their personal finances better—investments, insurance etc. For this to happen, Account aggregator will have to do what UPI did for payments. Hoping all banks, depositories, &amp;amp; RTAs will be on AA.</description></item><item><title>India is addicted to gold</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indians-and-gold/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indians-and-gold/</guid><description>Over $400billion went out of India to import gold vs $600 billion+ that came in through FPI, FDI &amp;amp; VC. Imagine, instead of gold, some of that money was invested in Indian startups &amp;amp; listed companies. There could&amp;rsquo;ve been immense and inclusive local wealth creation.
I think the goal of every Indian fintech firm focusing on savings and investing should be to nudge people to back Indian entrepreneurs and think long term.</description></item><item><title>A must watch interview of Rakesh Jhunjhunwala</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/must-watch-interview-of-rakesh-jhunjhunwala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/must-watch-interview-of-rakesh-jhunjhunwala/</guid><description>This RJ chat is a must-watch
The common thing among successful traders &amp;amp; entrepreneurs is to always think in terms of risk to reward. They take a trade—buy a stock or take a business bet—only if they&amp;rsquo;ve made peace with the worst possible outcome
An understanding that leverage (debt) is merciless &amp;amp; a double-edged sword. If at all they need to use leverage, it&amp;rsquo;s only a small portion of their networth.</description></item><item><title>Illiquidity premium</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/illquidity-and-the-temptation-of-selling-quick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/illquidity-and-the-temptation-of-selling-quick/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve asked a lot of successful MF, PE &amp;amp; VC managers if they would be able to resist the temptation to time the market and hold on to profitable investments if they could easily exit &amp;amp; enter investments like retail investors. The answer is almost always &amp;ldquo;hmm&amp;hellip; probably, not&amp;rdquo;.
The inability to time the market due to size constraints &amp;amp; illiquidity—especially in private markets forces fund managers to follow the fundamental investing rule—letting your winners run.</description></item><item><title>Nudging users to help them avoid mistakes</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-users-to-help-them-avoid-mistakes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-users-to-help-them-avoid-mistakes/</guid><description>Most people don&amp;rsquo;t spend time learning trading or forget what they&amp;rsquo;ve learnt when placing an order. The order placement step is also when users pay maximum attention. With &amp;ldquo;Nudge&amp;rdquo; we are now able to leverage that fraction of a second to educate users &amp;amp; help them avoid mistakes.
This Nudge on DHFL warning customers that the investment may go to 0 discouraged over 50% of our users from taking a trade.</description></item><item><title>The biggest wealth destroyer when investing</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/biggest-wealth-destroyer-when-investing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/biggest-wealth-destroyer-when-investing/</guid><description>What is the biggest wealth destroyer when investing?
Averaging down or buying more of an asset, be it stock or crypto, as the price keeps going down and hoping that the price bounces to recover losses or make profits faster. Common behaviour among retail investors.
While it is tempting to average down, the odds of this strategy working are significantly low in the long run. All it takes is one large move on the other side for things to go wrong.</description></item><item><title>The risk of offering high leverages</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-of-offering-high-leverages/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-of-offering-high-leverages/</guid><description>When a platform offers leverage or funds the customer to buy for more than the money in the account, the platform takes a credit risk. With Crypto exchanges offering 10 to 100x leverage (futures), on days like today, I wonder who monitors liquidity position of these platforms.
In regulated space, even with all checks &amp;amp; balances, brokerage firms once in a while on days of extreme volatility go bust. If exchange offers 50x leverage &amp;amp; say Bitcoin goes down 4% in one tick, a customer with $1K, can lose $2K.</description></item><item><title>On the Panic With Friends podcast with Howard Lindzon</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/panic-with-friends-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/panic-with-friends-podcast/</guid><description>This was a really fun conversation with Howard.</description></item><item><title>The pandemic has shown us it's the right time to move away from cities</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/moving-away-from-large-cities/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/moving-away-from-large-cities/</guid><description>While we all work together to figure out what we can do to help in the current situation, I think the only long-term fix is for as many of us to move away from large cities. This is the answer to many of India’s problems. And now is probably the right time to work towards it.
Large cities are choking &amp;amp; will continue to break down every time we&amp;rsquo;re tested, COVID today, could be water shortages, pollution, floods, etc.</description></item><item><title>Mis-selling is a systemic issue.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/misselling-is-a-systemic-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/misselling-is-a-systemic-issues/</guid><description>This is a more systemic issue, not with one bank but across the board, banks to ed-tech to fintech. As long as you give revenue targets &amp;amp; push employees to get there, products that generate more revenue for the business over what is right for the customer will be mis-sold.
Easier for employees of banks, brokerages, wealth management firms to mis-sell as relationships are already established &amp;amp; there is trust with the brand, which is why the customer has allowed them to be custodians of their assets.</description></item><item><title>A nudge to stop people from losing money in Rights Entitlements</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudge-to-stop-people-from-losing-money-in-rights-entitlements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudge-to-stop-people-from-losing-money-in-rights-entitlements/</guid><description>Many retail investors buy Rights Entitlements (REs) without knowing that the value of REs will be zero if they don&amp;rsquo;t apply. Since May 2020 our clients have lost ~Rs 10cr by buying Rights entitlements &amp;amp; not applying. We now have a nudge to warn customers. Read about it here.</description></item><item><title>Enabling women to start making financial decisions</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/enabling-women-to-start-making-financial-decisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/enabling-women-to-start-making-financial-decisions/</guid><description>This video from Paytm captures what we need to do most as a country - educate &amp;amp; enable as many women as possible to start making financial decisions. In my personal experience, women manage risk better than men, so they&amp;rsquo;ll probably take better financial decisions #womensday2021</description></item><item><title>The best way of investing in gold</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-of-investing-in-gold/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-of-investing-in-gold/</guid><description>https://tradingqna.com/t/whats-the-best-option-to-invest-in-gold/93314 Seems like everyone is selling digital gold. On digital gold, you lose 3% as GST, upto 2% in commissions, &amp;amp; a spread &amp;gt;5% (buy-sell difference). If you are looking at gold as an investment, Sovereign gold bonds followed by Gold ETF/MFs are the best option.</description></item></channel></rss>