<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>investing on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/investing/</link><description>Recent content in investing on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/investing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Technical issue at a depository disrupting settlement</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/technical-issue-at-a-depository-disrupting-settlement/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/technical-issue-at-a-depository-disrupting-settlement/</guid><description>There was a technical issue at one of the depositories this week that disrupted settlement and had a cascading effect on the market. Since many people may not fully understand how settlement works, let me explain what happened.
When you buy or sell stocks, the trade settles on T+1. The Clearing Corporation (CC) determines the net obligations. Meaning who owes shares and who owes money and instructs the depositories (NSDL/CDSL) to move shares between sellers’ and buyers’ demat accounts via their brokers (Depository Participants).</description></item><item><title>Recent updates to make investing easier for NRIs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recent-updates-to-make-investing-easier-for-nris/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recent-updates-to-make-investing-easier-for-nris/</guid><description>We at Zerodha , have ~40k NRI customers with an average account value of ₹40L, nearly 10x our overall average of ₹3.6L for resident accounts. Most of them opened accounts the hard way, with physical paperwork. If onboarding were fully online, this base would be much larger.
SEBI recently made changes that have allowed us to significantly simplify Non-PIS NRI accounts: they now work like resident accounts, with fully online Aadhaar-based onboarding (when visiting India) and intraday, BTST, and F&amp;amp;O access with no need for a CP code.</description></item><item><title>Check IPO lock-in period expiry on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-ipo-lock-in-period-expiry-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-ipo-lock-in-period-expiry-on-kite/</guid><description>When a company goes for an IPO, not all shareholders can sell their shares immediately. Certain categories of shareholders like promoters, early investors and ESOP holders have to wait anywhere between 30 days to 18 months before they can sell their shares.
Since these are large shareholders, whenever they sell, there can often be a downward move in the stock price. So if you are buying shares of companies that IPO&amp;rsquo;d recently, you should track when the lock-in period expires.</description></item><item><title>Risk management lessons from Tom Basso</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-lessons-from-tom-basso/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-lessons-from-tom-basso/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been noticing many recent IPOs continue running up for 2-3 days after listing. While demand and supply factors (limited free float) are obvious reasons, there may also be technical factors at play.
One common reason why traders blow up is because of poor position sizing. In other words, how much do you bet on a trade.
You can be right on direction 60% of the time and still lose everything if you size your positions poorly.</description></item><item><title>Why some IPOs keep rising even after listing day</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-some-ipos-keep-rising-even-after-listing-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-some-ipos-keep-rising-even-after-listing-day/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been noticing many recent IPOs continue running up for 2-3 days after listing. While demand and supply factors (limited free float) are obvious reasons, there may also be technical factors at play.
Let me explain the technical factor.
Many traders attempt to short these stocks intraday, expecting a fall, but if the stock hits the upper circuit, they get trapped with no buyers to sell to. This leads to what’s called a short delivery.</description></item><item><title>Protect your assets by adding a nominee</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/protect-your-assets-by-adding-a-nominee/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/protect-your-assets-by-adding-a-nominee/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s ₹104,000 crores worth of money and investments lying unclaimed across banks, insurance companies, and mutual funds. The number is from a post by our PM Narendra Modi.
Despite the nomination process being fully online and despite repeated nudges, 62% of Zerodha users with holdings don&amp;rsquo;t have a nominee. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t added any nominees, it takes barely a couple of minutes.
While adding nominees is a good first step, you still have to inform the nominees.</description></item><item><title>Unlisted market hype is blinding people to basic risks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/unlisted-market-hype-is-blinding-people-to-basic-risks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/unlisted-market-hype-is-blinding-people-to-basic-risks/</guid><description>Given how hot the IPO market is, I&amp;rsquo;m hearing some phenomenally stupid stories from the unlisted market. People are blindly punting on so-called &amp;ldquo;pre-IPO&amp;rdquo; companies hoping they&amp;rsquo;ll make bigger gains than during the actual IPO.
The greed is causing people to ignore some hard realities: these shares already come with 100–500% markups, ridiculous commissions, and terrible pricing. The biggest risk? There have been numerous cases where the IPO price ended up lower than the price at which people bought shares in the unlisted market.</description></item><item><title>Teaching finance and markets online with Varsity Live</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/teaching-finance-and-markets-online-with-varsity-live/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/teaching-finance-and-markets-online-with-varsity-live/</guid><description>I think we&amp;rsquo;ve finally found a way to teach finance and markets online with both quality and scale with Varsity Live.
We&amp;rsquo;ve had 2.3 lakh registrations so far, with about 3,000 new people signing up every week. By the way, this Sunday, the 23rd, we&amp;rsquo;re hosting a finance boot camp for kids. Most of this is a result of people discovering Varsity Live and sharing it with their friends and family.</description></item><item><title>SEBI cautions against investing in digital gold</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cautions-against-investing-in-digital-gold/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cautions-against-investing-in-digital-gold/</guid><description>Digital gold is unregulated. A timely reminder from SEBI.
Most people don’t realize that nobody regulates digital gold, and if something were to happen to the platforms or companies selling it, there’s not much you can do.
It’s also a subpar way to get exposure to gold. You pay 3% GST the moment you buy. Then there are spreads of another 2–3%, which means as soon as you purchase digital gold, you’re already down about 6%, and that’s before even factoring in regulatory risk.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha LIQUIDCASE grows to ₹6,000 crore AUM in under two years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-liquidcase-grows-to-6000-crore-aum-in-under-two-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-liquidcase-grows-to-6000-crore-aum-in-under-two-years/</guid><description>Zerodha LIQUIDCASE is India&amp;rsquo;s first liquid ETF with a growth NAV, and we launched it in January 2024. In just under two years, it&amp;rsquo;s incredible that the AUM has reached almost ₹6,000 crores.
All of this growth is organic, from traders and investors discovering the ETF and investing in it. We haven&amp;rsquo;t really spoken about it much, and you can&amp;rsquo;t pay commissions on an ETF anyway.
The innovation here was simple: no dividends, because they were tax-inefficient and a pain to redeem and track.</description></item><item><title>How India’s tax structure rewards growth over profits</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-indias-tax-structure-rewards-growth-over-profits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-indias-tax-structure-rewards-growth-over-profits/</guid><description>If you take money out of a business as dividends, the effective tax rate is 52% (25% corporate tax + 35.5% on personal income). Through capital gains, it’s just 14.95% (with cess).
Why does this matter? Here’s what you should know if you invest in IPOs.
If you’re an investor (especially a VC), the math is simple: reduce corporate tax by showing minimal profits or losses. Spend (Burn) on acquiring users, build a growth narrative, and then sell shares at a higher valuation while paying much lower tax.</description></item><item><title>Indian VC ecosystem has changed quite a bit in 15 years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-vc-ecosystem-has-changed-quite-a-bit-in-15-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-vc-ecosystem-has-changed-quite-a-bit-in-15-years/</guid><description>The Indian VC ecosystem has changed quite a bit in 15 years. When we started Zerodha in 2010, &amp;ldquo;VC&amp;rdquo; was an exotic term, and there was barely any startup activity. The most popular VCs were dads, uncles and aunts.
Starting around 2010, we began seeing interest driven by India&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;opportunity size.&amp;rdquo; India&amp;rsquo;s population has done more to attract VC money than anything else 😛 &amp;ldquo;India has 120 crore people, and even if 1% buy X&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Real stories from parents investing through Zerodha minor accounts.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-stories-from-parents-investing-through-zerodha-minor-accounts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-stories-from-parents-investing-through-zerodha-minor-accounts/</guid><description>I can keep giving gyan about starting to invest early for your kids, but nothing beats hearing it from parents who are actually doing it. Here are some first-hand takes from people using a Zerodha minor account to invest for their children.
P.S. Our youngest account holder is just 64 days old. 😀</description></item><item><title>India’s $3 trillion in idle gold needs smarter financialization.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</guid><description>Indian households hold ~$3 trillion in gold (World Gold Council estimate), sitting idle in lockers. Meanwhile, equity investments fund companies that need capital to grow. We need better ways to financialize this gold beyond just gold loans.</description></item><item><title>Rainmatter investment in Capitalmind</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-capitalmind/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-capitalmind/</guid><description>It is sometimes surreal how life comes full circle.
Deepak Shenoy was among the first people I spoke to about the idea of Zerodha. When we started, he agreed to lend his credibility by having his name on our website as an advisor. 😬
We&amp;rsquo;re happy to be backing him through Rainmatter, as Capitalmind continues its journey of now being an AMC.</description></item><item><title>Stanley Druckenmiller on position sizing</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stanley-druckenmiller-on-position-sizing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stanley-druckenmiller-on-position-sizing/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Druckenmiller: What I actually learned is that position sizing is probably 70 to 80 per cent of the equation. It&amp;rsquo;s not just about being right or wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s about how much you make when you&amp;rsquo;re right.&amp;rdquo;
Link to the full video.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Zerodha Multi Asset Fund</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-zerodha-multi-asset-fund/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-zerodha-multi-asset-fund/</guid><description>After 20+ years of being in the markets, one thing has become crystal clear to me: most investors should just invest in low-cost equity, debt, and gold index funds and do something useful with their lives. 😬 Trying to pick the &amp;ldquo;best fund&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;best asset class&amp;rdquo; is largely a waste of time and energy.
What most investors don&amp;rsquo;t realize is that they&amp;rsquo;d get far better returns by focusing on maximizing their earning potential rather than obsessing over picking the &amp;ldquo;best stocks and funds.</description></item><item><title>Sport startups we're proud to support</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sport-startups-were-proud-to-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sport-startups-were-proud-to-support/</guid><description>One of the issues with fitness is that gyms and similar facilities feel boring for a lot of people. I&amp;rsquo;ve always said that a better way to stay fit is to play a sport you enjoy because it won&amp;rsquo;t feel like a chore. Sports are also more accessible for a lot of people.
With this in mind, we&amp;rsquo;ve supported many sports-focused startups that are trying to get more Indians to pick up a sport through Rainmatter.</description></item><item><title>SCRA rules clarified</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scra-rules-clarified/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scra-rules-clarified/</guid><description>Finally, after clarification of SCRA rules by Ministry of Finance and NSE, brokers can now invest their own funds without exchange approvals or restrictions.
This is huge for Rainmatter. We can now allocate more capital to support Indian startups directly from the brokerage entity.</description></item><item><title>Retail buying spree continues</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/retail-buying-spree-continues/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/retail-buying-spree-continues/</guid><description>One of the crazy things about the last five-odd years is that retail investors have consistently been net buyers of equities. Whether they&amp;rsquo;ll continue to buy the dip is anybody&amp;rsquo;s guess. 😬
By the way, if markets fall sharply, investors might stay out of the market for years—just like they did after 2008.</description></item></channel></rss>