<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>investing on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/investing/</link><description>Recent content in investing on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/investing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The pandemic has shown us it's the right time to move away from cities</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/moving-away-from-large-cities/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/moving-away-from-large-cities/</guid><description>While we all work together to figure out what we can do to help in the current situation, I think the only long-term fix is for as many of us to move away from large cities. This is the answer to many of India’s problems. And now is probably the right time to work towards it.
Large cities are choking &amp;amp; will continue to break down every time we&amp;rsquo;re tested, COVID today, could be water shortages, pollution, floods, etc.</description></item><item><title>Mis-selling is a systemic issue.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/misselling-is-a-systemic-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/misselling-is-a-systemic-issues/</guid><description>This is a more systemic issue, not with one bank but across the board, banks to ed-tech to fintech. As long as you give revenue targets &amp;amp; push employees to get there, products that generate more revenue for the business over what is right for the customer will be mis-sold.
Easier for employees of banks, brokerages, wealth management firms to mis-sell as relationships are already established &amp;amp; there is trust with the brand, which is why the customer has allowed them to be custodians of their assets.</description></item><item><title>A nudge to stop people from losing money in Rights Entitlements</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudge-to-stop-people-from-losing-money-in-rights-entitlements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudge-to-stop-people-from-losing-money-in-rights-entitlements/</guid><description>Many retail investors buy Rights Entitlements (REs) without knowing that the value of REs will be zero if they don&amp;rsquo;t apply. Since May 2020 our clients have lost ~Rs 10cr by buying Rights entitlements &amp;amp; not applying. We now have a nudge to warn customers. Read about it here.</description></item><item><title>Enabling women to start making financial decisions</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/enabling-women-to-start-making-financial-decisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/enabling-women-to-start-making-financial-decisions/</guid><description>This video from Paytm captures what we need to do most as a country - educate &amp;amp; enable as many women as possible to start making financial decisions. In my personal experience, women manage risk better than men, so they&amp;rsquo;ll probably take better financial decisions #womensday2021</description></item><item><title>The best way of investing in gold</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-of-investing-in-gold/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-of-investing-in-gold/</guid><description>https://tradingqna.com/t/whats-the-best-option-to-invest-in-gold/93314 Seems like everyone is selling digital gold. On digital gold, you lose 3% as GST, upto 2% in commissions, &amp;amp; a spread &amp;gt;5% (buy-sell difference). If you are looking at gold as an investment, Sovereign gold bonds followed by Gold ETF/MFs are the best option.</description></item></channel></rss>