<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>investing on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/investing/</link><description>Recent content in investing on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/investing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zerodha LIQUIDCASE grows to ₹6,000 crore AUM in under two years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-liquidcase-grows-to-6000-crore-aum-in-under-two-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-liquidcase-grows-to-6000-crore-aum-in-under-two-years/</guid><description>Zerodha LIQUIDCASE is India&amp;rsquo;s first liquid ETF with a growth NAV, and we launched it in January 2024. In just under two years, it&amp;rsquo;s incredible that the AUM has reached almost ₹6,000 crores.
All of this growth is organic, from traders and investors discovering the ETF and investing in it. We haven&amp;rsquo;t really spoken about it much, and you can&amp;rsquo;t pay commissions on an ETF anyway.
The innovation here was simple: no dividends, because they were tax-inefficient and a pain to redeem and track.</description></item><item><title>How India’s tax structure rewards growth over profits</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-indias-tax-structure-rewards-growth-over-profits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-indias-tax-structure-rewards-growth-over-profits/</guid><description>If you take money out of a business as dividends, the effective tax rate is 52% (25% corporate tax + 35.5% on personal income). Through capital gains, it’s just 14.95% (with cess).
Why does this matter? Here’s what you should know if you invest in IPOs.
If you’re an investor (especially a VC), the math is simple: reduce corporate tax by showing minimal profits or losses. Spend (Burn) on acquiring users, build a growth narrative, and then sell shares at a higher valuation while paying much lower tax.</description></item><item><title>Indian VC ecosystem has changed quite a bit in 15 years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-vc-ecosystem-has-changed-quite-a-bit-in-15-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-vc-ecosystem-has-changed-quite-a-bit-in-15-years/</guid><description>The Indian VC ecosystem has changed quite a bit in 15 years. When we started Zerodha in 2010, &amp;ldquo;VC&amp;rdquo; was an exotic term, and there was barely any startup activity. The most popular VCs were dads, uncles and aunts.
Starting around 2010, we began seeing interest driven by India&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;opportunity size.&amp;rdquo; India&amp;rsquo;s population has done more to attract VC money than anything else 😛 &amp;ldquo;India has 120 crore people, and even if 1% buy X&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Real stories from parents investing through Zerodha minor accounts.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-stories-from-parents-investing-through-zerodha-minor-accounts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-stories-from-parents-investing-through-zerodha-minor-accounts/</guid><description>I can keep giving gyan about starting to invest early for your kids, but nothing beats hearing it from parents who are actually doing it. Here are some first-hand takes from people using a Zerodha minor account to invest for their children.
P.S. Our youngest account holder is just 64 days old. 😀</description></item><item><title>India’s $3 trillion in idle gold needs smarter financialization.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</guid><description>Indian households hold ~$3 trillion in gold (World Gold Council estimate), sitting idle in lockers. Meanwhile, equity investments fund companies that need capital to grow. We need better ways to financialize this gold beyond just gold loans.</description></item><item><title>Rainmatter investment in Capitalmind</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-capitalmind/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-capitalmind/</guid><description>It is sometimes surreal how life comes full circle.
Deepak Shenoy was among the first people I spoke to about the idea of Zerodha. When we started, he agreed to lend his credibility by having his name on our website as an advisor. 😬
We&amp;rsquo;re happy to be backing him through Rainmatter, as Capitalmind continues its journey of now being an AMC.</description></item><item><title>Stanley Druckenmiller on position sizing</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stanley-druckenmiller-on-position-sizing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stanley-druckenmiller-on-position-sizing/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Druckenmiller: What I actually learned is that position sizing is probably 70 to 80 per cent of the equation. It&amp;rsquo;s not just about being right or wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s about how much you make when you&amp;rsquo;re right.&amp;rdquo;
Link to the full video.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Zerodha Multi Asset Fund</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-zerodha-multi-asset-fund/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-zerodha-multi-asset-fund/</guid><description>After 20+ years of being in the markets, one thing has become crystal clear to me: most investors should just invest in low-cost equity, debt, and gold index funds and do something useful with their lives. 😬 Trying to pick the &amp;ldquo;best fund&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;best asset class&amp;rdquo; is largely a waste of time and energy.
What most investors don&amp;rsquo;t realize is that they&amp;rsquo;d get far better returns by focusing on maximizing their earning potential rather than obsessing over picking the &amp;ldquo;best stocks and funds.</description></item><item><title>Sport startups we're proud to support</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sport-startups-were-proud-to-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sport-startups-were-proud-to-support/</guid><description>One of the issues with fitness is that gyms and similar facilities feel boring for a lot of people. I&amp;rsquo;ve always said that a better way to stay fit is to play a sport you enjoy because it won&amp;rsquo;t feel like a chore. Sports are also more accessible for a lot of people.
With this in mind, we&amp;rsquo;ve supported many sports-focused startups that are trying to get more Indians to pick up a sport through Rainmatter.</description></item><item><title>SCRA rules clarified</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scra-rules-clarified/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scra-rules-clarified/</guid><description>Finally, after clarification of SCRA rules by Ministry of Finance and NSE, brokers can now invest their own funds without exchange approvals or restrictions.
This is huge for Rainmatter. We can now allocate more capital to support Indian startups directly from the brokerage entity.</description></item><item><title>Retail buying spree continues</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/retail-buying-spree-continues/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/retail-buying-spree-continues/</guid><description>One of the crazy things about the last five-odd years is that retail investors have consistently been net buyers of equities. Whether they&amp;rsquo;ll continue to buy the dip is anybody&amp;rsquo;s guess. 😬
By the way, if markets fall sharply, investors might stay out of the market for years—just like they did after 2008.</description></item><item><title>Why ETFs are more popular than mutual funds in the U.S</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-etfs-are-more-popular-than-mutual-funds-in-the-u.s/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-etfs-are-more-popular-than-mutual-funds-in-the-u.s/</guid><description>Something I learned recently on why ETFs in the US are preferred over MFs. 😬
US mutual funds are pass-through vehicles—if they generate capital gains, these must be distributed to unit holders who pay the taxes on the gains which makes MFs less tax-efficient. ETFs avoid this through &amp;lsquo;in-kind&amp;rsquo; creation/redemption that washes away gains. This tax advantage is significant. This is one underrated reason for the popularity of index funds, especially ETFs in the US.</description></item><item><title>India's trading hubs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-trading-hubs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-trading-hubs/</guid><description>Ahmedabad and Mumbai account for 80% of equity delivery trades. Let that sink in. Essentially, the real money is with Gujjus 😬
Btw, Gujarat accounts for just 8% of the total registered investors, and the share has been falling.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Money Mindful series</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-money-mindful-series/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-money-mindful-series/</guid><description>Despite all the interest in the stock market after COVID, there are still only 5 crore unique mutual fund investors. I&amp;rsquo;ve said this earlier as well—one of the biggest challenges for the Indian markets is the lack of an advisory ecosystem with just about 900 RIAs.
If you consider mutual fund distributors, there are about 2.7 lakh+ plus, but still not enough. For a broad comparison, there are over 27 lakh+ insurance agents.</description></item><item><title>New investor demographics in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/new-investor-demographics-in-india/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/new-investor-demographics-in-india/</guid><description>For the longest time, most of the investors in the Indian markets were more or less from the major metro cities. But this has changed dramatically after COVID. The bulk of new investors are from North India, and we&amp;rsquo;ve kinda missed out on getting them to invest with us.
This was something interesting that came up when I was catching up withAshish Chauhan as he shared the NSE India coffee table book.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha's growing AUM and investor profits</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodhas-growing-aum-and-investor-profits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodhas-growing-aum-and-investor-profits/</guid><description>Equity investors at Zerodha have realized a profit of Rs 50,000 crores over the last 4+ years and are sitting on unrealized profits of Rs 1,00,000 crores on an AUM of Rs 4,50,000 crores.
By the way, most of the AUM was added in the last four years.</description></item><item><title>Companies can now issue bonds with face value of Rs.10,000</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/companies-can-now-issue-bonds-with-face-value-of-rs-10000/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/companies-can-now-issue-bonds-with-face-value-of-rs-10000/</guid><description>Companies can now issue bonds with face value of Rs.10,000. This is a great move that can help attract retail participation in the bonds. With all the changes in the last few years, SEBI has done an amazing job of making bonds accessible to small investors.
Read more.</description></item><item><title>Social Stock Exchange for social organizations to raise funds</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/social-stock-exchange-for-social-organizations-to-raise-funds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/social-stock-exchange-for-social-organizations-to-raise-funds/</guid><description>The Social Stock Exchange (SSE) is a platform for social organizations to raise funds from the public. So far, 6 non-profit organizations have raised money, and we are happy to have supported them.
There&amp;rsquo;s no online mechanism to donate to these organizations like we have for regular IPOs but I&amp;rsquo;m hoping this will soon be possible. We will then make it possible for all @zerodhaonline customers to support social sector organizations working on important issues.</description></item><item><title>Using passive funds to build the core of your portfolio</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/using-passive-funds-to-build-the-core-of-your-portfolio/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/using-passive-funds-to-build-the-core-of-your-portfolio/</guid><description>I have a vested interest in saying this 😬 being part of @ZerodhaAMC, but it&amp;rsquo;s a no-brainer to use low-cost index funds for your core portfolio. You can complement that with other funds, but the core should be passive funds.
The data shows it&amp;rsquo;s getting increasingly harder for active funds to outperform their benchmarks.
Link.</description></item><item><title>Why adding a nominee for your demat account is important</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-adding-a-nominee-for-your-demat-account-is-important/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-adding-a-nominee-for-your-demat-account-is-important/</guid><description>Between 50,000 and 80,000 crores of assets are unclaimed across demat accounts, mutual funds, insurance, etc. This is because most investors don&amp;rsquo;t add nominees to their investors. In fact, 72% of Individual investors don&amp;rsquo;t have a nominee for their demat accounts and mutual fund folios. Even if investors do add nominees, they don&amp;rsquo;t tell their nominees.
Life is unpredictable, and anything can happen. It&amp;rsquo;s not a pleasant thought, but making sure life is as comfortable as possible for your loved ones in your absence is a key part of life.</description></item></channel></rss>