<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>zerodha on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/zerodha/</link><description>Recent content in zerodha on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/zerodha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Kite Terminal Mode is now live on beta</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kite-terminal-mode-is-now-live-on-beta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kite-terminal-mode-is-now-live-on-beta/</guid><description>Kite Terminal Mode is now live on beta!
We are quite excited about this. 😬
Check out the Kite Beta, and you can provide feedback here.</description></item><item><title>Simplifying Corporate NPS with PensionBox</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/simplifying-corporate-nps-with-pensionbox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/simplifying-corporate-nps-with-pensionbox/</guid><description>In FY25, around 72% of taxpayers chose the New Tax Regime. At Zerodha, that number was over 90%.
This shift makes sense. The new tax regime trades deductions for simpler filing and lower tax rates. For many—especially younger salaried taxpayers, avoiding paperwork-heavy exemptions matters more than maximising deductions.
With most deductions removed, salaried employees are left with the ₹75,000 standard deduction and one meaningful tax-saving option: the employer contribution to NPS, commonly called Corporate NPS.</description></item><item><title>Recent updates to make investing easier for NRIs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recent-updates-to-make-investing-easier-for-nris/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recent-updates-to-make-investing-easier-for-nris/</guid><description>We at Zerodha , have ~40k NRI customers with an average account value of ₹40L, nearly 10x our overall average of ₹3.6L for resident accounts. Most of them opened accounts the hard way, with physical paperwork. If onboarding were fully online, this base would be much larger.
SEBI recently made changes that have allowed us to significantly simplify Non-PIS NRI accounts: they now work like resident accounts, with fully online Aadhaar-based onboarding (when visiting India) and intraday, BTST, and F&amp;amp;O access with no need for a CP code.</description></item><item><title>Commodity markets look very different today</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/commodity-markets-look-very-different-today/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/commodity-markets-look-very-different-today/</guid><description>Up until a few years ago, commodity trading was more or less an afterthought. Most traders didn&amp;rsquo;t bother with it because liquidity was thin relative to NSE F&amp;amp;O.
But that&amp;rsquo;s changed dramatically, thanks to the spectacular rally in gold and silver. If you look at gold and silver as a percentage of total MCX trading volumes today, the numbers are kind of crazy. A lot of this increase has come at the expense of other commodities like crude.</description></item><item><title>The broking business has a hard growth ceiling</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-broking-business-has-a-hard-growth-ceiling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-broking-business-has-a-hard-growth-ceiling/</guid><description>Broking is a unique business because there&amp;rsquo;s a hard ceiling on how much we can grow and the rate at which we can grow. What most people don&amp;rsquo;t realise is that SEBI has set a 15% open interest (OI) cap at the broker level.
No single broker can hold more than 15% of the total market OI. This restriction exists to mitigate the risk of concentration from any single broker becoming too large.</description></item><item><title>Open-source projects from Zerodha Tech team</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-projects-from-zerodha-tech-team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-projects-from-zerodha-tech-team/</guid><description>The number of full-fledged Free and open-source software (FOSS) products and initiatives coming out of the 4th Phase, JP Nagar (Zerodha Tech), must be unprecedented for a team of its size globally.
All of these projects started as a way to solve problems we faced internally and were then open sourced. We use them at scale in our stack, and several large organisations and even government departments globally use many of these tools today.</description></item><item><title>A year of MTF launch and product growth</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-year-of-mtf-launch-and-product-growth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-year-of-mtf-launch-and-product-growth/</guid><description>We launched our MTF product a year ago. Despite being one of the last brokers to offer this and without actively promoting it on the order screen or elsewhere, we captured ~5% of the market. But growth has plateaued along with the broader industry.
One surprising thing I have noticed is that customers don&amp;rsquo;t seem to care about MTF brokerage or know what they&amp;rsquo;re being charged. Our current brokerage is 0.</description></item><item><title>Protect your assets by adding a nominee</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/protect-your-assets-by-adding-a-nominee/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/protect-your-assets-by-adding-a-nominee/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s ₹104,000 crores worth of money and investments lying unclaimed across banks, insurance companies, and mutual funds. The number is from a post by our PM Narendra Modi.
Despite the nomination process being fully online and despite repeated nudges, 62% of Zerodha users with holdings don&amp;rsquo;t have a nominee. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t added any nominees, it takes barely a couple of minutes.
While adding nominees is a good first step, you still have to inform the nominees.</description></item><item><title>Why encouraging less trading leads to better outcomes for everyone</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-encouraging-less-trading-leads-to-better-outcomes-for-everyone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-encouraging-less-trading-leads-to-better-outcomes-for-everyone/</guid><description>As a % of client funds, our brokerage revenue is 20-25% of our listed peers. That means our clients trade a lot less (75% lesser) as a proportion of their capital.
Here&amp;rsquo;s something counterintuitive but true: With few exceptions, the more frequently people trade, the lower their odds of being profitable. More activity doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean better returns; it usually means a higher chance of blowing out your account.
So it&amp;rsquo;s actually in a platform&amp;rsquo;s best interest to get customers to trade less, not more.</description></item><item><title>On today’s issue caused by the Cloudflare outage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-today-issue-caused-by-the-cloudflare-outage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-today-issue-caused-by-the-cloudflare-outage/</guid><description>Cloudflare powers approximately 20-25% of all internet traffic globally. It&amp;rsquo;s the infrastructure behind millions of websites and apps—from content delivery and DDoS protection to DNS services. When Cloudflare has an outage, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just affect one company; it impacts a significant chunk of the internet simultaneously.
Today, they had a brief outage that affected Kite along with numerous other brokers, fintech platforms, and online services worldwide.
This is why we built Kite Backup on WhatsApp.</description></item><item><title>10 years of zero brokerage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/10-years-of-zero-brokerage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/10-years-of-zero-brokerage/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 10 years since we went zero brokerage on stocks, ETFs, and more. Back in 2015, if you had asked whether Zerodha would keep brokerage on investing at zero in 2025, I would&amp;rsquo;ve probably said no.
The backstory of how we decided to go zero is a bit funny. K(Kailash, CTO) and I were sitting at Bengaluru airport on our way to Kochi, talking about the need to change Zerodha&amp;rsquo;s image of being meant only for traders.</description></item><item><title>Take break from trading using Kill Switch</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-break-from-trading-using-kill-switch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-break-from-trading-using-kill-switch/</guid><description>The other common trading mistake I have seen over and over again in all my years of being a trader and running a brokerage is over-trading and revenge trading.
Sometimes, the best trade is the one you don&amp;rsquo;t take.
This is why we launched Kill Switch. If you get the urge to keep trading, you can enable it, and you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to place trades for the rest of the day.</description></item><item><title>Portfolio update of a colleague at work</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/portfolio-update-of-a-colleague-at-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/portfolio-update-of-a-colleague-at-work/</guid><description>Portfolio update of a colleague at work. He&amp;rsquo;s now invested in 3,100 stocks (it was 2,100 last time), taking diversification to its logical extreme. 😀
At least he&amp;rsquo;s beating G-Secs.
Btw, you can check your account’s performance on Console.</description></item><item><title>Accessibility has always been core to how we build</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/accessibility-has-always-been-core-to-how-we-build/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/accessibility-has-always-been-core-to-how-we-build/</guid><description>In November 2024, the Supreme Court ruled that accessibility is a fundamental right, directing businesses to ensure their digital platforms are accessible to people with disabilities. The Court essentially said that in a digital-first world, denying digital access means denying basic rights. It’s not just about compliance, it’s about constitutional equality.
Accessibility has been core to how we build at Zerodha. The mandate didn’t change our approach, it just gave us a deadline.</description></item><item><title>Robinhood makes $150 million a year just from instant withdrawal fee</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-makes-150-million-a-year-just-from-instant-withdrawal-fee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-makes-150-million-a-year-just-from-instant-withdrawal-fee/</guid><description>I just discovered that Robinhood will generate approximately $150 million (~₹1,300 crores) in revenue from the fees it charges for processing instant client withdrawals. Their cost to process these is around $35–40 million, which means a clean $100 million to the bottom line, and that’s just from instant withdrawals. 😬
As an Indian startup with some scale, founders dream of generating revenue like this from non-core products. Hence the rush to introduce everything: loans, insurance, payments, and other financial services.</description></item><item><title>AMA with Zerodha's core team</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ama-with-zerodhas-core-team/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ama-with-zerodhas-core-team/</guid><description>A bunch of you asked us questions about our revenues, regulations, international investing, AI, and more. Nikhil, Kailash, Karthik Rangappa, Venu, and I answered a lot of those questions in this AMA.
Since there were several questions about US investing: we didn&amp;rsquo;t offer it until now because the regulations were unclear, but now there&amp;rsquo;s clarity. In May, SEBI and IFSCA allowed brokers to operate in GIFT City, and in June, the exchanges allowed brokers to offer third-party products.</description></item><item><title>The love we get for all the content is crazy</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-love-we-get-for-all-the-content-is-crazy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-love-we-get-for-all-the-content-is-crazy/</guid><description>The love we get for all the content on Varsity, Markets by Zerodha etc. is crazy. 😀What we&amp;rsquo;ve done from day 1 is focus on sharing quality insights rather than chasing engagement, pointless optimizations, and gimmicks. The trust we&amp;rsquo;ve built over almost a decade is a direct result of that—people reading and watching us and then sharing it with their friends and family.</description></item><item><title>Real stories from parents investing through Zerodha minor accounts.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-stories-from-parents-investing-through-zerodha-minor-accounts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-stories-from-parents-investing-through-zerodha-minor-accounts/</guid><description>I can keep giving gyan about starting to invest early for your kids, but nothing beats hearing it from parents who are actually doing it. Here are some first-hand takes from people using a Zerodha minor account to invest for their children.
P.S. Our youngest account holder is just 64 days old. 😀</description></item><item><title>India’s $3 trillion in idle gold needs smarter financialization.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</guid><description>Indian households hold ~$3 trillion in gold (World Gold Council estimate), sitting idle in lockers. Meanwhile, equity investments fund companies that need capital to grow. We need better ways to financialize this gold beyond just gold loans.</description></item><item><title>Why short-term growth is the wrong metric</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-short-term-growth-is-the-wrong-metric/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-short-term-growth-is-the-wrong-metric/</guid><description>On the question of what would we do if weekly options were removed, I suppose we&amp;rsquo;ll see another hit to our revenues in the short-term.
Having said that, when you&amp;rsquo;re building a business for the long term, focusing on quarterly or even annual growth is a poor metric. The more you focus on them, the higher the odds that you&amp;rsquo;ll do things that are bad for your customers.</description></item></channel></rss>