<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>zerodha on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/zerodha/</link><description>Recent content in zerodha on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/zerodha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beware of these fake Zerodha investment scams</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-these-fake-zerodha-investment-scams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-these-fake-zerodha-investment-scams/</guid><description>These fake app and website scams keep getting worse and worse. Not a day goes by where I don&amp;rsquo;t read about such scams or hear from people who&amp;rsquo;ve been affected. The scale of these scams is just insane.
There are now countless phishing scams that take advantage of the familiarity of all major brands, celebrities, etc. The tricks vary—fake apps, fake websites, fake social media profiles, scam calls—but all with the same goal: to steal your money.</description></item><item><title>10 Years of Zerodha Varsity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/10-years-of-zerodha-varsity/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/10-years-of-zerodha-varsity/</guid><description>It’s been 10 years since we started Varsity. What began as a simple blog has gradually grown into a full-fledged stock market education initiative. Today, Varsity spans text, video, audio, and our latest addition—a live format called Varsity Live. It’s an interactive, live education program and the first of its kind.
When we started, Karthik Rangappa and I decided that Varsity would have no agenda. There would be no pitching of Zerodha to Varsity users, no mandatory login, or anything else.</description></item><item><title>100 episodes of The Daily Brief podcast</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/100-episodes-of-the-daily-brief-podcast/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/100-episodes-of-the-daily-brief-podcast/</guid><description>One personal problem I had was that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a good short finance podcast in India that helped me get a sense of the 3-4 major finance stories of the day. So, as an experiment, we launched a new YouTube channel called Markets by Zerodha and started a short daily finance podcast called &amp;ldquo;The Daily Brief.&amp;rdquo;
The response has been surprising. We just crossed 100 episodes, and it has become one of the most popular finance podcasts and newsletters in India, with nearly 1.</description></item><item><title>Don’t do unto others what you don’t want done unto you</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dont-do-unto-others-what-you-dont-want-done-unto-you/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dont-do-unto-others-what-you-dont-want-done-unto-you/</guid><description>With everybody chasing &amp;ldquo;engagement,&amp;rdquo; we seem to have made many things on the internet annoying and unusable. My own phone is constantly on silent because of annoying calls, notifications, emails, etc.
From day one of Zerodha, &amp;ldquo;don&amp;rsquo;t do unto others what you don&amp;rsquo;t want done unto you&amp;rdquo; has been at the core of our philosophy. We don&amp;rsquo;t send an email or a notification unless it&amp;rsquo;s important. Counter-intuitively, this is why people trust us?</description></item><item><title>Update on all our educational content initiatives</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/update-on-all-our-educational-content-initiatives/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/update-on-all-our-educational-content-initiatives/</guid><description>Some people, jokingly perhaps, say, &amp;ldquo;Zerodha is a content company.&amp;rdquo; But this isn&amp;rsquo;t something we are doing now. We&amp;rsquo;ve been sharing everything we know about finance, markets, and investing since day 1 of Zerodha in text form—even before &amp;ldquo;content&amp;rdquo; was a thing. In fact, Z-Connect is one of the oldest finance blogs in India.
It&amp;rsquo;s just that now we are publishing a lot more video content across @ZerodhaVarsity, @zerodhamarkets, @zerodhaonline, @Rainmatterin, Zero1 and there&amp;rsquo;s @nikhilkamathcio&amp;rsquo;s WTF and @kmr_dilip&amp;rsquo;s The Other Side as well.</description></item><item><title>14-years of Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/14-years-of-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/14-years-of-zerodha/</guid><description>A few highlights from FY2023/24 @zerodhaonline
For years now, I&amp;rsquo;d been talking about regulatory risk in running a brokerage, and this was the year when all the risks materialized at the same time.
We had plenty of positives.
Content
Today, we have some of the best content on all things stock market with @ZerodhaVarsity videos, Varsity Live, Zero1, @zerodhamarkets and more. All this is not just in English but also Hindi.</description></item><item><title>Alert Triggers Order feature on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alert-triggers-order-feature-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alert-triggers-order-feature-on-kite/</guid><description>Alert triggers an order (ATO) was on our to-do list for a long time, and we just launched it on Kite web.
ATO orders allow you to execute trades based on If This Then That conditions.
For example, buy Reliance if Nifty 50 crosses 25000 or execute a nifty short straddle (sell a call and put option of the same strike) if Nifty 50 falls to 24975.
ATO will soon be available on Kite mobile.</description></item><item><title>What changes due to a settlemet holiday?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-changes-at-zerodha-due-to-settlement-holiday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-changes-at-zerodha-due-to-settlement-holiday/</guid><description>Today is a settlement holiday, and thus, settlements of funds and stocks don&amp;rsquo;t happen. This happens when banks in Maharashtra are closed, but trading on exchanges is open.
Most brokers don&amp;rsquo;t allow shares bought on Friday to be sold on Monday because of this. We @zerodhaonline are among the few brokers that allow you to sell stocks bought on Friday.
By the way, due to the settlement holiday, your equity intraday profit credits and F&amp;amp;O credits aren&amp;rsquo;t included in your trading balance or are not available for withdrawal today.</description></item><item><title>Interactive learning with Varsity Live</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/interactive-learning-with-varsity-live/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/interactive-learning-with-varsity-live/</guid><description>We started @ZerodhaVarsity almost a decade ago to simplify how the stock market worked in English and Hindi for free. For people who preferred video, we turned all the modules into video. Today, Varsity is easily one of the most read and watched resources for all things financial markets.
But until now it was self-directed—you had to read, watch, and then learn about things. We had always wanted to introduce an interactive mode of learning about markets, and we finally got around to launching Varsity Live in collaboration with @LearnappHQ.</description></item><item><title>NSE circular suspending referral programmes</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nse-circular-suspending-referral-programmes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nse-circular-suspending-referral-programmes/</guid><description>NSE issued a circular last week stopping brokers from sharing any brokerage as a referral incentive unless that person is registered as an authorized person with the exchanges. This is another one of those circulars that will hurt the business. 😬
So, we are stopping our referral programme and making one-time payouts for whatever is due. But we will continue to give out reward points every time you refer a customer to us.</description></item><item><title>Daily brief podcast</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/daily-brief-podcast/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/daily-brief-podcast/</guid><description>A personal problem I had was that there wasn&amp;rsquo;t a short ~15 minute podcast that covered the top 3–5 markets and business stories in a given day. There are many in the US, but none in India.
So we started The Daily Brief by @zerodhamarkets. It&amp;rsquo;s a daily podcast that gives you a quick overview of the big stories in the markets.
It&amp;rsquo;s been quickly climbing the rankings on every platform in the business category.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha account opening is now free</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-account-opening-is-now-free/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-account-opening-is-now-free/</guid><description>When we started, we charged an account opening fee because it only attracted customers who were serious about investing. Since then, a lot has changed, like the introduction of Aadhaar, eSign, the influx of younger investors and so on. Charging an account fee certainly doesn&amp;rsquo;t make sense anymore.
A little late😬, but we&amp;rsquo;ve made account opening for resident individuals free at Zerodha for over a month now. 😀</description></item><item><title>SEBI consultation paper to review RIA framework</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-sonsultation-paper-to-review-ria-frameowrk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-sonsultation-paper-to-review-ria-frameowrk/</guid><description>One of the biggest challenges for the Indian markets is the lack of an advisory ecosystem. While the number of unique investors has grown from about 3 crore in 2020 to 10 crore today, the number of RIAs has barely grown. If anything, the number of RIAs seems to be decreasing.
We just have about 900 odd RIAs, and not all of them do holistic advisory, and if you only consider these, the number drops to less than half.</description></item><item><title>AMA with our core team</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ama-with-our-core-team/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ama-with-our-core-team/</guid><description>All of us from the core team are doing an AMA this month. If you have any questions for us, share them below:
@nikhilkamathcio on investments Kailash on technology Venu on operations @karthikrangappa on education Me on everything, including how we are going to survive all the changes in regulations 😬</description></item><item><title>Reports for tax filing at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/reports-for-tax-filing-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/reports-for-tax-filing-at-zerodha/</guid><description>The last date for filing taxes is July 31, 2024. All the details that you need to file taxes are available as reports on Console:
Tax P&amp;amp;L statement that has details of speculative and non-speculative trades, P&amp;amp;L, capital gains, and charges. Contract notes for the year. Funds statement as of March 31. Holding statement as of March 31. Annual Global statement (AGS). So, if you haven’t already filed your ITR :) We&amp;rsquo;ve also partnered with @Quicko_official to make tax filing easy if you need help.</description></item><item><title>K's push to avoid all enterprise deals saved us yesterday</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ks-push-to-avoid-enterprise-deals-saved-us-yesterday/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ks-push-to-avoid-enterprise-deals-saved-us-yesterday/</guid><description>Almost the entire employee base, including non-technical folks, uses Linux laptops. I use Zorin (Linux). Kailash&amp;rsquo;s push to avoid all enterprise deals saved us yesterday. Read more.</description></item><item><title>Single ledger facility at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/single-ledger-facility-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/single-ledger-facility-at-zerodha/</guid><description>Now, you can trade commodities using the same equity account balance without maintaining a separate commodity account. This was a legacy issue that took us a long time to address.
Zerodha Broking is our primary membership, and Zerodha Commodities Pvt Ltd is the commodity member. We have started allowing customers to move to Zerodha Broking even if they are trading commodities.
As part of this process, we are also surrendering the Zerodha Commodities Pvt Ltd license on exchanges where we weren&amp;rsquo;t active, i.</description></item><item><title>Introducing fundamentals widget by Tijori Finance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-fundamentals-widget-by-tijori-finance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-fundamentals-widget-by-tijori-finance/</guid><description>The fundamentals widget on Zerodha is now powered by Tijori. It now has much more financial data about the company to help you make informed decisions.</description></item><item><title>Election day activity on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/election-day-activity-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/election-day-activity-on-kite/</guid><description>Activity today on Kite 😬</description></item><item><title>Introducing instant withdrawals</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-instant-withdrawals/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-instant-withdrawals/</guid><description>One of our to-dos was to allow instant withdrawals. By instant, I mean instant. To start with, we (@zerodhaonline) will allow instant withdrawals between 9 a.m. and 4 p.m., up to ₹1 lakh throughout the week, including weekends, at no additional cost.
This is only possible due to our amazing payment systems, thanks to the @RBI and @NPCI_NPCI.</description></item><item><title>Introducing notes feature on Kite Web</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-notes-feature-on-kite-web/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-notes-feature-on-kite-web/</guid><description>Have you checked out the notes feature on Kite Web? Read more on how to add notes on Kite.</description></item><item><title>At the Zero1 fest</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/at-the-zero1-fest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/at-the-zero1-fest/</guid><description>Slowly getting back to normal. 😀
At the Zero1 fest, talking about health and wealth with Nuseir Yassin, JC, and Shashank Mehta</description></item><item><title>Zerodha's remarkable market growth post COVID</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodhas-remarkable-market-growth-post-covid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodhas-remarkable-market-growth-post-covid/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s unreal how much our markets have expanded post-COVID. Zerodha customers now hold ~ Rs 4.5 lakh crores worth of assets in their demat accounts.</description></item><item><title>The remoteness of remote work</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-remoteness-of-remote-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-remoteness-of-remote-work/</guid><description>All of us at @zerodhaonline went fully remote during the pandemic lockdown in 2020. While it&amp;rsquo;s been great for some, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been for others. In this post, K explains why it didn&amp;rsquo;t work for everybody at Zerodha.
Work from home works well for support roles given the structured nature of the work. But for tech, business, and decision making teams, it has been detrimental, primarily due to the big gaps in remote communication.</description></item><item><title>Rrvamped Z-Connect blog</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/revamped-z-connect-blog/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/revamped-z-connect-blog/</guid><description>We recently redesigned Z-Connect, our blog that was started in 2012. It reminded me of how and why we started it. When we started Zerodha, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford to spend money on advertising. So, we figured that sharing everything we knew about trading, investing, and the capital markets openly was a better way to reach new customers.
At that point, it was probably one of a handful of finance blogs. Over the years, we&amp;rsquo;ve published hundreds of blog posts.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Timeline and Stock Insights by Tijori Finance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-timeline-and-stock-insights-by-tijori-finance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-timeline-and-stock-insights-by-tijori-finance/</guid><description>We just introduced two new cool features on Zerodhaonline Console: Timeline and Stock Insights, both powered by Tijori.
Timeline
If you invest in stocks, tracking all the events that can affect your investments and developments in one place is hard. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to switch between multiple websites and apps to figure out what happened. This is where the Timeline comes in.
Think of your Timeline on Console as a social media feed, but only with updates about the stocks in your portfolio.</description></item><item><title>Alar an open source Kannada to English dictionary</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alar-an-open-source-kannada-to-english-dictionary/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alar-an-open-source-kannada-to-english-dictionary/</guid><description>This is V. Krishna (picture from the site). Sometime in the 1970s, he started working on a Kannada-English dictionary as a hobby project. In 2019, through @zerodhaonline, we collaborated with V. Krishna to open source and publish his dictionary online. The dictionary contains over 150,000 Kannada words with over 240,000 English definitions, and all of this was the effort of just one man.
Today, the free and open dictionary is being used by lakhs of people monthly.</description></item><item><title>Why adding a nominee for your demat account is important</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-adding-a-nominee-for-your-demat-account-is-important/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-adding-a-nominee-for-your-demat-account-is-important/</guid><description>Between 50,000 and 80,000 crores of assets are unclaimed across demat accounts, mutual funds, insurance, etc. This is because most investors don&amp;rsquo;t add nominees to their investors. In fact, 72% of Individual investors don&amp;rsquo;t have a nominee for their demat accounts and mutual fund folios. Even if investors do add nominees, they don&amp;rsquo;t tell their nominees.
Life is unpredictable, and anything can happen. It&amp;rsquo;s not a pleasant thought, but making sure life is as comfortable as possible for your loved ones in your absence is a key part of life.</description></item><item><title>Open a Zerodha account for your kids and invest together</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-a-zerodha-a-count-for-your-kids-and-invest-together/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-a-zerodha-a-count-for-your-kids-and-invest-together/</guid><description>You need to know how to manage your money to do well in life. The things you need to know to manage your money well apply to other aspects of life as well. One of the best ways to learn about money is to start early, because the things we learn when we&amp;rsquo;re young tend to stick with us for the rest of our lives. One thing that has been on our to-do list for a long time is to make it as easy for parents to invest for their kids as they teach them about money.</description></item><item><title>Introducing LIQUIDCASE, India's first ETF with a growth NAV</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-liquidcase-indias-first-etf-with-a-growth-nav/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-liquidcase-indias-first-etf-with-a-growth-nav/</guid><description>LIQUIDCASE, India&amp;rsquo;s first ETF with a growth NAV from ZerodhaAMC just listed today with the same symbol. When we were thinking about the product, we wanted to offer something simple where investors didn&amp;rsquo;t have to bother about dividends, taxes etc.
So, the way LIQUIDCASE works is simple: the returns in the ETF will be added to the NAV just like growth mutual funds, and there are no dividends. This makes it easier for you to track your returns, and there are no hassles with fractional units and figuring out your taxes.</description></item><item><title>2023 at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/2023-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/2023-at-zerodha/</guid><description>2023 was a busy year for us at Zerodha, with the majority focus on backend and behind-the-scenes changes, be it technology, operations, compliance, or customer support. Our 13th year was dedicated to streamlining, overhauling and refactoring the behind-the-scenes systems, and R&amp;amp;D, paving the way for several new products and features we have in the pipeline.
Looking back, maybe we didn&amp;rsquo;t do a good job proactively sharing updates, which might have made you feel like nothing new was happening at Zerodha.</description></item><item><title>Performance of equity investors and mutual fund investors at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/performance-of-equity-investors-and-mutual-fund-investors-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/performance-of-equity-investors-and-mutual-fund-investors-at-zerodha/</guid><description>As strange as it sounds, our equity investors are sitting on higher overall notional gains than equity mutual fund investors.
Maybe the popular narrative that retail investors are clueless and “gambling” isn’t fully accurate. That’s because you would expect direct equity investors to do worse than mutual fund investors.
Disclaimer: Most of our AUM was added post-2020, which is one of the biggest bull markets India has seen.</description></item><item><title>An apology for the two consecutive tech issues in the last two months</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/an-apology-for-the-two-consecutive-tech-issues-in-the-last-two-months/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/an-apology-for-the-two-consecutive-tech-issues-in-the-last-two-months/</guid><description>In the business updates post I shared in August this year, I mentioned how we hadn’t had any large tech issues for a couple of years. Unfortunately, we have had two episodes in quick succession in the last two months, affecting between 5 and 20% of our active customers.
The issues on Nov 6th and Dec 4th were triggered due to edge cases with our external dependencies. This is no excuse, and I understand that, as a platform, we are responsible for all the issues you face.</description></item><item><title>Simplifying NRI investments at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/simplifying-nri-investments-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/simplifying-nri-investments-at-zerodha/</guid><description>NRI account opening reminds me of how retail broking worked before it became digital, thanks to Aadhaar, e-Sign, and Digilocker. Physical applications, couriers back &amp;amp; forth, ~30+ signatures, &amp;amp; more reasons to drop off. Many NRIs want to invest in India but don&amp;rsquo;t because of the onerous account opening process and the added notarizing &amp;amp; international courier costs.
To open an NRI account, you must fill out physical forms and notarize the documents by visiting banks or embassies.</description></item><item><title>Introducing open interest visualization on charts by Sensibull</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-open-interest-visualization-on-charts-by-sensibull/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-open-interest-visualization-on-charts-by-sensibull/</guid><description>Tracking the accumulation of open interest (OI) at different strikes can give you insight into market directions. The idea traders have is that option writers have deeper pockets, and if OI is building up at certain strikes, they can act as support or resistance.
Tracking OI across strikes is easier now as you can visualize OI on price charts by Sensibull which can be accessed through the Zerodha account.
Here is a post by Abid Hassan on this and some other new features on Sensibull.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Zerodha Fund House</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-zerodha-fund-house/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-zerodha-fund-house/</guid><description>So, the NFOs of the first two funds of Zerodha Fund House are finally open.
The two funds we have launched are an open-ended index fund and an equity-linked savings scheme (ELSS), or tax saver fund that tracks the Nifty LargeMidcap 250 Index.
We will be a passive-only AMC to avoid the conflict of promoting what generates higher income (active funds). By focusing only on index products, we can hopefully help spread the idea of passive funds in India.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Zing! by Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-zing-by-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-zing-by-zerodha/</guid><description>Right from day 1 of Zerodha, we&amp;rsquo;ve spent a significant amount of time and effort to educate people about finance through Zerodha Varsity, Z-Connect, Tradingqna, etc. Since video was becoming the dominant way people consumed information, we also launched Varsity videos. Along the way, we&amp;rsquo;ve been debating whether all this content we were publishing appealed to younger audiences. We&amp;rsquo;re launching a new YouTube channel called Zing! by Zerodha in partnership with Prateek and Learnapp where we make finance a little more fun.</description></item><item><title>A realistic valuations of Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-realistic-valuation-of-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-realistic-valuation-of-zerodha/</guid><description>Every time our financials are out, there is a lot of speculation about Zerodha&amp;rsquo;s valuation. It might sound counterintuitive for me to say it, but most assumptions, I think, are way higher than reality.😬
All of us on the core team have never thought of notional valuations right from the start because they can go up and down with market conditions. Focussing on ever changing valuations is a distraction. The focus has always been on building a resilient business, which means never having to rely on external capital.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha turns 13</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-turns-13/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-turns-13/</guid><description>We turned 13 on August 15th. Last year, I had made some business predictions, and I was wrong for the third year in a row😬
As someone once said, the good thing about being a pessimist is that you are either right or pleasantly surprised, and FY22–23 was the latter.
There is an investing lesson here: markets are random, and even subject matter experts can&amp;rsquo;t predict market movements. 😀
Some highlights from the post</description></item><item><title>Dark patterns in banking</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dark-patterns-in-banking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dark-patterns-in-banking/</guid><description>A colleague had to visit a bank branch offline to close a personal loan he took online. This branch was one of only 2 in Bangalore. It&amp;rsquo;s the same with many other banks. Making it hard to close an account is a dark pattern, and maybe there should be regulations on this.
By the way, SEBI mandates that all stockbrokers must provide a facility to close accounts online. Additionally, at Zerodha, we are maybe one of the few brokers to allow online transfer of stocks to demat accounts outside Zerodha.</description></item><item><title>Why we launched verified P&amp;l on Console</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-we-launched-verified-p-and-l-on-console/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-we-launched-verified-p-and-l-on-console/</guid><description>We launched verified P&amp;amp;L at Zerodha to bring accountability, given all the fake P&amp;amp;L screenshots and videos shared on social media to peddle courses, advisory, trading accounts, &amp;amp; other financial products.
The idea was that if someone shared a screenshot or video of the P&amp;amp;L, the audience could demand a verified P&amp;amp;L link. Since the P&amp;amp;L is served directly from our side, there is no way to tamper with it.</description></item><item><title>Sensibull is now free for all our customers</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sensibull-is-now-free-for-all-our-customers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sensibull-is-now-free-for-all-our-customers/</guid><description>We have good news for all Zerodha option traders, Sensibullwill now be completely free.
We cover the costs so that Abid Hassan and Team, can focus on only one thing: Help option traders do better.</description></item><item><title>Cyber security practices at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cyber-security-practices-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cyber-security-practices-at-zerodha/</guid><description>Cyber risk is one of the biggest financial risks. I heard of a single scam of Rs 20,000 crores that affected lakhs of Indians. A precaution you can take to significantly reduce the odds of being a victim of cyber fraud is to enable two-factor authentication (2FA) everywhere.
What&amp;rsquo;s 2FA?
The first factor in a login is a password you remember, but it has the risk of being easily compromised. 2FA is an additional factor to secure your account.</description></item><item><title>Introducing virtual contract note on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-virtual-contract-note-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-virtual-contract-note-on-kite/</guid><description>Overtrading is one of the biggest reasons why traders lose money. It might sound weird coming from me, but low brokerage costs can trigger people to trade more. We just launched a virtual contract note on Kite that hopefully acts as a deterrent.
More on overtrading here👇</description></item><item><title>Reducing financial frauds by using in-person verification</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/reducing-financial-frauds-by-using-in-person-verification/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/reducing-financial-frauds-by-using-in-person-verification/</guid><description>In most financial frauds, the account that is scammed is compromised. Also, the scammer, to hide the trail, uses a mule account which is also compromised. Here&amp;rsquo;s what we did to fix such issues.
We mandate In-person verification (IPV) over webcam when any account details are being changed to ensure the person making the changes is the account holder and not someone else.
At Zerodha, IPV is mandatory for:
Opening an account Change of email &amp;amp; mobile Change in mapped Demat account High-value demat transfers Reactivating an Inactive account (Re-KYC) IPV is a regulatory requirement only to onboard new investors.</description></item><item><title>Artificial intelligence (AI) policy at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/artificial-intelligence-policy-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/artificial-intelligence-policy-at-zerodha/</guid><description>We’ve just created an internal AI policy at Zerodha to give clarity to the team, given the AI/job loss anxiety. This is our stance: &amp;ldquo;We will not fire anyone on the team just because we have implemented a new piece of technology that makes an earlier job redundant.&amp;rdquo; 1/8
In 2021, we&amp;rsquo;d said that we hadn’t found AI use cases when everyone was claiming to be powered by AI without any AI.</description></item><item><title>Entrepreneur of the Year</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/entrepreneur-of-the-year/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/entrepreneur-of-the-year/</guid><description>No Business Background No Pedigree education across the team No VC/PE No Advertising spending No Spamming customer
Zerodha is an example that a successful business can be built by not following the norm, by average folks with common sense wanting to solve a problem.
Link to the award ceremony</description></item><item><title>How we use FOSS to store billions of lines of log data</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-we-use-foss-to-store-billions-of-lines-of-log-data/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-we-use-foss-to-store-billions-of-lines-of-log-data/</guid><description>As brokers, we must store billions of lines of log data while complying with strict data handling and retention regulations. Here&amp;rsquo;s a post by Karan Sharma about how we do this efficiently with FOSS.
Disclaimer: Content not suitable for non-tech folks like me. 😬</description></item><item><title>Why Zerodha doesn't have a data team</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-doesnt-have-a-data-team/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-doesnt-have-a-data-team/</guid><description>How useful is collecting &amp;amp; analysing tons of data is a question I ask my peers. We have no data team at Zerodha as we believe it doesn&amp;rsquo;t give useful insights &amp;amp; also since we never upsell.
Article &amp;amp; comments on this topic are interesting 😬</description></item><item><title>Overtrading is the biggest reason why traders lose money</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/overtrading-is-the-biggest-reason-why-traders-lose-money/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/overtrading-is-the-biggest-reason-why-traders-lose-money/</guid><description>The biggest reason active traders lose money is overtrading, the low brokerage doesn&amp;rsquo;t help. Traders forget that costs like STT, stamp duty, etc. are charged as a % of every trade &amp;amp; compound quickly. You&amp;rsquo;ll now see the total cost of a trade on the order form.
Ideally, we should have introduced this feature even before the SEBI circular requiring all trading platforms to display costs on the order form. This was a miss from our side.</description></item><item><title>Making auction markets accessible to retail investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-auction-markets-accessible-to-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-auction-markets-accessible-to-retail-investors/</guid><description>If you actively trade, you would&amp;rsquo;ve faced a short delivery and a large auction penalty at least once. Such penalties are due to illiquid auction markets.
We are now trying to improve liquidity in auctions by allowing our customers to participate.
Short delivery happens when the seller doesn&amp;rsquo;t deliver the shares. This can happen if:
Stocks sold for intraday hit an upper circuit. Buy today, sell tomorrow (BTST) traders don&amp;rsquo;t deliver.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Varsity Junior</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-varsity-junior/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-varsity-junior/</guid><description>The skills required to do well in life &amp;amp; with money are very similar. Learning them early can help internalize them. Varsity Junior is our attempt to help create financial awareness in the younger generation so they are better prepared for life.
The first video of Varsity Junior is a brilliant story by Karthik Rangappa explaining how compounding works with money &amp;amp; everything else in life.
We will try to have these videos in Hindi and other regional languages as well.</description></item><item><title>The cyclicality of stockbroking</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-cyclicality-of-stockbroking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-cyclicality-of-stockbroking/</guid><description>Whenever our financials are out, the headline numbers get all the attention. But I think most people don&amp;rsquo;t appreciate just how cyclical broking is.
We had written recently about the business, the risks, looming degrowth, Rainmater Foundation, and more.</description></item><item><title>The dark side of setting goals</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-dark-side-of-setting-goals/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-dark-side-of-setting-goals/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve never set goals at Zerodha, be it user growth, revenues, or profits. The idea has been to get up every day, improve, &amp;amp; do what&amp;rsquo;s right for users, knowing that we&amp;rsquo;ll get to wherever we have to get to. The journey is a lot more fun this way.
In any case, the range of outcomes in business is mostly driven by luck and being at the right place at the right time.</description></item><item><title>Free and open source software (FOSS) has been key to the sucess at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/free-and-open-source-software-has-been-key-to-the-sucess-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/free-and-open-source-software-has-been-key-to-the-sucess-at-zerodha/</guid><description>Free and open source software (FOSS) has been the pillar on which Zerodha is built. Our tech team has been funding &amp;amp; contributing to FOSS. We&amp;rsquo;ve signed the FOSS pledge &amp;amp; hope that companies benefitting from FOSS also sign &amp;amp; start giving back.
Here are some Indian FOSS projects, including ERPNext and Listmonk (built and open-sourced by Dr.K).</description></item><item><title>Business updates, increased disclosures and improving transparency</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/business-updates-increased-disclosures-and-improving-transparency/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/business-updates-increased-disclosures-and-improving-transparency/</guid><description>Almost every brokerage firm, including Zerodha, has had a phenomenal last 2.5 years thanks to a raging bull market. Given our success, thanks primarily to our customers&amp;rsquo; trust, we are obligated to be more transparent &amp;amp; disclose more.Henceforth, we will regularly update our business performance, financial health, business risks, industry risks, technical issues with root cause analysis (RCA), and more.</description></item><item><title>Learning what works and what doest with trading tags</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/learning-what-works-and-what-doesnt-with-trading-tags/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/learning-what-works-and-what-doesnt-with-trading-tags/</guid><description>Like everything in life, the way to get better at trading is to do more of what works &amp;amp; less of what doesn&amp;rsquo;t. Most traders don&amp;rsquo;t track reasons for taking trades &amp;amp; their track record since it has to be done manually. Now you can on Kite web &amp;amp; soon on mobile.
Tags have been on Console since last year for creating goals on holdings &amp;amp; tracking P&amp;amp;L (trading journal). But trades &amp;amp; holdings could be tagged only by the next day, which meant many missed doing it.</description></item><item><title>Can the Indian broking industry continue growing at the same pace?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/can-the-indian-broking-industry-continue-growing-at-the-same-pace/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/can-the-indian-broking-industry-continue-growing-at-the-same-pace/</guid><description>Whenever I get asked if @zerodhaonline or the Indian broking industry will continue to grow at the same pace, I refer to Robinhood, which is a good proxy.
US markets are down ~30% and monthly active users are down ~50%. The activity is back to pre-pandemic levels.</description></item><item><title>New quarterly settlement guidelines</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/new-quarterly-settlement-guidelines/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/new-quarterly-settlement-guidelines/</guid><description>Starting this October 7th, every first Friday of the quarter, all brokerages must transfer unused funds back to the customer&amp;rsquo;s bank account as part of the new account settlement (AS) process. I guess it will be more than Rs 25,000 crores across the industry.
So if your Zerodha account balance reduces or you receive funds in your bank this Saturday, you know why. Until now, AS was spread across a quarter.</description></item><item><title>Margin penalties</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/margin-penalties/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/margin-penalties/</guid><description>Margin penalties are charged on F&amp;amp;O in case of insufficient minimum margins. Upfront penalty is on the broker if a client is allowed to trade with insufficient margins. Non-upfront is on the customer if there&amp;rsquo;s margin shortfall after entering a trade.
There&amp;rsquo;s been a debate over what&amp;rsquo;s an upfront penalty &amp;amp; what&amp;rsquo;s not.
If a broker ensures the required margin is available when entering trades, but if it goes up by EOD, is it upfront?</description></item><item><title>Health challenge at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/health-challenge-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/health-challenge-at-zerodha/</guid><description>Our latest health challenge at Zerodha is to give an option to set a daily activity goal on our fitness trackers. Anyone meeting whatever goal set on 90% of the days over next year gets 1 month&amp;rsquo;s salary as a bonus. One lucky draw of Rs 10lks as a motivation kicker.😃
It is an optional program. Min of 350 active calories/day, in any form. Given that most of us are WFH &amp;amp; sitting is the new smoking, turning into an epidemic.</description></item><item><title>My life guru &amp; the biggest reason for Zerodha's success</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-life-guru-and-the-biggest-reason-for-zerodhas-success/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-life-guru-and-the-biggest-reason-for-zerodhas-success/</guid><description>How K (Kailash) builds tech is how he leads his life, constantly questioning the cost of everything he does—physical, environmental, &amp;amp; debt in any form. My life guru &amp;amp; the biggest reason for Zerodha&amp;rsquo;s success. This chat with Arnav Gupta is awesome.</description></item><item><title>Making insurance easy with ditto</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-insurance-easy-with-ditto-by-finshots/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-insurance-easy-with-ditto-by-finshots/</guid><description>For a long time, one item on our to-do was to build an insurance platform free of conflicts, mis-selling, spam, &amp;amp;, most importantly, advisors to handhold people through the purchase journey. And then we met the Finshot team, and ditto happened. We&amp;rsquo;ve partnered with ditto to make insurance simple for Indians.</description></item><item><title>SEBI prohibits brokers from associating with unregulated algo trading platforms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-prohibits-brokers-from-associating-with-unregulated-algo-trading-platforms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-prohibits-brokers-from-associating-with-unregulated-algo-trading-platforms/</guid><description>A few thoughts on the Indian broking industry and updates about @zerodhaonline as we turn 12 years old. Check out this post on Z-Connect. Some of these platforms have built utilities using broker APIs or macros when APIs aren&amp;rsquo;t available to automate order placements for their users &amp;amp; claim to be partners. We have been reaching out to all these platforms, asking them to remove our names from their website.</description></item><item><title>We just got to 1 crore customers</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/1-crore-customers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/1-crore-customers/</guid><description>We, @zerodhaonline just got to 1 crore customers. Looking back, the biggest tipping point was AADHAR for online account opening. Can&amp;rsquo;t thank the Government &amp;amp; SEBI &amp;amp; Exchanges &amp;amp; Depositories enough for making this happen.
A few things we did that had unintended benefits. The plan to rely on word-of-mouth &amp;amp; have a single offering for all customers had benefits that we never thought of at the start. Economies of scale kicked in not just in tech but across support &amp;amp; ops—the team size has remained the same as we went from 20lk to 1cr clients.</description></item><item><title>12 years of Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/12-years-of-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/12-years-of-zerodha/</guid><description>A few thoughts on the Indian broking industry and updates about @zerodhaonline as we turn 12 years old. Check out this post on Z-Connect.</description></item><item><title>On hacking incidents at Zerodha and measures we're taking</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-hacking-incidents-at-zerodha-and-measures-were-taking-and-what-users-should-do/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-hacking-incidents-at-zerodha-and-measures-were-taking-and-what-users-should-do/</guid><description>There has been some noise about the hacking incidents at Zerodha. Here is some data: Out of the ~65lk customers who traded with us last year, we have ~100 complaints of fraud. ~ 80 where login details were shared willingly &amp;amp; ~20 where email was hacked (all Rediffmail IDs).
As a % of such cases or even normal complaints to overall active customers, we are among the lowest in the broking industry.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha tax reports</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-tax-reports/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-tax-reports/</guid><description>There is no extension for tax filing this year😅 Don&amp;rsquo;t miss filing even if you&amp;rsquo;ve made losses, you may get a notice.
Our Tax P&amp;amp;L report has everything to file your ITR—capital gains, speculative &amp;amp; business income, turnover reports, &amp;amp; more. Check out this Z-Connect blog post for more.</description></item><item><title>Varsity Bytes</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/varsity-bytes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/varsity-bytes/</guid><description>Starting a new playlist on Zerodha Varsity Youtube channel to answer some of the frequently asked queries on Varsity. Here is the 1st video about buying a CE vs. selling a PE when you are bullish (talk about lousy timing🙄 )
PS: Watch at 1.5x 😬</description></item><item><title>Console portfolio visualization</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/console-portfolio-visualization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/console-portfolio-visualization/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;re all searching for stocks that always go up. Looking at charts of winners is easy, but picking such stocks is tough. For normal people, the best way to build wealth is to survive first, that means diversifying. Reason why we have this on Console
A tree map to check the performance by holdings and sectors.
Portfolio insights by TickerTape.</description></item><item><title>Brokerage charges across the indsutry</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/brokerage-charges-across-the-industry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/brokerage-charges-across-the-industry/</guid><description>Don’t know how to say it, but slowdown &amp;amp; all😬
We still don&amp;rsquo;t charge brokerage for equity delivery &amp;amp; charge Rs 20 or 0.03% whichever is lower for intraday.
Many of our competitors, with similar pricing, now charge for equity delivery or have a higher minimum brokerage %</description></item><item><title>Questioning how milk is sourced</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/questioning-how-milk-is-sourced/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/questioning-how-milk-is-sourced/</guid><description>Like many, I had never cared or questioned how my milk is sourced until I started talking to Shashi from Akshayakalpa. Cows that are always tied down, tend to catch diseases fast &amp;amp; the use of antibiotics becomes a necessity. This ultimately shows up in the milk &amp;amp; our bodies.
Scientists &amp;amp; health orgs have long highlighted the serious threat of antibiotic resistance to health &amp;amp; food security. The continued misuse of antibiotics in animals &amp;amp; humans is making this worse.</description></item><item><title>Kailash on the core philosophy that makes Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dr-k-on-the-core-philosophy-that-makes-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dr-k-on-the-core-philosophy-that-makes-zerodha/</guid><description>Dr K’s new post talks about the core philosophy that makes Zerodha. Don’t do unto others, what you don’t want done unto you. So, no spam or tracking, or no freebies to trigger random activity. And yes, it is possible to build a business this way too.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Iceberg orders</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-iceberg-orders/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-iceberg-orders/</guid><description>Active traders lose much more to impact costs than all charges, especially with larger trades. You can now use Iceberg orders on Kite to slice large orders into smaller legs that are executed only once the previous leg is, helping reduce impact costs.
Impact cost, or the money a trader loses in the bid-ask spreads, increases substantially with high volumes or overtrading. Given the very low brokerage costs, it is easy to think that quick buy &amp;amp; sells at small price difference can generate profits, but very tough in reality.</description></item><item><title>Segregation of client collateral</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/segregation-of-client-collateral/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/segregation-of-client-collateral/</guid><description>Starting May 2nd, brokers have to segregate collateral at client level. So funds of one client can&amp;rsquo;t be used to fund another. This is an important regulatory change that makes our markets even safer. India is one of the few in the world to have this.
Post this regulation, broker&amp;rsquo;s capital will get blocked if they allow clients to sell stocks without any funds in the account, use credit from sales to trade more, use 100% of funds, &amp;amp; more.</description></item><item><title>On the growth and profitability of Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-the-growth-and-profitability-of-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-the-growth-and-profitability-of-zerodha/</guid><description>Thanks to the liquidity-driven bull run, we were able to grow &amp;gt;50% in terms of revenue &amp;amp; profitability on an already large base in FY21/22. Every time the press covers our financials, we end up sharing more context to avoid misinterpretation.
Shift to WFH, increased savings, bull market, volatility, IPOs, &amp;amp; India stack led to significant growth in the investor base in the last 2+ years. In almost every bull market, it looks like the broking industry can grow forever, but it cannot—there are significant risks.</description></item><item><title>What's it like being a CEO in a song?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-is-it-like-being-a-ceo-in-a-song/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-is-it-like-being-a-ceo-in-a-song/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s it like being a CEO in a song😬
Jab Koi Baat Bigad Jaaye, Jab Koi Mushkil Pad Jaaye Tum Dena Saath Mera, O Humnawaaz Ho Chaandni Jab Tak Raat, Deta Hai Har Koi Saath Tum Magar Andheron Mein, Na Chhodna Mera Haath This &amp;amp; more with Chandra Srikanth.
I was forced to translate this for my non-Hindi speaking colleagues. 🥶
If something goes wrong, When going gets tough Stand by me, oh my love When there is moonlight, Everyone sticks around When there is darkness, Don’t leave my hand</description></item><item><title>NSE reintroduces Do Not Excersise (DNE)</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nse-reintroduces-do-not-excersise/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nse-reintroduces-do-not-excersise/</guid><description>The Do Not Exercise (DNE) facility for stock options is reintroduced from this expiry onwards. The removal of DNE had increased the risk of losses for traders if OTM options suddendly became ITM.</description></item><item><title>A fun health program at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-fun-health-pogram-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-fun-health-pogram-at-zerodha/</guid><description>We are running a fun health program at Zerodha. Anyone on our team with BMI &amp;lt;25 gets half a month&amp;rsquo;s salary as bonus. The avg BMI of our team is 25.3 &amp;amp; if we can get to &amp;lt;24 by Aug, everyone gets another ½ month as a bonus. It&amp;rsquo;d be fun to compete with other companies 😁
The lowest average BMI or the largest change in average BMI wins. The winner chooses a charity everyone else contributes to.</description></item><item><title>Voting on shareholder proposals at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/voting-on-shareholder-proposals-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/voting-on-shareholder-proposals-at-zerodha/</guid><description>As a shareholder of a company, you are entitled to vote on important company decisions like board appointments, corporate actions, mergers &amp;amp; acquisitions, executive compensation, etc. But very few retail investors vote on shareholder proposals. One reason for this is, of course, retail investors are a small part of the Indian markets. The retail shareholding in NSE-listed companies is about ~7%.
There&amp;rsquo;s also a lack of awareness among investors that they are entitled to vote on company resolutions.</description></item><item><title>Startup of the year 2021</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/startup-the-year-2021/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/startup-the-year-2021/</guid><description>Thanks, Business Standard and the jury, for the acknowledgement. When we win these awards, we get asked, is still a startup? I guess being a startup in today’s world is a state of mind and not just age. In that sense, we hopefully can remain a startup forever.</description></item><item><title>A nudge to stop people from buying stocks that are going to zero</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-nudge-to-stop-people-from-buying-stocks-that-are-going-to-zero/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-nudge-to-stop-people-from-buying-stocks-that-are-going-to-zero/</guid><description>It is concerning that we have a few customers still buying Sintex shares even after this nudge that the stock price will go to 0 and mandating a TOTP. There are so many who decide to buy just because a stock is at 52 week or all-time lows without caring about the reason.</description></item><item><title>How is Zerodha profitable when most new-age startups aren't?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-is-zerodha-profitable-when-most-new-age-startups-arent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-is-zerodha-profitable-when-most-new-age-startups-arent/</guid><description>We get asked often how is Zerodha profitable when most new-age companies aren&amp;rsquo;t. The answer is simple: our cost of acquisition (CAC) is 0. If we had to spend heavily, we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be. CAC at 0 is a philosophical decision, a bit like Dr K on hiring &amp;amp; building products. Philosophical because we aren&amp;rsquo;t in a hurry to grow or get to X valuation. We believe that if you can build products with the customers&amp;rsquo; best interests at heart and enjoy the journey as a team, we&amp;rsquo;ll continue to do okay.</description></item><item><title>Videos on Varsity options trading module</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/videos-on-varsity-options-trading-module/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/videos-on-varsity-options-trading-module/</guid><description>We know you&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for a long time. Here&amp;rsquo;s the first video of the long-awaited options trading module😀 In this video, we start with the basics and understand how an option works. More importantly, we look at how options can be used to reduce risk.</description></item><item><title>User verification at Zerodha and protecting yourself against identity theft</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/user-verification-at-zerodha-and-protecting-yourself-against-identity-theft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/user-verification-at-zerodha-and-protecting-yourself-against-identity-theft/</guid><description>With the rise of online loan platforms, online identity frauds have skyrocketed. These platforms tend to have poor checks when onboarding, given the competitive landscape and pressure to show fast user growth.
Today, it is possible to verify all the proofs submitted by a customer very easily by matching them against the source. PAN through Income tax database. Proof of Identity &amp;amp; Address through Digilocker. Bank details using penny drop facility.</description></item><item><title>From Native to React Native to Flutter</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/from-native-to-react-native-to-flutter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/from-native-to-react-native-to-flutter/</guid><description>A regular question that comes up is about our use of Flutter for building our mobile apps. Here is the history and journey of Kite and Coin mobile apps from our tech team.</description></item><item><title>One of the most complex projects at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-most-challening-project-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-most-challening-project-at-zerodha/</guid><description>Building reports like Tax P&amp;amp;L, holdings, turnover reports etc. have been one of the most complex projects at Zerodha. This involves calculations on a first-in, first-out (FIFO) basis since day 1 for stocks bought, transferred in and adjusting for various corporate actions.
What is a simple number on the UI involves calculations on the fly &amp;amp; innovations in how we store and crunch hundreds of billions of rows of data. This post from our tech team talks about some of this.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Varsity video series</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/varsity-video-series/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/varsity-video-series/</guid><description>Varsity has been 8 yrs in the making with 180+ chapters and 1 lakh+ comments answered by Karthik. Since Video is now a popular format, Karthik has been hard at work creating videos for Varsity. Finally, we&amp;rsquo;re super excited to introduce the Varsity video series..</description></item><item><title>The story behind how the name "Zerodha" came to be</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/story-behind-the-name-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/story-behind-the-name-zerodha/</guid><description>Zerodha = Zero + Rodha. Rodha in Sanskrit means barrier. Removing all barriers for traders is what we were trying to attempt when we started. I hear all versions, Jirodha, Jarodha, 0-dha, etc. Maybe we should have had an easier name, but also tells you name isn&amp;rsquo;t as important.</description></item><item><title>Why are we valuing ourselves at just $2 Billion</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-are-we-valuing-zerodha-at-2-billion/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-are-we-valuing-zerodha-at-2-billion/</guid><description>The only reason why we do a valuation exercise at Zerodha every year is for our ESOP buyback. I keep getting asked why are we valuing ourselves at just $2Billion currently when smaller players are raising money at far higher valuations. Here is why we&amp;rsquo;re conservative.
Some background: We don&amp;rsquo;t promise ESOPs for anyone on our team. Frankly, we never thought we were building something that could become so valuable. So we never thought of ESOPs.</description></item><item><title>On "Powered by AI / ML" marketing</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-powered-by-ai-ml-marketing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-powered-by-ai-ml-marketing/</guid><description>The note yesterday on &amp;ldquo;Powered by AI&amp;rdquo; hype got surprising amounts of attention. Here is a detailed post by Dr K that draws parallels between AI and Rumali roti when it comes to marketing hype.</description></item><item><title>AI and ML at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ai-ml-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ai-ml-at-zerodha/</guid><description>I keep getting asked how we use AI/ML/Blockchain at Zerodha and I keep saying we don&amp;rsquo;t and haven&amp;rsquo;t found any use-case yet. This time I asked our man behind the scene, Dr K, to comment. Couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but share his response.</description></item><item><title>Investing in high growth, low profit businesses</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/new-age-high-growth-businesses/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/new-age-high-growth-businesses/</guid><description>If you are investing in new-age businesses that aren&amp;rsquo;t profitable yet &amp;amp; carry large risks, the right questions to ask are: Can the target market expand? Can they continue growing? Is the user growth real?
Here are a bunch of things to keep in mind</description></item><item><title>Why not IPO Zerodha?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-not-ipo-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-not-ipo-zerodha/</guid><description>Why not IPO Zerodha when you can potentially get ridiculous valuations? Firstly, we think an IPO is the beginning &amp;amp; not the end. As soon as you have lakhs of conservative retail investors on your cap table, the obligations go up exponentially.
We are in a world where companies are getting priced to perfection based on all the future growth potential. For a stock to do well, you have to outperform.</description></item><item><title>Introduction of T+1 settlement</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introduction-of-t1-settlement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introduction-of-t1-settlement/</guid><description>From Feb 2022, the T+1 settlement cycle will be introduced in a phased manner in the Indian markets. The biggest benefit: You can withdraw funds within 1 day when you sell stocks. We&amp;rsquo;ll be the 2nd large market in the world to move to T+1, kudos to SEBI for pushing this.
Why isn&amp;rsquo;t it possible for T+0 or Instant settlement like UPI? Unlike bank transfers where it&amp;rsquo;s money, stocks &amp;amp; money to be settled.</description></item><item><title>Nice guys never finish last</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/be-nice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/be-nice/</guid><description>If there was one life lesson that I could share, it would be: Nice guys never finish last. Your odds of getting lucky in a connected world like ours dramatically go up when you have people genuinely wishing you well.
People root for you when you are genuinely nice to everyone you interact with without any expectation. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if it&amp;rsquo;s a teammate, customer or a stranger. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if you are working for someone or running a business.</description></item><item><title>Trading actively is the toughest way to make easy money</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/active-trading-and-stress/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/active-trading-and-stress/</guid><description>Trading actively is the toughest way to make easy money in life, unlike what most people think. Also, it can be quite stressful &amp;amp; stress can snowball. To trade well, you need to trade less—both no of trades &amp;amp; capital. Beautiful thread by Karthik on stress &amp;amp; trading.</description></item><item><title>The future of Zerodha and competition</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-competition/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-competition/</guid><description>When you&amp;rsquo;re candid in interviews, you run the risk of being quoted out of context with misleading headlines. One such headline was about the future of Zerodha, of us getting beaten by competition in 5 years. This was getting shared and a few people asked me about it.
I think when running a business or even trading, the odds of succeeding are much higher if you have made peace with the worst possible outcome.</description></item><item><title>A corporate actions Nudge to help users avoid mistakes</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-corporate-action-nudge-to-help-users-avoid-mistakes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-corporate-action-nudge-to-help-users-avoid-mistakes/</guid><description>Every time there is a corporate action like a stock split in #IRCTC today and the stock price drops in adjustment, retail investors tend to buy the stock wrongly thinking that the stock has become cheaper. We now have a nudge to inform users.
If you had 1 share of IRCTC at a price of Rs 4500, you will now have 5 shares at Rs 900 each—4 new shares will be credited in 4 days after the stock split.</description></item><item><title>Behaviour of younger investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/first-time-investors-and-the-current-bull-market/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/first-time-investors-and-the-current-bull-market/</guid><description>Unlike the previous bull runs, most of the new investors starting especially because of IPOs this time are under 30 years. The good thing is that they are younger and have less to invest. Meaning they can learn hands-on and bounce back quicker if money mistakes are made.
Historically, activity has always dropped sharply post serious market falls. Folks who have significant investments typically don&amp;rsquo;t do anything in such markets. It will be interesting to see how the new young investors with small ticket sizes behave this time around.</description></item><item><title>Offering unregulated products like Digital Gold, US Stocks, and Unlisted Stocks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/offering-unregulated-products/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/offering-unregulated-products/</guid><description>When you are regulated, everything is normally black &amp;amp; white. People keep asking me why don&amp;rsquo;t we offer crypto, unlisted private companies, US stocks, digital gold — which we anyways didn&amp;rsquo;t sell because it&amp;rsquo;s not the best way to buy gold, and more. Here&amp;rsquo;s why</description></item><item><title>Algo trading platforms and regulations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/algo-trading-platforms-and-regulations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/algo-trading-platforms-and-regulations/</guid><description>Algo trading platforms are becoming popular of late, many of them claim to make you quick &amp;amp; easy money. We thought it&amp;rsquo;s a good time to highlight the risks, regulations, difference b/w APIs &amp;amp; Algos, &amp;amp; the fact that we&amp;rsquo;ve no partnerships with these platforms</description></item><item><title>FOSS (Free &amp; Open Source Software) at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/foss-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/foss-at-zerodha/</guid><description>We use Listmonk built by our very own Dr K Smiling face with open mouth, to send 30mil emails/month at ~$200. It would have cost us tens of 000&amp;rsquo;s $/month otherwise. One of the main reasons for our high margins, profitability, &amp;amp; hence ability to bootstrap is because almost everything we use is FOSS.
K &amp;amp; our tech team also contribute back to FOSS (Free &amp;amp; Open Source Software) significantly. K built Listmonk as a hobby project to solve our email problems.</description></item><item><title>Online nomination and dormant account alerts</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/online-nomination/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/online-nomination/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s at least Rs 80,000 crores of unclaimed money across Banks, Mutual funds, Demats, &amp;amp; more.
We are hoping this alert feature which notifies nominees when accounts become dormant &amp;amp; they don&amp;rsquo;t reKYC, can help in solving this problem.
Hopefully, the Banks &amp;amp; others follow.</description></item><item><title>Who can disrupt new-age online brokers or even exchanges?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/who-can-disrupt-brokers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/who-can-disrupt-brokers/</guid><description>I get asked often, who out there do you think can disrupt the new-age online brokers or even exchanges? Me: I don’t think it will be another stock brokerage firm or a new stock exchange. It will most likely be an outsider, maybe Crypto. Here is why.
In broking or exchange business, both on pricing and product, there is not much left to disrupt. Unless of course, someone figures a way to pay people money for trading (-ve brokerage not allowed by regulation) or figures a way to help all customers make money (very tough)</description></item><item><title>In-Principle approval for our AMC</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/in-principle-approval-for-our-amc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/in-principle-approval-for-our-amc/</guid><description>So, we just got our in-principle approval for our AMC (MF) license. I guess now comes the hard part.</description></item><item><title>Get fit challenge at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/get-fit-challenge-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/get-fit-challenge-at-zerodha/</guid><description>Post the first lockdown, like everywhere, our team Zerodha as a whole was probably the unhealthiest ever, due to the lack of physical activity, work-life imbalance, bad diet, &amp;amp; more. We thought of a way to nudge the team to get healthy and the results are phenomenal.
On our internal @discourse forum, we asked everyone to set a 12-month get-healthy goal &amp;amp; update the progress every month, to create accountability. To increase participation, we said everyone who reaches the goal will get a 1-month salary as bonus &amp;amp; 1 lucky draw for Rs 10lks.</description></item><item><title>Freak trades in options</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/freak-trades-in-futures-and-options/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/freak-trades-in-futures-and-options/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been getting a lot of questions about freak trades in options with huge slippages recently. Here is everything you need to know, why you should use limit orders, &amp;amp; how Zerodha internal dynamic execution range will help you avoid such scenarios.</description></item><item><title>Meet zero</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/featuring-zero/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/featuring-zero/</guid><description>Zero&amp;rsquo;s featured 😍 She sits in on all meetings at Zerodha from regulatory to tech to everything else, quietly assimilating. I&amp;rsquo;ve had dreams, where I come to the office and Zero says &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m the CEO, you can leave now.&amp;ldquo;😬</description></item><item><title>Zerodha's 11th birthday.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-turns-eleven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-turns-eleven/</guid><description>Happy Independence day 🇮🇳. Coincidentally it&amp;rsquo;s Zerodha&amp;rsquo;s 11th birthday today too.😀 If I were to look back, we are most proud of building a business that continues to innovate, &amp;amp; prioritise customer interest over business growth constantly.
We&amp;rsquo;re also proud of the part we continue to play in growing the capital market ecosystem in India through Rainmatterin and give back to society through our foundation RainmatterOrg.
There&amp;rsquo;s plenty for us to get better at, especially around our support.</description></item><item><title>I've stopped giving random gifts. Only been gifting stocks &amp; ETFs for a while now.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-gift-you-can-give/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-gift-you-can-give/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped giving random gifts. Only been gifting stocks &amp;amp; ETFs for a while now. Don&amp;rsquo;t have to waste hours choosing the right gift and the best bit: several of my family &amp;amp; friends have started investing because of this.
The only challenge now is with convincing the wife that Sovereign Gold bonds is the best form of gold on her birthday.</description></item><item><title>Almost 20% of all Zomato applications are through Zerodha.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zomato-ipo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zomato-ipo/</guid><description>Almost 20% of all Zomato applications are through Zerodha. Deepinder, returning the favour from everyone at Zerodha for all the tasty food Zomato delivered when we were hungry. Face savouring food Wishing you and the team at Zomato a blockbuster listing.</description></item><item><title>The last 18 months at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/user-growth-in-the-last-18-months/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/user-growth-in-the-last-18-months/</guid><description>The last 18 months at Zerodha have been eventful, to say the least. Historically, market crashes caused panic &amp;amp; reduced activity. But this crisis led to a rush of new customers looking to buy into stocks on sale. Free time due to lockdowns &amp;amp; low bank deposit rates helped.
Once this younger bunch of first-time investors saw quick profits, they started spreading the word and got their friends &amp;amp; family to invest.</description></item><item><title>Why look at notional contract value when buying options?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-look-at-notional-contract-value/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-look-at-notional-contract-value/</guid><description>Why look at notional contract value when buying options?
Yes, when you buy options the max you can lose is the premium you have paid. But to get a sense of risk and how fast or easily you can lose, you should look at the exposure or contract value, not the premium.
For eg, you have Rs 1L &amp;amp; you use it to buy 20 lots of Nifty calls = Rs 1.</description></item><item><title>Option buying - The riskiest trade</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/options-buying-the-riskiest-trade/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/options-buying-the-riskiest-trade/</guid><description>~80% of all open buy option positions at the end of every day are in losses.
Buying options ruins most retail traders. Because they don&amp;rsquo;t understand the risk of leverage, averaging down, &amp;amp; impact costs.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;re doing to help our users</description></item><item><title>Impact of trading costs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-trading-costs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-trading-costs/</guid><description>What most traders don&amp;rsquo;t realize is that they pay a good chunk of their capital as costs. If you add impact costs, the minimum return an active trader should generate to break even yearly on their portfolio is usually well above 20%. Yep, that high and that tough.
Costs include Statutory costs like STT, Stamp duty, GST Impact costs or slippages (while this doesn’t even seem like a cost, it adds up quickly.</description></item><item><title>Introducing kill switch</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-kill-switch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-kill-switch/</guid><description>When you&amp;rsquo;re in a drawdown while trading, the best thing to do is to take a break. Otherwise, the chances of you being irrational, taking large bets, overtrading &amp;amp; blowing up are high. And to nudge you to do just that, we now have a “Kill Switch”.
Enabling the Kill switch will instantly disable trading. Currently, this is manual. But we are working on automating this where you can set a maximum loss.</description></item><item><title>Introducing tags and trading journal on Console</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-tags-on-console/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-tags-on-console/</guid><description>We are stoked about the new tagging feature on Console. Tagging your trades and maintaining a trading journal can help you become a better trader and also help you track your investment goals.
You can&amp;rsquo;t become a better trader if you don&amp;rsquo;t learn from your mistakes. But in order to learn, you need a proper journal of all your trades and the reasons you took the trades. You can then look back, review, and do more of what is working &amp;amp; less of what isn&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>On the noise about our salaries</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-the-noise-about-our-salaries/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-the-noise-about-our-salaries/</guid><description>I’m surprised by the unwanted noise around this whole salary news of Nikhil, Seema (my wife), &amp;amp; me. The headlines are misleading. We are a private company &amp;amp; no obligations to clarify, but we thought maybe we should, as there are folks who are misinterpreting this.
Firstly the reported figure isn’t the actual salary being drawn. This is an enabling resolution that allows us as working promoters to draw salaries up to the number in case of liquidity requirements.</description></item><item><title>A few thoughts on the Zerodha journey so far</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-zerodha-journey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-zerodha-journey/</guid><description>Last 2 years have been spectacular for Zerodha . Lucky to be at right place right time, ready with products &amp;amp; initiatives when there was a surge in retail participation. With success, what I say gets valued more Grimacing faceHere are a few questions that we get asked frequently.
Why haven’t we raised any external capital, especially at times like these when we could get some crazy valuation? I had talked about it earlier</description></item><item><title>Worklife balance at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/worklife-balance-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/worklife-balance-at-zerodha/</guid><description>At Zerodha, we have just killed all work-related chats post 6 pm &amp;amp; holidays. Also trying to get as many conversations to be asynchronous, moving them from chat to our internal instance of Discourse. Curious to see if this helps reduce the feeling of burnt out &amp;amp; brain fried. Apparently, multitasking hurts performance and may even damage the brain (check the link below). Being part of multiple discussions on different topics in different chat groups simultaneously (Multitasking) has gone up exponentially post WFH.</description></item><item><title>Why FOSS?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-foss/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-foss/</guid><description>Every time we share a post on the Zerodha tech blog, we get a lot of love from the tech community, but also questions like - Why FOSS? Why be so transparent? No security concerns sharing all this info? So yeah, answers from the man behind the scene - Dr. K
Why Free &amp;amp; Open source software?
Superior utility: Pretty much everything in the known universe uses FOSS, from the Mars rovers to our phones to washing machines.</description></item><item><title>Why doesn't Zerodha advertise?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-doesnt-zerodha-advertise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-doesnt-zerodha-advertise/</guid><description>One thing I get asked the most and I’ve tweeted about this numerous times is that why don’t we advertise. Firstly I&amp;rsquo;d shared this sometime back.
Unlike buying a mobile phone or ordering a pizza, you don&amp;rsquo;t invest in stocks &amp;amp; MFs impulsively. Most often than not, we invest because of greed or because of our friends. And regulations don&amp;rsquo;t allow you to advertise greed.
Ads do help you create visibility and build credibility - two really important things in the business of money, especially the first few years.</description></item><item><title>Podcast with Prateek Singh, the founder of LearnApp</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-with-prateek-learnapp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-with-prateek-learnapp/</guid><description>From the start at Zerodha, we&amp;rsquo;ve constantly shared things to educate people about the capital markets. Zerodha Varsity was our first formal attempt in text. But we knew that video was also important, &amp;amp; that people trust content delivered by experts.
This was the reason behind partnering with LearnApp through Rainmatter. The amazing bit in the journey has been that some of the best folks in our industry have been incredibly generous with their time to share their knowledge with no expectations.</description></item><item><title>Right now is probably the stupidest time for fintech firms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-stupidest-time-to-be-raising-money/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-stupidest-time-to-be-raising-money/</guid><description>Right now, is probably the stupidest time for fintech firms like @zerodhaonline to be raising money. It is quite crazy the number of folks reaching out &amp;amp; the different deals. We might regret it in the future, but we are not raising &amp;amp; here are the counterintuitive reasons why.
We don’t need the money, so there’s no point in raising money just because someone is ready to give it to you.</description></item><item><title>Risks of running a brokerage firm</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risks-of-running-a-brokerage-firm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risks-of-running-a-brokerage-firm/</guid><description>The big news from last week was the blow-up of a leveraged hedge fund Archegos &amp;amp; how it caused $billions in losses to its bank/broker. A primer to what it means to be a brokerage for such trades, the risk to reward, and more.
Being a broker is almost like running an insurance business, you keep earning brokerage income (like premium) &amp;amp; are always one black swan or mega volatile day away from giving it all back and more if one large client or many small clients default at the same time.</description></item><item><title>Market size estimates</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/maket-size-estimates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/maket-size-estimates/</guid><description>Market size estimate (Revenue), from the two reports that I just read. Stockbroking: ~$3billion according to ICRA. Gold loan: ~$162billion according to MorningContext.</description></item><item><title>CNBC India business leader award</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cnbc-india-business-leader-awards/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cnbc-india-business-leader-awards/</guid><description>2014: CNBC Young Turks, our first time on TV 2021: CNBC India business leader awards Some year 2020 has been for Zerodha &amp;amp; the capital markets. The challenge though is to help clients avoid making trading mistakes. We are attempting with Nudge &amp;amp; Zerodha Varsity.</description></item><item><title>Being at the right place at right time and surviving</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/right-place-right-time-survival/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/right-place-right-time-survival/</guid><description>Right place right timeSmiling face with open mouthBut damn it&amp;rsquo;s tough to survive &amp;amp; be there when it matters. Zerodha probably started when I started trading 15 years before 2010. It&amp;rsquo;s been 25 years of ups &amp;amp; many downs, almost gave up many times. If it works out you are called passionate, if not foolish.</description></item><item><title>Free &amp; open-source software (FOSS) — one of the reasons behind Zerodha's success</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/foss-the-reason-for-zerodhas-success/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/foss-the-reason-for-zerodhas-success/</guid><description>Free &amp;amp; open-source software (FOSS) is the main reason for the success of Zerodha as K writes.
https://nadh.in/blog/the-atmanirbhartha-of-open-source-software</description></item><item><title>Forbes cover</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/forbes-cover/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/forbes-cover/</guid><description>https://tradingqna.com/t/personal-lessons-from-20-years-of-trading-broking-working/94600
Almost unreal that we could represent Zerodha on the cover of Forbes. Some personal lessons from the many highs &amp;amp; many lows in this 20-year journey working, trading, trying to build different types of businesses, &amp;amp; more.
Businesses can be built in multiple ways. Don&amp;rsquo;t try to cut-copy-paste what others are doing - it mostly won’t work. Do what feels right to you. Your instincts on what is right will work better when you build a business/career around what you love.</description></item><item><title>Why don’t we offer pre-IPO orders?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-doesnt-offer-pre-ipo-orders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-doesnt-offer-pre-ipo-orders/</guid><description>SEBI ICDR regulations define a subscription period for an IPO during which it has to be kept open. Pre-IPO orders act like bids &amp;amp; hence not in spirit. If everyone collected bids before IPO, the sanctity of the book-building process is lost.</description></item></channel></rss>