<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>zerodha on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/zerodha/</link><description>Recent content in zerodha on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/zerodha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Robinhood makes $150 million a year just from instant withdrawal fee</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-makes-150-million-a-year-just-from-instant-withdrawal-fee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-makes-150-million-a-year-just-from-instant-withdrawal-fee/</guid><description>I just discovered that Robinhood will generate approximately $150 million (~₹1,300 crores) in revenue from the fees it charges for processing instant client withdrawals. Their cost to process these is around $35–40 million, which means a clean $100 million to the bottom line, and that’s just from instant withdrawals. 😬
As an Indian startup with some scale, founders dream of generating revenue like this from non-core products. Hence the rush to introduce everything: loans, insurance, payments, and other financial services.</description></item><item><title>AMA with Zerodha's core team</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ama-with-zerodhas-core-team/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ama-with-zerodhas-core-team/</guid><description>A bunch of you asked us questions about our revenues, regulations, international investing, AI, and more. Nikhil, Kailash, Karthik Rangappa, Venu, and I answered a lot of those questions in this AMA.
Since there were several questions about US investing: we didn&amp;rsquo;t offer it until now because the regulations were unclear, but now there&amp;rsquo;s clarity. In May, SEBI and IFSCA allowed brokers to operate in GIFT City, and in June, the exchanges allowed brokers to offer third-party products.</description></item><item><title>The love we get for all the content is crazy</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-love-we-get-for-all-the-content-is-crazy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-love-we-get-for-all-the-content-is-crazy/</guid><description>The love we get for all the content on Varsity, Markets by Zerodha etc. is crazy. 😀What we&amp;rsquo;ve done from day 1 is focus on sharing quality insights rather than chasing engagement, pointless optimizations, and gimmicks. The trust we&amp;rsquo;ve built over almost a decade is a direct result of that—people reading and watching us and then sharing it with their friends and family.</description></item><item><title>Real stories from parents investing through Zerodha minor accounts.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-stories-from-parents-investing-through-zerodha-minor-accounts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-stories-from-parents-investing-through-zerodha-minor-accounts/</guid><description>I can keep giving gyan about starting to invest early for your kids, but nothing beats hearing it from parents who are actually doing it. Here are some first-hand takes from people using a Zerodha minor account to invest for their children.
P.S. Our youngest account holder is just 64 days old. 😀</description></item><item><title>India’s $3 trillion in idle gold needs smarter financialization.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</guid><description>Indian households hold ~$3 trillion in gold (World Gold Council estimate), sitting idle in lockers. Meanwhile, equity investments fund companies that need capital to grow. We need better ways to financialize this gold beyond just gold loans.</description></item><item><title>Why short-term growth is the wrong metric</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-short-term-growth-is-the-wrong-metric/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-short-term-growth-is-the-wrong-metric/</guid><description>On the question of what would we do if weekly options were removed, I suppose we&amp;rsquo;ll see another hit to our revenues in the short-term.
Having said that, when you&amp;rsquo;re building a business for the long term, focusing on quarterly or even annual growth is a poor metric. The more you focus on them, the higher the odds that you&amp;rsquo;ll do things that are bad for your customers.</description></item><item><title>15 years of Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/15-years-of-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/15-years-of-zerodha/</guid><description>From 2021, I had been tweeting about the risks to the broking business, but somehow I kept getting surprised on the upside. But starting around October last year, all the risks I was thinking about crystallised. First came the STT increase on options, then the removal of exchange transaction charge rebates, and a reduction in weekly expiries. In addition to this, there was a significant decline in market activity. Due to all these factors, our revenues and profits suffered a decline.</description></item><item><title>What does Zerodha do differently?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-zerodha-do-differently/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-zerodha-do-differently/</guid><description>Someone on Reddit asked what does Zerodha do differently, how are we profitable, why don&amp;rsquo;t IPO etc. This is what I replied:
Hmmm&amp;hellip; so you forget that we have spent 15 years getting here. And maybe another 10 years, before Zerodha, I was involved in the markets in some form. So, 25 years in all. Things in business compound over time, especially if you like or love what you are doing and if you are lucky to be in the right place and time.</description></item><item><title>2 lakh registrations on Varsity Live</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/2-lakh-registrations-on-varsity-live/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/2-lakh-registrations-on-varsity-live/</guid><description>We just hit 2 lakh registrations on Varsity Live in a short time!
The goal with Varsity Live has always been to make high-quality, interactive financial education accessible to as many people as possible.
By live, I don’t mean boring webinars or one-way monologues. I mean fun, engaging sessions where you can interact with a mentor, learn by doing exercises, use tools, build things, take quizzes, and more.
So yeah, people are really liking what we’re doing so far.</description></item><item><title>Manage investments better with secondary demat account</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/manage-investments-better-with-secondary-demat-account/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/manage-investments-better-with-secondary-demat-account/</guid><description>When I was trading actively (before Zerodha), I had an offline demat account where I held all my investments and an online account for all my trades. This was a way to avoid the temptation of &amp;ldquo;trading&amp;rdquo; my investments 😬
If I had to sell any of my investments, there was effort involved. I had to physically fill out the delivery instruction slips and send them to the broker to move holdings to my primary demat and then sell them.</description></item><item><title>Tax filing simplified with Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/tax-filing-simplified-with-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/tax-filing-simplified-with-zerodha/</guid><description>Just about 10 days left to file your taxes. While figuring out taxation for trading and investments is usually a nightmare, we&amp;rsquo;ve made it super easy. I think our tax statements are easily the best in the industry by a mile.
On Console, you’ll find all the statements you need to file taxes for your trades and investments:
Tax P&amp;amp;L statement with trade-wise charges, turnover across all segments, equity and non-equity segregation, capital gains split for pre- and post-July 23, 2024, and more.</description></item><item><title>In her Interest, an initiative by Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/in-her-interest-an-initiative-by-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/in-her-interest-an-initiative-by-zerodha/</guid><description>I still remember that around 2014–15, only 2–3% of our customers were women. Today, that number is about 30%. When I saw this spike, I was surprised and wanted to understand what had changed. So we ran a small survey among a couple of hundred customers.
Roughly 50% of the women use their accounts on their own, while the other 50% have their accounts managed by someone else, such as their husbands, brothers, or children.</description></item><item><title>How Zerodha grew without Advertising</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-zerodha-grew-without-advertising/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-zerodha-grew-without-advertising/</guid><description>When we started Zerodha, we didn&amp;rsquo;t have the money to advertise, not that it would&amp;rsquo;ve worked. So that only way we could grow was through word of mouth and customer referrals, and the only way that was possible was to offer products and services that customers would talk about.
We started our referral program when we started in 2010, and since then, the referral incentives have changed numerous times because of regulations.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Kite Backup - A WhatsApp-based emergency mode</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-kite-backup-a-whatsapp-based-emergency-mode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-kite-backup-a-whatsapp-based-emergency-mode/</guid><description>Trading platforms are ridiculously complex. One hiccup anywhere from exchange connections to cloud servers can create an issue. Over the years, we&amp;rsquo;ve built tons of safeguards and redundancies, but we&amp;rsquo;re still paranoid.
Apart from all of this, we&amp;rsquo;ve built a new emergency trading mode using WhatsApp. In case of a disaster scenario, which we hope never happens, and the Kite web and mobile both become inaccessible during market hours, this backup mode will allow you to cancel orders and exit positions.</description></item><item><title>How SEBIs standardised files made our systems leaner and efficient</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-sebis-standardised-files-made-our-systems-leaner-and-efficient/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-sebis-standardised-files-made-our-systems-leaner-and-efficient/</guid><description>One critical aspect of the brokerage business most people are unaware of is the sheer underlying complexity.
At a high level, we integrate with multiple stock exchanges, depositories, RTAs, banks, and others. Each of these integrations (hundreds of APIs and file exchanges) has been non-uniform and non-standard, resulting in massive amounts of technical and operational complexity. These are completely invisible to a broker&amp;rsquo;s clients.
A great example of quiet, systemic backend work yielding significant impact is the multi-year exercise SEBI undertook to standardise data exchange across market entities—the Unified Distilled File Formats (UDiFF).</description></item><item><title>Easier account opening and lower brokerage for NRI clients</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/easier-account-opening-and-lower-brokerage-for-nri-clients/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/easier-account-opening-and-lower-brokerage-for-nri-clients/</guid><description>The number of NRIs who want to invest in India but don&amp;rsquo;t because of the complex account opening process is quite high. NRI accounts are also much higher in value compared to resident Indian accounts, by at least 10 times.
Hardly a day goes by without emails or messages from NRIs asking us to make account opening easier at Zerodha. The paperwork today is onerous, especially the need to visit an embassy.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Zerodha Multi Asset Fund</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-zerodha-multi-asset-fund/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-zerodha-multi-asset-fund/</guid><description>After 20+ years of being in the markets, one thing has become crystal clear to me: most investors should just invest in low-cost equity, debt, and gold index funds and do something useful with their lives. 😬 Trying to pick the &amp;ldquo;best fund&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;best asset class&amp;rdquo; is largely a waste of time and energy.
What most investors don&amp;rsquo;t realize is that they&amp;rsquo;d get far better returns by focusing on maximizing their earning potential rather than obsessing over picking the &amp;ldquo;best stocks and funds.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha doesn’t charge for equity and mutual fund investments</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-doesnt-charge-for-equity-and-mutual-fund-investments/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-doesnt-charge-for-equity-and-mutual-fund-investments/</guid><description>The one question I get asked the most by new customers is: Does Zerodha charge for equity and mutual fund investments?
No, investing in stocks, ETFs, and direct mutual funds at Zerodha is free. We also don&amp;rsquo;t charge any DP charges for mutual funds and bear the cost ourselves.
Also, we only charge a DP charge once per day per stock, regardless of the number of sell orders. So even if you sell a stock ten times in a day, the DP charge only applies once.</description></item><item><title>Privacy simple at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/privacy-made-simple-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/privacy-made-simple-at-zerodha/</guid><description>Storage was the only permission we used to ask for, and we&amp;rsquo;ve removed that as well. It&amp;rsquo;s now 0 permissions out of 10 😀</description></item><item><title>Why India needs easier short selling for better price discovery</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-india-needs-easier-short-selling-for-better-price-discovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-india-needs-easier-short-selling-for-better-price-discovery/</guid><description>The lack of short selling in Indian markets is causing potential market distortions.
Unless we make shorting of stocks easy in the Indian markets, price discovery will be impaired. India has been a structurally long-only market with almost no shorting activity, because borrowing stock to short is really hard and is an offline process.
Because of this long-only bias, there&amp;rsquo;s probably very little short-selling talent as well, even if large funds want to start shorting.</description></item></channel></rss>