<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>zerodhacapital on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/zerodhacapital/</link><description>Recent content in zerodhacapital on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/zerodhacapital/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Our Loan Against Shares (LAS) business just crossed Rs. 500 crores</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/our-loan-against-shares-las-business-just-crossed-rs-500-crores/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/our-loan-against-shares-las-business-just-crossed-rs-500-crores/</guid><description>Our Loan Against Shares (LAS) business just crossed Rs 500 crores.
It&amp;rsquo;s a business that we hadn&amp;rsquo;t spoken about much for a long time, for a variety of reasons, including regulatory. But the reason why we offer LAS via Zerodha Capital is that it&amp;rsquo;s a secured product.
The other reason is that I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good way to help clients clear their high-interest loans, like personal loans, credit card dues, etc.</description></item><item><title>Drawing regulatory boundaries between trading and lending</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/drawing-regulatory-boundaries-between-trading-and-lending/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/drawing-regulatory-boundaries-between-trading-and-lending/</guid><description>The exchanges reiterated last night that stock brokers cannot distribute any lending products other than those explicitly tied to trading (MTF). This applies even if the broker is registered as a research analyst. However, despite yesterday&amp;rsquo;s circular, brokers&amp;rsquo; parent companies are allowed to create a &amp;ldquo;super-app&amp;rdquo; where broking and lending happens side-by-side. This is permissible today because there are no restrictions on the parent entity.
The core concern is that any type of lending or inducement to borrow on a trading platform could lead to borrowed money flowing back into the markets.</description></item><item><title>Why we don't provide personal and credit card loans through Zerodha Capital</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-we-dont-provide-personal-and-credit-card-loans-through-zerodha-capital/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-we-dont-provide-personal-and-credit-card-loans-through-zerodha-capital/</guid><description>Someone on our team recently asked, &amp;ldquo;Why do we only offer Loan Against Securities on Zerodha Capital?&amp;rdquo; Why not personal loans or credit cards with their higher interest rates?
The simple answer is we can&amp;rsquo;t do anything different there. And our cost of funds doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. We&amp;rsquo;re at ~8.5%, while banks raise money at ~3.5%, and large NBFCs around ~7%.
Can&amp;rsquo;t compete on rates, and usually the best borrowers go where the rates are the lowest.</description></item><item><title>Check your credit rating on Zerodha Capital</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-your-credit-rating-on-zerodha-capital/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-your-credit-rating-on-zerodha-capital/</guid><description>I did a credit check on Zerodha Capital to check out the flow, and my score is 747.
So I am not good enough for CRED😬
Btw, if you want to run a quick credit check (no Spam), check it out.</description></item></channel></rss>