<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>zero1 on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/zero1/</link><description>Recent content in zero1 on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/zero1/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Zero1 by Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-zero1-by-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-zero1-by-zerodha/</guid><description>We started the Zero1 network to collaborate with people to create high-quality content and support them so they can focus on content.
This, as seen in this pic, taken at the Zero1 fest, is turning into quite a line-up. 😀
And the fest was incredible! Thanks to Prateek Singh, Under 25 Universe, Sagar Gudekote, and the rest of the team.
The panel with Nikhil and Kunal Shah, where Nik, as usual, changed the format on the stage and amongst everything else, we spoke about what we don&amp;rsquo;t like about each other.</description></item><item><title>First real market correction after COVID</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/first-real-market-correction-after-covid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/first-real-market-correction-after-covid/</guid><description>For investors who started investing after the pandemic, this is the first real market correction. Markets are cyclical, and given the way our markets went up from late 2020, this fall was inevitable. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how good the data is, but it seems like the number of investors stopping their SIPs has gone up. This is the wrong thing to do. What an SIP helps you do is to average your investments across different market cycles.</description></item><item><title>Retiring Early? Read This First</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/retiring-early-read-this-first/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/retiring-early-read-this-first/</guid><description>I hadn’t realized how popular this Financial Independence, Retire Early (FIRE) trend had become until I saw this Zero1ByZerodha video😬. There’s nothing wrong with wanting to retire early, but retirement isn’t just about money.
From what I’ve seen, many people don’t consider all the financial, emotional, and psychological pitfalls of retirement and end up regretting it later. So, if you’ve been thinking about retiring early, here are some things you should know.</description></item><item><title>At the Zero1 fest</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/at-the-zero1-fest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/at-the-zero1-fest/</guid><description>Slowly getting back to normal. 😀
At the Zero1 fest, talking about health and wealth with Nuseir Yassin, JC, and Shashank Mehta</description></item></channel></rss>