<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rainmatter climate on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter-climate/</link><description>Recent content in rainmatter climate on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter-climate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Wheels in motion, a short film on Rainmatter</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/wheels-in-motion-a-short-film-on-rainmatter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/wheels-in-motion-a-short-film-on-rainmatter/</guid><description>The more I interact with Sameer Shisodia, who heads Rainmatter Foundation, our foundation team, and people from social organizations, the more I appreciate the need for a vibrant social sector.
Like how startups can help solve some problems that larger companies can’t due to legacy reasons or because of their size, which makes getting things done harder, the social sector can attempt to experiment with solutions that can benefit society but are hard for the Government &amp;amp; bureaucracy to attempt given its sheer size.</description></item><item><title>Social Stock Exchange can help improve funding access to social organizations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/social-stock-exchange-can-help-improve-funding-access-to-social-organizations/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/social-stock-exchange-can-help-improve-funding-access-to-social-organizations/</guid><description>One of the big challenges for social organizations to raise funds from the mainstream population is overcoming the trust barrier— potential donors have a hard time trusting that their investment will be put to good use.
In the case of listed companies on stock exchanges, we have regulators &amp;amp; comprehensive disclosure norms that have built trust over time. If we had something similar for social organizations – a social stock exchange (SSE), could it help them raise funds easily and not just rely on Corporate social responsibility (CSR)?</description></item></channel></rss>