<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>fintech on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/fintech/</link><description>Recent content in fintech on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/fintech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How SEBIs standardised files made our systems leaner and efficient</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-sebis-standardised-files-made-our-systems-leaner-and-efficient/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-sebis-standardised-files-made-our-systems-leaner-and-efficient/</guid><description>One critical aspect of the brokerage business most people are unaware of is the sheer underlying complexity.
At a high level, we integrate with multiple stock exchanges, depositories, RTAs, banks, and others. Each of these integrations (hundreds of APIs and file exchanges) has been non-uniform and non-standard, resulting in massive amounts of technical and operational complexity. These are completely invisible to a broker&amp;rsquo;s clients.
A great example of quiet, systemic backend work yielding significant impact is the multi-year exercise SEBI undertook to standardise data exchange across market entities—the Unified Distilled File Formats (UDiFF).</description></item><item><title>Dark patterns in finance apps</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dark-patterns-in-finance-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dark-patterns-in-finance-apps/</guid><description>One of the biggest challenges in building a financial services business is that the incentives are often skewed toward doing what’s good for the business and not for the customer. It’s very hard to consistently put customers first.
This is one of the main reasons why finance apps are full of dark patterns, more than almost any other category. Dark patterns are design tricks used in apps and websites to make you do things that are not in your best interest.</description></item><item><title>The best example of an Indian fintech product made for India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-example-of-an-indian-fintech-product-made-for-india/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-example-of-an-indian-fintech-product-made-for-india/</guid><description>India is unique. Copy-pasting models from the US, etc, has hardly worked. Paytm&amp;rsquo;s speaker for Indian vendors that reads out payments is one of the best examples of a product made specifically for the Indian context by an Indian fintech.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on why digital wealth management platforms haven't scaled</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-challenges-of-scaling-digital-wealth-platforms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-challenges-of-scaling-digital-wealth-platforms/</guid><description>In offline wealth management, overselling is par for the course. Since these conversations don&amp;rsquo;t leave a trail, overselling isn&amp;rsquo;t spotted—this is why conversion is better. Digital platforms cannot do the same because it leaves a trail &amp;amp; this is why I think they haven&amp;rsquo;t scaled.</description></item><item><title>Wrong estimates of trading activity, market size and market share</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/wrong-estimates-of-trading-activity-market-size-and-market-share/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/wrong-estimates-of-trading-activity-market-size-and-market-share/</guid><description>Even to this day, a lot of people misconstrue the turnover numbers declared by the exchanges. This often leads to wrong estimates of trading activity and market size &amp;amp; share. So if A buys stock X for Rs 1lk &amp;amp; B sells for Rs 1lk, the exchange turnover = Rs 1lk &amp;amp; not Rs 2lks.
To calculate market size estimates based on exchange turnovers, the right way would be to multiply the exchange turnover by 2 and then calculate the %.</description></item><item><title>How large is the Indian market for B2C tech businesses and fintechs by revenue potential?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-large-is-the-indian-market-for-b2c-tech-businesses-and-fintechs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-large-is-the-indian-market-for-b2c-tech-businesses-and-fintechs/</guid><description>How large is the Indian market for B2C tech businesses in terms of users who can generate revenue? Maybe 15 crores max! Here&amp;rsquo;s why, with Fintech as a reference, since some data is available. I guess it is important to know this, so we can all be rationally optimistic.
I get puzzled whenever someone says India has 140cr people &amp;amp; only 9cr demat accounts (6% of the population), &amp;amp; this can grow to 40 crores (25% as in developed nations) over the next few years.</description></item></channel></rss>