<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>regulation on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/regulation/</link><description>Recent content in regulation on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/regulation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>SEBI cautions against investing in digital gold</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cautions-against-investing-in-digital-gold/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cautions-against-investing-in-digital-gold/</guid><description>Digital gold is unregulated. A timely reminder from SEBI.
Most people don’t realize that nobody regulates digital gold, and if something were to happen to the platforms or companies selling it, there’s not much you can do.
It’s also a subpar way to get exposure to gold. You pay 3% GST the moment you buy. Then there are spreads of another 2–3%, which means as soon as you purchase digital gold, you’re already down about 6%, and that’s before even factoring in regulatory risk.</description></item><item><title>Crypto F&amp;O thrives without clear regulation in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/crypto-fo-thrives-without-clear-regulation-in-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/crypto-fo-thrives-without-clear-regulation-in-india/</guid><description>I hadn’t realised how popular crypto F&amp;amp;O has become.
These Indian crypto platforms seem to be thriving in a regulatory grey zone, and because of lower taxes and extreme leverage in derivatives.
From the Economic Times</description></item><item><title>How SEBIs standardised files made our systems leaner and efficient</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-sebis-standardised-files-made-our-systems-leaner-and-efficient/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-sebis-standardised-files-made-our-systems-leaner-and-efficient/</guid><description>One critical aspect of the brokerage business most people are unaware of is the sheer underlying complexity.
At a high level, we integrate with multiple stock exchanges, depositories, RTAs, banks, and others. Each of these integrations (hundreds of APIs and file exchanges) has been non-uniform and non-standard, resulting in massive amounts of technical and operational complexity. These are completely invisible to a broker&amp;rsquo;s clients.
A great example of quiet, systemic backend work yielding significant impact is the multi-year exercise SEBI undertook to standardise data exchange across market entities—the Unified Distilled File Formats (UDiFF).</description></item><item><title>What the Jane Street probe tells us about India’s market oversight</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-the-jane-street-probe-tells-us-about-indias-market-oversight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-the-jane-street-probe-tells-us-about-indias-market-oversight/</guid><description>You’ve got to hand it to SEBI for going after Jane Street. If the allegations are true, it’s blatant market manipulation.
The shocking part? They kept at it even after receiving warnings from the exchanges. Maybe this is what happens when you&amp;rsquo;re used to the lenient U.S. regulatory regime. Think about the structure of U.S. markets: dark pools, payment for order flow, and other loopholes that allow hedge funds to make billions off retail investors.</description></item><item><title>SEBI's new UPI security feature</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-new-upi-security-feature/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-new-upi-security-feature/</guid><description>The number of fraud cases involving scammers impersonating brokers and asking for money to be transferred to random accounts has skyrocketed.
To protect investors, SEBI has introduced a new UPI security feature. All legitimate fund transfers will now only go to verified UPI handles like: brokername@validbank (as shown in the image). We @zerodhaonline will implement this soon, and this should help reduce fraud incidents significantly.</description></item><item><title>SCRA rules clarified</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scra-rules-clarified/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scra-rules-clarified/</guid><description>Finally, after clarification of SCRA rules by Ministry of Finance and NSE, brokers can now invest their own funds without exchange approvals or restrictions.
This is huge for Rainmatter. We can now allocate more capital to support Indian startups directly from the brokerage entity.</description></item><item><title>SEBIs consultation paper on algo trading</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-consultation-paper-on-algo-trading/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-consultation-paper-on-algo-trading/</guid><description>SEBI recently published a consultation paper on algo trading for retail investors.
My understanding of it is it should be ok for savvy traders using APIs for individual trading with some reasonable order limits. But the APIs have to be accessed through only static IPs, but this isn’t hard to get.
But platforms that offer algos or readymade strategies will need to get them approved through the broker. The broker, in turn, has to register all algos and strategies with the exchanges.</description></item><item><title>SEBI reasserts regulations on unlisted shares</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-reasserts-regulations-on-unlisted-shares/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-reasserts-regulations-on-unlisted-shares/</guid><description>Allowing transactions in unlisted shares is a violation of SEBI regulations. Clarification from SEBI, today.</description></item><item><title>How SEBI puts consumer interest first</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-sebi-puts-consumer-interest-first/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-sebi-puts-consumer-interest-first/</guid><description>One challenge in today&amp;rsquo;s media-saturated environment for brokers like us and also regulators is the sheer noise because even small things can be blown out of proportion.
Having said that, I am part of various committees, and what has always amazed me is the consultative approach that SEBI has taken over the years. No regulation is passed without hearing from the industry and other experts. This shows in the fact that today, our capital markets are among the safest in the world, if not the safest.</description></item><item><title>Rise in options trading and the regulatory risks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rise-in-options-trading-and-the-regulatory-risks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rise-in-options-trading-and-the-regulatory-risks/</guid><description>As I&amp;rsquo;ve said before, regulatory risk is the biggest risk for any regulated business.
We are in the middle of a period of excess in options trading. Volumes in index options have gone up from 4.6 lk cr in 2018 to 138 lk cr in 2024, and, more importantly, the share of retail has gone up from 2% to 41%.
We have been a big beneficiary of this jump in volume but have always been aware that it can be significantly reduced in size due to regulations, which can significantly hurt revenues, and that&amp;rsquo;s also why we have never made any forward projections.</description></item><item><title>SEBI’s new regulations on direct securities transfer and increased BSDA limits</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-new-regulations-on-direct-securities-transfer-and-increased-bsda-limits/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-new-regulations-on-direct-securities-transfer-and-increased-bsda-limits/</guid><description>Since 2019, SEBI has brought in several changes that have made our markets safer and more investor-friendly. It started with segregation of client funds, compulsory quarterly bank runs on brokers (quarterly settlement), removing pooling of funds for MF transactions, and more.
The latest regulation is around the direct payout of securities to investor demat accounts upon purchase. Today, when investors buy securities, they&amp;rsquo;re credited by the clearing corporation to the stock broker&amp;rsquo;s pool account, who in turn transfers them to the clients.</description></item><item><title>SEBI circular on sharing realtime price data with third parties</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-circular-on-sharing-realtime-price-data-with-third-parties/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-circular-on-sharing-realtime-price-data-with-third-parties/</guid><description>Sebi&amp;rsquo;s circular essentially means that it ends all platforms offering trading competition, demo trading, CFDs, and more.
I had written a oost on this topic. Read more.</description></item><item><title>Companies can now issue bonds with face value of Rs.10,000</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/companies-can-now-issue-bonds-with-face-value-of-rs-10000/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/companies-can-now-issue-bonds-with-face-value-of-rs-10000/</guid><description>Companies can now issue bonds with face value of Rs.10,000. This is a great move that can help attract retail participation in the bonds. With all the changes in the last few years, SEBI has done an amazing job of making bonds accessible to small investors.
Read more.</description></item><item><title>Could this be the death of currency derivative trading?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/could-this-be-the-death-of-currency-derivative-trading-/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/could-this-be-the-death-of-currency-derivative-trading-/</guid><description>I have said this before, regulatory risk is by far the biggest risk for stock brokers.
The RBI has its own reasons for restricting unhedged currency derivatives, but this means the death of currency derivative trading on stock exchanges by retail traders.
Context</description></item><item><title>Rise in unauthorized forex, CFD and binary trading platforms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rise-in-unauthorized-forex-cfd-and-binary-trading-platforms/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rise-in-unauthorized-forex-cfd-and-binary-trading-platforms/</guid><description>Unauthorized forex, CFD and binary trading platforms have become a serious nuisance. You might have seen advertisements for these platforms on YouTube and other social media platforms.
These platforms blatantly sell greed and offer insane leverage (~100X) to attract users. Not only are these platforms illegally operating in India, but they are also incredibly scammy. Even if you unknowingly put some money in, they make it incredibly hard to withdraw.</description></item><item><title>A few things I learned about food and sustainability</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-need-to-protect-net-neutrality/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-need-to-protect-net-neutrality/</guid><description>Recently, there have been talks of revisiting the idea of net neutrality in India. We enjoy some of the strongest net neutrality rules in the world, ensuring a fair and level playing field for everyone to access and innovate on the internet, no matter how big and small.
The exponential growth of our technology and startup ecosystem would not have been possible without this. Without net-neutrality, there perhaps would not have been a Zerodha.</description></item><item><title>Stock market prediction gaming platforms are regulatorily grey</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-market-prediction-gaming-platforms-are-regulatorily-grey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-market-prediction-gaming-platforms-are-regulatorily-grey/</guid><description>Stock market prediction gaming platforms where you guess the direction of stocks and indices for rewards is a regulatorily grey business model, to say the least.
NSE has always been clear that any market data (bid, ask, LTP, etc.) can only be used by the customers of a brokerage firm for trading purposes. Exchanges have IP over this data. Globally, revenues from data feeds are more than transaction fee revenues for exchanges.</description></item><item><title>The twisted world of illegal CFDs &amp; binary options</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Evolution of the Indian stock broking industry since the Harshad Mehta scam - Scam92 TV Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/evolution-of-the-indian-stock-broking-industry-the/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/evolution-of-the-indian-stock-broking-industry-the/</guid><description>#Scam1992TheHarshadMehtaStory - a thread on everything that has changed since then in the world of Indian stockbroking.
Today the settlement cycle is 2 days &amp;amp; SEBI is hinting at a 1-day cycle soon (first few countries in the world). Back then, it was 14 days (the time within which you have to pay full money and take delivery of stocks or deliver stocks if sold).
Today, a customer can’t buy stocks without the minimum money in the account or sell without stocks in Demat.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping vs Funding – a tax arbitrage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</guid><description>Promoters of businesses to professional investors, now chase “growth” and increase valuations to sell their stake in the business instead of trying to earn profits and taking the earnings out through dividends — to save on taxes and earn more efficiently.</description></item></channel></rss>