<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>scams on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/scams/</link><description>Recent content in scams on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/scams/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The case of Octfax and other CFD platforms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-case-of-octfax-and-other-cfd-platforms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-case-of-octfax-and-other-cfd-platforms/</guid><description>The case of Octafx is another example of how people are lured by extreme leverage and then scammed. OctaFX, and most other CFD platforms, are the counterparty to every trade you take on them.
Essentially, the platform makes money only when you lose. And trading with extreme leverage of 100 to 500 times your capital is a sure way to lose money.
I had written about CFDs sometime back. We recently spoke about this in The Daily Brief by Markets by Zerodha as well.</description></item><item><title>The nuisance of fake trading apps</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-nuisance-of-fake-trading-apps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-nuisance-of-fake-trading-apps/</guid><description>Fake trading app scams have exploded and have become a mega nuisance.
These scams work by inducing you to trade and making you think that making money is easy. So first, you are added to WhatsApp groups and then asked to install fake trading apps that look exactly like those of major brokers.
On the first couple of trades, you will make money. This is designed to convince you that you can make a lot of money.</description></item><item><title>From loan apps to phishing websites, more scams</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/from-loan-apps-to-phishing-websites-more-scams/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/from-loan-apps-to-phishing-websites-more-scams/</guid><description>After the Chinese loan apps scam, the latest scam from actors in China and other Asian countries is phishing websites. Fraudsters are creating hundreds of websites and trading apps that look similar to the websites of Indian brokers.
Unwitting users who click on the app download links, etc., will be prompted to download the fake app. The goal is to get people to transfer money by taking advantage of their familiarity with these apps.</description></item><item><title>Rise in shady illegal loan apps</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rise-in-shady-illegal-loan-apps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rise-in-shady-illegal-loan-apps/</guid><description>Finance apps that ask for full access to contacts, messages, photos, etc. are a red flag, especially if it&amp;rsquo;s a loan app. A lot of these lending apps are digital avatars of predatory moneylenders (Sudakhor in Hindi).
The number of people getting fleeced by shady and illegal loan apps has gone up significantly. Many individuals caught up in the web of these apps frequently resort to drastic actions, such as suicide.</description></item><item><title>Rise in scams involving fake screenshots, P&amp;L reports, ID cards, bank statements, etc.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rise-in-scams-involving-fake-screenshots-pl-reports-id-cards-bank-statements-etc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rise-in-scams-involving-fake-screenshots-pl-reports-id-cards-bank-statements-etc/</guid><description>Scams involving fake screenshots, P&amp;amp;L reports, ID cards, bank statements, etc., have become a mega nuisance. We just spotted a new one.
A scammer created a fake Zerodha employee ID card and met our customer whom he had spotted online and said he had won an award from Zerodha. He tells our customer that if he transfers Rs 1.8 lakh as a registration fee, he will get back Rs 5 crore.</description></item><item><title>Beware of pig butchering scams</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-pig-butchering-scams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-pig-butchering-scams/</guid><description>The scale of pig butchering scams in India runs into tens of thousands of crores. It is scary how many people fall for fake job offer scams, scammy high-return investment schemes and crypto investments, etc.
As the name implies, a pig butchering scam involves fattening the victim before butchering. Scammers gain the trust of users by using fake profiles. They use the pretense of love and friendship to gain the trust of users and then induce them to send money for jobs and high-return investments and steal the money.</description></item><item><title>Scams in the name of courier companies</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scams-in-the-name-of-courier-companies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scams-in-the-name-of-courier-companies/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a new scam in the name of FedEx, Blue Dart, and other courier companies that you need to be aware of 👇 A colleague got a call from a person claiming to be from FedEx saying that a parcel had been confiscated by the police because drugs were found in it.
Since he was expecting a courier from an e-commerce platform, he panicked. He then got a video call from someone claiming to be the police and issued this official-looking letter.</description></item></channel></rss>