<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>crypto on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/crypto/</link><description>Recent content in crypto on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/crypto/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The growing risks of trading crypto derivatives without clear rules</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-growing-risks-of-trading-crypto-derivatives-without-clear-rules/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-growing-risks-of-trading-crypto-derivatives-without-clear-rules/</guid><description>Crypto derivative exchanges exist in regulatory limbo. A bit like Schrödinger&amp;rsquo;s cat—neither fully regulated nor unregulated. This ambiguity is being exploited in dangerous ways. By the way, I am not referring to the actual buying and selling of Cryptocurrency.
The first risk with unregulated platforms is, of course, that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing you can do if something goes wrong.
The other big problem with crypto F&amp;amp;O is that you have no idea who&amp;rsquo;s on the other side of your order.</description></item><item><title>Crypto F&amp;O thrives without clear regulation in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/crypto-fo-thrives-without-clear-regulation-in-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/crypto-fo-thrives-without-clear-regulation-in-india/</guid><description>I hadn’t realised how popular crypto F&amp;amp;O has become.
These Indian crypto platforms seem to be thriving in a regulatory grey zone, and because of lower taxes and extreme leverage in derivatives.
From the Economic Times</description></item><item><title>Crypto platforms flaunting rules</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/crypto-platforms-flaunting-rules/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/crypto-platforms-flaunting-rules/</guid><description>On one side, SEBI is working on restricting F&amp;amp;O, but on the other side, this crypto F&amp;amp;O ad is on the front page of ET.
By the way, all these platforms have taken the stance that the 1% TDS rule doesn&amp;rsquo;t apply to crypto F&amp;amp;O. For regular crypto transactions, 1% of the transaction is deducted as TDS. Something for @nsitharaman and @FinMinIndia to check out.</description></item><item><title>Crypto and FTX collapse</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/crypto-and-ftx-collapse/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/crypto-and-ftx-collapse/</guid><description>For those wanting to know what is happening in Crypto, @finshots has explained the FTX collapse.</description></item><item><title>Indian companies incorporated outside inside are flipping back</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-companies-incorporated-outside-inside-are-flipping-back/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-companies-incorporated-outside-inside-are-flipping-back/</guid><description>Happy to see many companies building for India incorporated outside, flipping back. While some are for regulatory reasons, but mostly for conducive IPO markets here. For India to become wealthy inclusively, wealth creation from successful businesses has to happen at home.
If wealth created by leveraging Indian resources doesn&amp;rsquo;t stay back home, how will we ever be a $5 trillion economy &amp;amp; more? Hoping India can do whatever it takes to be attractive for companies to incorporate here—from the ease of running a business to raising capital to go IPO</description></item><item><title>Government taxes on Crypto could have been blessing in disguise</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/government-taxes-on-crypto-could-have-been-blessing-in-disguise-for-indian-crypto-investors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/government-taxes-on-crypto-could-have-been-blessing-in-disguise-for-indian-crypto-investors/</guid><description>I think many Indian crypto investors accidentally got lucky due to TDS &amp;amp; Tax on Crypto announcement this budget in Feb. Activity &amp;amp; participation dropped significantly immediately. If not, many could have potentially been trapped trying to buy the dip &amp;amp; then averaging down.
Even when trading stocks, the biggest reason for losses is trying to make a wrong trade right by throwing good money at bad money. That is averaging down when the price moves against the trade, without considering if the portfolio is getting concentrated or not.</description></item><item><title>Impact of 1% TDS on all Crypto trades</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-1-percent-tds-on-all-crypto-trades/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-1-percent-tds-on-all-crypto-trades/</guid><description>They say the devil is in the details. I missed the 1% TDS on all Crypto trades, similar to the TCS of 0.1% on Gold. I assumed that the TDS is only on the gains. With this 1% TDS, I think Crypto volumes in India will drop off the cliff come July 1st 2022 when it is implemented.
A 1% TDS means 1% of every trade value is blocked by the platform.</description></item></channel></rss>