<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rainmatter foundation on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter-foundation/</link><description>Recent content in rainmatter foundation on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter-foundation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The idea behind Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-idea-behind-rainmatter-foundation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-idea-behind-rainmatter-foundation/</guid><description>Rainmatter Foundation started with the question of what&amp;rsquo;s the point of all this success if we don&amp;rsquo;t have a planet to live on?
Despite the success of Zerodha, we’re still only helping ~ 2-3% of Indians. At the same time, our planet is facing an existential threat due to climate change. So we asked ourselves—what if we could use our learnings &amp;amp; experiences from building Zerodha to help make a difference.</description></item><item><title>The risk of holding crypto assets with crypto exchanges</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-risk-of-holding-crypto-assets-with-crypto-exchanges/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-risk-of-holding-crypto-assets-with-crypto-exchanges/</guid><description>Coinbase&amp;rsquo;s latest filing: Customer assets could be at risk in case of bankruptcy. Indian crypto investors on exchanges also need to be aware of this. Unlike the stock market where stocks are held in a demat with a depository &amp;amp; have no broker risk, crypto with exchanges carry a risk</description></item><item><title>Partnership with Organic Mandya</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/partnership-with-organic-mandya/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/partnership-with-organic-mandya/</guid><description>Our focus at Rainmatter foundation is to help create green jobs, livelihoods &amp;amp; help preserve the environment using sustainable agri practices. In that journey, we&amp;rsquo;re super delighted to join Madhu Chandan &amp;amp; Organic Mandya on their mission to change farming &amp;amp; improve lives of farmers.
Organic Mandya has helped create kitchen gardens with fruit tree saplings in 5,000+ homes. Through Sunday Santhes in Mandya, they&amp;rsquo;re creating direct farmer to consumer relationships.</description></item></channel></rss>