<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rainmatter-foundation on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter-foundation/</link><description>Recent content in rainmatter-foundation on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter-foundation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A project to spread the health and ecological benefits of millets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-project-to-spread-the-health-and-ecological-benefits-of-millets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-project-to-spread-the-health-and-ecological-benefits-of-millets/</guid><description>We add millet (ragi) to wheat flour and dosa batter at home. It&amp;rsquo;s healthier &amp;amp; tastier. Most of us don&amp;rsquo;t know that millets are also good for the planet because they consume much less water &amp;amp; pesticides. The reason why everyone should introduce millet &amp;amp; talk about it too.
The United Nations has declared 2023 the International Year of Millets.
As the world discovers the health and ecological benefits of millets, India can become the global millet hub and also create green jobs locally.</description></item><item><title>Elephants By The Lake</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/elephants-by-the-lake.md/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/elephants-by-the-lake.md/</guid><description>Elephants by the lake or EBTL was Rainmatter Foundation&amp;rsquo;s first experiment to regenerate ~70 acres of land adjoining a forest not far from Bengaluru. We hope to create an open playbook that can be replicated elsewhere to create many more EBTLs.
Make sure to read the brilliant project updates by Team Ananas, who are executing the restoration based on permaculture principles. We hope to have workshops at EBTL soon, share learnings, &amp;amp; provide help to anyone attempting similar projects across the country.</description></item><item><title>Social stock exchange can making investing for the future mainstream</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/social-stock-exchange-can-make-investing-for-the-future-mainstream/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/social-stock-exchange-can-make-investing-for-the-future-mainstream/</guid><description>The second-biggest problem for the planet outside climate change is the concentration of wealth unless it helps society. Now that SEBI has put a framework on the Social stock exchange (SSE), we are excited to see how we can nudge the top 5% of India to think of the bottom 80%.
For anybody who wants to invest in the future, the biggest challenge is the trust deficit. Non-profits that list on the SSE have to adhere to regulations &amp;amp; make disclosures like listed companies.</description></item><item><title>Indian cities weren't built to handle their current population</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-cities-werent-built-to-handle-their-current-population.md/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-cities-werent-built-to-handle-their-current-population.md/</guid><description>Most large Indian cities weren&amp;rsquo;t built in a way to handle as many people living in them today. Disasters are bound to continue. The only real solution is to have many smaller cities with their own economies. Over 50% of our team now live there; a silver lining from Covid. If companies can afford to have teams work remotely or through small satellite offices, I think they should nudge teams to work out of small towns &amp;amp; cities.</description></item><item><title>A little more forest everywhere</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-little-more-forrest-everywhere/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-little-more-forrest-everywhere/</guid><description>Through Rainmatter Organisation, we support organizations working on climate change issues. But we understand that the biggest impact can be made by individuals. Planting trees is a good start &amp;amp; we have been trying to help by giving free saplings. Karthik Rangappa&amp;rsquo;s Deverakadu.</description></item><item><title>The idea behind Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-idea-behind-rainmatter-foundation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-idea-behind-rainmatter-foundation/</guid><description>Rainmatter Foundation started with the question of what&amp;rsquo;s the point of all this success if we don&amp;rsquo;t have a planet to live on?
Despite the success of Zerodha, we’re still only helping ~ 2-3% of Indians. At the same time, our planet is facing an existential threat due to climate change. So we asked ourselves—what if we could use our learnings &amp;amp; experiences from building Zerodha to help make a difference.</description></item><item><title>The risk of holding crypto assets with crypto exchanges</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-risk-of-holding-crypto-assets-with-crypto-exchanges/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-risk-of-holding-crypto-assets-with-crypto-exchanges/</guid><description>Coinbase&amp;rsquo;s latest filing: Customer assets could be at risk in case of bankruptcy. Indian crypto investors on exchanges also need to be aware of this. Unlike the stock market where stocks are held in a demat with a depository &amp;amp; have no broker risk, crypto with exchanges carry a risk</description></item><item><title>Partnership with Organic Mandya</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/partnership-with-organic-mandya/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/partnership-with-organic-mandya/</guid><description>Our focus at Rainmatter foundation is to help create green jobs, livelihoods &amp;amp; help preserve the environment using sustainable agri practices. In that journey, we&amp;rsquo;re super delighted to join Madhu Chandan &amp;amp; Organic Mandya on their mission to change farming &amp;amp; improve lives of farmers.
Organic Mandya has helped create kitchen gardens with fruit tree saplings in 5,000+ homes. Through Sunday Santhes in Mandya, they&amp;rsquo;re creating direct farmer to consumer relationships.</description></item></channel></rss>