<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rainmatter-foundation on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter-foundation/</link><description>Recent content in rainmatter-foundation on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter-foundation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>IISc x Rainmatter</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/iisc-x-rainmatter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/iisc-x-rainmatter/</guid><description>We recently partnered with the Indian Institute of Science (IISc) to create India’s first Entrepreneur-in-Residence (EIR) Program for longevity.
Longevity isn’t just about living longer—it’s about living better. This program provides an opportunity for scientists, technologists, and aspiring entrepreneurs to build solutions at the intersection of deep science and technology.
India needs accessible and affordable healthcare solutions, and this program serves as a platform to encourage such innovation. The selected teams will work closely with IISc faculty at Longevity and our team at Rainmatter .</description></item><item><title>Nine years of Rainmatter</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nine-years-of-rainmatter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nine-years-of-rainmatter/</guid><description>At Rainmatter we invested about Rs 275 crores in 47 startups last year. It may seem like we&amp;rsquo;re investing in too many startups, but we aren&amp;rsquo;t a typical VC and don&amp;rsquo;t function like one. We don&amp;rsquo;t take board seats, have no exit clauses, and have a perennial structure (patient capital)—that is, we are in it for the long term.
We may be early, but our thesis right now is that climate and health will be megatrends of the future.</description></item><item><title>Wheels in motion, a short film on Rainmatter</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/wheels-in-motion-a-short-film-on-rainmatter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/wheels-in-motion-a-short-film-on-rainmatter/</guid><description>The more I interact with Sameer Shisodia, who heads Rainmatter Foundation, our foundation team, and people from social organizations, the more I appreciate the need for a vibrant social sector.
Like how startups can help solve some problems that larger companies can’t due to legacy reasons or because of their size, which makes getting things done harder, the social sector can attempt to experiment with solutions that can benefit society but are hard for the Government &amp;amp; bureaucracy to attempt given its sheer size.</description></item><item><title>Rethinking the idea of corporate social responsibility (CSR)</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rethinking-the-idea-of-corporate-social-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rethinking-the-idea-of-corporate-social-responsibility/</guid><description>The more time I spend at Rainmatter Foundation, the more I realize that India&amp;rsquo;s social sector&amp;rsquo;s funding model needs to be fixed. There are too few funders and too many existential issues.
Most people think that supporting non-profits is only the job of Corporate CSR.
Last year, ~Rs 25,000 crores was allocated to the social sector under CSR, which mandates corporations to give 2% of their profits. But given the monumental challenges the social sector is trying to tackle, such as education, health, conservation, and more, this isn&amp;rsquo;t enough.</description></item><item><title>The importance of long-term support for philanthropy in the social sector</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-long-term-support-for-philanthropy-in-the-social-sector/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-long-term-support-for-philanthropy-in-the-social-sector/</guid><description>As part of Rainmatter, I get to be in meetings &amp;amp; learn from the smartest people in the social sector, like #ClimateRISE today. The thing I still don&amp;rsquo;t understand is why Philanthropy/CSR is oriented toward funding projects &amp;amp; not supporting organizations over the long-term.
In both profit and non-profit organizations, the odds of creating returns or impact are highest when you find the right founders and give them enough runway to experiment.</description></item><item><title>The many benfits of hemp</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-many-benfits-of-hemp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-many-benfits-of-hemp/</guid><description>Hemp belongs to the Cannabis sativa family—the same as marijuana. They look similar, but hemp is versatile and has multiple uses, including as a superfood. It&amp;rsquo;s also good for the planet. Unlike its notorious cousin, hemp doesn&amp;rsquo;t get you high 😬. Partly why it isn&amp;rsquo;t popular.
Because they look alike and come from the same family, hemp is often mistaken for marijuana, which is one reason why it isn&amp;rsquo;t mainstream.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Bill Gates and talking about Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/meeting-bill-gates-and-talking-about-rainmatter-foundation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/meeting-bill-gates-and-talking-about-rainmatter-foundation/</guid><description>Thanks for the acknowledgment Bill Gates. All our giving forward initiatives are mostly thanks to the team at Rainmatter Foundation
In this journey, we&amp;rsquo;re at that place where we&amp;rsquo;re also still building up Zerodha. Kailash building tech and I managing the overall business, and both of us giving some time to Rainmatter, while Nikhil manages investments.
We are incredibly lucky to be in a position to be able to give forward or invest for future.</description></item><item><title>Two years of Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/two-years-of-rainmatter-foundation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/two-years-of-rainmatter-foundation/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s 2 years since we started giving back through Rainmatter Foundation with Sameer leading it. We started with a question: What&amp;rsquo;s the point of wealth, if we can&amp;rsquo;t use it to make a difference to society. Fast-forward 2 years, I have more questions than answers.
First lesson was that it isn&amp;rsquo;t giving back. We think of it as giving forward or investing in our collective future. Just reframing what we are attempting to do has given us more clarity</description></item><item><title>A project to spread the health and ecological benefits of millets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-project-to-spread-the-health-and-ecological-benefits-of-millets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-project-to-spread-the-health-and-ecological-benefits-of-millets/</guid><description>We add millet (ragi) to wheat flour and dosa batter at home. It&amp;rsquo;s healthier &amp;amp; tastier. Most of us don&amp;rsquo;t know that millets are also good for the planet because they consume much less water &amp;amp; pesticides. The reason why everyone should introduce millet &amp;amp; talk about it too.
The United Nations has declared 2023 the International Year of Millets.
As the world discovers the health and ecological benefits of millets, India can become the global millet hub and also create green jobs locally.</description></item><item><title>Elephants By The Lake</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/elephants-by-the-lake.md/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/elephants-by-the-lake.md/</guid><description>Elephants by the lake or EBTL was Rainmatter Foundation&amp;rsquo;s first experiment to regenerate ~70 acres of land adjoining a forest not far from Bengaluru. We hope to create an open playbook that can be replicated elsewhere to create many more EBTLs.
Make sure to read the brilliant project updates by Team Ananas, who are executing the restoration based on permaculture principles. We hope to have workshops at EBTL soon, share learnings, &amp;amp; provide help to anyone attempting similar projects across the country.</description></item><item><title>Social stock exchange can making investing for the future mainstream</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/social-stock-exchange-can-make-investing-for-the-future-mainstream/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/social-stock-exchange-can-make-investing-for-the-future-mainstream/</guid><description>The second-biggest problem for the planet outside climate change is the concentration of wealth unless it helps society. Now that SEBI has put a framework on the Social stock exchange (SSE), we are excited to see how we can nudge the top 5% of India to think of the bottom 80%.
For anybody who wants to invest in the future, the biggest challenge is the trust deficit. Non-profits that list on the SSE have to adhere to regulations &amp;amp; make disclosures like listed companies.</description></item><item><title>Indian cities weren't built to handle their current population</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-cities-werent-built-to-handle-their-current-population.md/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-cities-werent-built-to-handle-their-current-population.md/</guid><description>Most large Indian cities weren&amp;rsquo;t built in a way to handle as many people living in them today. Disasters are bound to continue. The only real solution is to have many smaller cities with their own economies. Over 50% of our team now live there; a silver lining from Covid. If companies can afford to have teams work remotely or through small satellite offices, I think they should nudge teams to work out of small towns &amp;amp; cities.</description></item><item><title>A little more forest everywhere</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-little-more-forrest-everywhere/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-little-more-forrest-everywhere/</guid><description>Through Rainmatter Organisation, we support organizations working on climate change issues. But we understand that the biggest impact can be made by individuals. Planting trees is a good start &amp;amp; we have been trying to help by giving free saplings. Karthik Rangappa&amp;rsquo;s Deverakadu.</description></item><item><title>The idea behind Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-idea-behind-rainmatter-foundation/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-idea-behind-rainmatter-foundation/</guid><description>Rainmatter Foundation started with the question of what&amp;rsquo;s the point of all this success if we don&amp;rsquo;t have a planet to live on?
Despite the success of Zerodha, we’re still only helping ~ 2-3% of Indians. At the same time, our planet is facing an existential threat due to climate change. So we asked ourselves—what if we could use our learnings &amp;amp; experiences from building Zerodha to help make a difference.</description></item><item><title>The risk of holding crypto assets with crypto exchanges</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-risk-of-holding-crypto-assets-with-crypto-exchanges/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-risk-of-holding-crypto-assets-with-crypto-exchanges/</guid><description>Coinbase&amp;rsquo;s latest filing: Customer assets could be at risk in case of bankruptcy. Indian crypto investors on exchanges also need to be aware of this. Unlike the stock market where stocks are held in a demat with a depository &amp;amp; have no broker risk, crypto with exchanges carry a risk</description></item><item><title>Alternatives to plastic using seaweed</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alternatives-to-plastic-using-seaweed/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alternatives-to-plastic-using-seaweed/</guid><description>Today&amp;rsquo;s Finshots talks about the 300 million tonnes of plastic the world produces every year and the irreversible damage we together cause the planet. We RainmatterOrg were blown away when we first met Zerocircle who are working on an alternative to plastic using seaweed.
Zerocircle is building a compostable &amp;amp; ocean-safe alternative to plastics from farmed seaweed, which dissolves harmlessly in the ocean after use. These are the ideas that really need to scale so that they lower costs &amp;amp; achieve mass adoption for the sake of our planet.</description></item><item><title>Partnership with Organic Mandya</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/partnership-with-organic-mandya/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/partnership-with-organic-mandya/</guid><description>Our focus at Rainmatter foundation is to help create green jobs, livelihoods &amp;amp; help preserve the environment using sustainable agri practices. In that journey, we&amp;rsquo;re super delighted to join Madhu Chandan &amp;amp; Organic Mandya on their mission to change farming &amp;amp; improve lives of farmers.
Organic Mandya has helped create kitchen gardens with fruit tree saplings in 5,000+ homes. Through Sunday Santhes in Mandya, they&amp;rsquo;re creating direct farmer to consumer relationships.</description></item></channel></rss>