<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>technology on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/technology/</link><description>Recent content in technology on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Potential impact of artificial intelligence (AI) on mankind and capitalism.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/potential-impact-of-artificial-intelligence-on-mankind-and-capitalism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/potential-impact-of-artificial-intelligence-on-mankind-and-capitalism/</guid><description>It took us ~30 mins to integrate commoditized ChatGPT, see tangible benefits, and realize that more than 20% of jobs could be automated. Now, imagine what more intelligent tools could lead to?
Dr K on what artificial intelligence (AI) could mean for capitalism and humanity</description></item><item><title>Dictpress - Build dictionaries for any language</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dictpress-build-dictionaries-for-any-language/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dictpress-build-dictionaries-for-any-language/</guid><description>FOSS has to be one of the purest forms of art - build a product that solves a problem &amp;amp; then give it away for others to build on for free.
Damn, wish I had learnt some programming when I was younger or can figure a way to swap my brains with his (K). 😬
https://dict.press</description></item><item><title>From Native to React Native to Flutter</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/from-native-to-react-native-to-flutter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/from-native-to-react-native-to-flutter/</guid><description>A regular question that comes up is about our use of Flutter for building our mobile apps. Here is the history and journey of Kite and Coin mobile apps from our tech team.</description></item><item><title>Why FOSS?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-foss/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-foss/</guid><description>Every time we share a post on the Zerodha tech blog, we get a lot of love from the tech community, but also questions like - Why FOSS? Why be so transparent? No security concerns sharing all this info? So yeah, answers from the man behind the scene - Dr. K
Why Free &amp;amp; Open source software?
Superior utility: Pretty much everything in the known universe uses FOSS, from the Mars rovers to our phones to washing machines.</description></item></channel></rss>