<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>technology on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/technology/</link><description>Recent content in technology on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Alar’s new update makes the dictionary faster and easier to build on</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alars-new-update-makes-the-dictionary-faster-and-easier-to-build-on/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alars-new-update-makes-the-dictionary-faster-and-easier-to-build-on/</guid><description>In 2020, we did something very odd. Well, K (Kailash, CTO) did. He helped open-source Alar, a Kannada–English dictionary. It&amp;rsquo;s a little absurd, considering we&amp;rsquo;re a stockbroking company, but the project itself is one of monumental importance.
The story of how Alar came to be is even more inspiring. It was essentially the life&amp;rsquo;s work of one man: V. Krishna. Alar is the online version of what he had built over 40 years—researching, writing, and cataloguing more than 150,000 Kannada words and 240,000 English definitions, complete with all their attendant details.</description></item><item><title>Accessibility has always been core to how we build</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/accessibility-has-always-been-core-to-how-we-build/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/accessibility-has-always-been-core-to-how-we-build/</guid><description>In November 2024, the Supreme Court ruled that accessibility is a fundamental right, directing businesses to ensure their digital platforms are accessible to people with disabilities. The Court essentially said that in a digital-first world, denying digital access means denying basic rights. It’s not just about compliance, it’s about constitutional equality.
Accessibility has been core to how we build at Zerodha. The mandate didn’t change our approach, it just gave us a deadline.</description></item><item><title>Robinhood makes $150 million a year just from instant withdrawal fee</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-makes-150-million-a-year-just-from-instant-withdrawal-fee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-makes-150-million-a-year-just-from-instant-withdrawal-fee/</guid><description>I just discovered that Robinhood will generate approximately $150 million (~₹1,300 crores) in revenue from the fees it charges for processing instant client withdrawals. Their cost to process these is around $35–40 million, which means a clean $100 million to the bottom line, and that’s just from instant withdrawals. 😬
As an Indian startup with some scale, founders dream of generating revenue like this from non-core products. Hence the rush to introduce everything: loans, insurance, payments, and other financial services.</description></item><item><title>Didn’t expect our support for FFmpeg to get this much love</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/didnt-expect-our-support-for-ffmpeg-to-get-this-much-love/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/didnt-expect-our-support-for-ffmpeg-to-get-this-much-love/</guid><description>The amount of love this has gotten is quite crazy. I was just asking K, &amp;lsquo;How does it make sense that there are tech companies worth billions and trillions of dollars who use these pieces of open source software without which they could not exist, and yet are unwilling to fund them?&amp;rsquo;
We’ve been funding open source projects from ~2018 on and off before setting up FLOSS/fund in 2024. We run on open source, so supporting is a no-brainer.</description></item><item><title>One year of the Zerodha FLOSS fund</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/one-year-of-the-zerodha-floss-fund/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/one-year-of-the-zerodha-floss-fund/</guid><description>We started FLOSS/fund in 2024 to give up to $1 million annually to support the development of FOSS (free and open-source) projects globally.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what K said in a post reflecting on the past year, making the case for the Indian government also to fund FOSS for strategic tech sovereignty:
&amp;ldquo;Actually, no amount of material resources can enable governments to develop, nurture, and sustain complex, high-quality FOSS projects themselves in the way a community of passionate maintainers can.</description></item><item><title>Open source for tech sovereignty</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-for-tech-sovereignty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-for-tech-sovereignty/</guid><description>Tech sovereignty and self-sufficiency are national conversations now, the world over. Free and open-source software (FOSS) enables just that—tech sovereignty and, at the same time, mutually assured global collaboration and innovation. IndiaAI Mission&amp;rsquo;s recent push for sovereign open-source LLMs is a great example for this. Without FOSS, there would be no Zerodha or the global digital ecosystem as we know it today.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an article by K (Kailash) on the topic from 2021 that&amp;rsquo;s still relevant now.</description></item><item><title>Financial inclusion needs more than just digital access</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-inclusion-needs-more-than-just-digital-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-inclusion-needs-more-than-just-digital-access/</guid><description>The entire Indian financial services industry, including Zerodha, has been a massive beneficiary of the ease of digital onboarding via Aadhaar e-Sign, eKYC, etc. It has been a big reason for the increase in financial inclusion among Tier 2 and 3 cities and rural parts of the country; people who had not previously interacted with the formal financial system.
While many of us take the benefits of these digital systems for granted, being in a city like Bengaluru (and a position of privilege), I was surprised by the extent of challenges with OTP verification and the physical/biometric side of these systems until I read articles like these in The Times of India and elsewhere.</description></item><item><title>How SEBIs standardised files made our systems leaner and efficient</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-sebis-standardised-files-made-our-systems-leaner-and-efficient/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-sebis-standardised-files-made-our-systems-leaner-and-efficient/</guid><description>One critical aspect of the brokerage business most people are unaware of is the sheer underlying complexity.
At a high level, we integrate with multiple stock exchanges, depositories, RTAs, banks, and others. Each of these integrations (hundreds of APIs and file exchanges) has been non-uniform and non-standard, resulting in massive amounts of technical and operational complexity. These are completely invisible to a broker&amp;rsquo;s clients.
A great example of quiet, systemic backend work yielding significant impact is the multi-year exercise SEBI undertook to standardise data exchange across market entities—the Unified Distilled File Formats (UDiFF).</description></item><item><title>About MCP and the future of investing and trading in a world of AI</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/about-mcp-and-the-future-of-investing-and-trading-in-a-world-of-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/about-mcp-and-the-future-of-investing-and-trading-in-a-world-of-ai/</guid><description>I keep asking K about what all this progress in AI means for our business. It feels to me like we&amp;rsquo;re at the very beginning of a massive shift in how financial services will work.
At some point, I think all of it, from investing and trading to banking and payments, will happen through custom AI-powered apps built by users themselves using natural language instructions.
In that world, what&amp;rsquo;s the role of a broker?</description></item><item><title>Prayoga students contribute to Global Science</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/prayoga-students-contribute-to-global-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/prayoga-students-contribute-to-global-science/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s something awesome 😍
Reshma, Lakshmi, Kirat, and Yamini are four young 8th- and 9th-standard girls from rural and socially disadvantaged communities in Karnataka. They published a scientific research paper in a peer-reviewed international journal on an innovative method for synthesizing copper oxide nanoparticles for water purification, with the help of three researchers from Prayoga. What&amp;rsquo;s even more impressive is that these girls are the first in their families to go to school.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha wouldn’t exist without open-source software</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-wouldnt-exist-without-open-source-software/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-wouldnt-exist-without-open-source-software/</guid><description>Suffice to say, without Free and Open-Source Software (FOSS), there would be no Zerodha . Our tech stack is built on open source software. Remember, it is trusted by almost 2 crore Indians with ~₹6 lakh crores of assets, and we contribute about 15% of daily retail exchange volumes in India.
Over the years, we&amp;rsquo;ve not only been using FOSS, but have been actively contributing code, money, and time to existing projects.</description></item><item><title>Reducing CO₂ emissions with faster software</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/reducing-co-emissions-with-faster-software/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/reducing-co-emissions-with-faster-software/</guid><description>The topic of reducing emissions from our software came up yesterday, and when I asked K about it, he said this. 😃
Check out the article here.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha's new FLOSS fund</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodhas-new-floss-fund/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodhas-new-floss-fund/</guid><description>Free and Open Source Software (FOSS) has been an integral part of Zerodha&amp;rsquo;s success. We rely on it heavily to power everything from our products to Z-connect, Tradingqna, and even my laptop (which runs Zorin Linux). Without FOSS, Zerodha wouldn&amp;rsquo;t exist and neither would the larger startup ecosystem.
We have always supported the open source ecosystem in numerous ways and are now formalizing all those efforts by setting up a fund to support FOSS projects globally, starting with $1 million a year.</description></item><item><title>K on software as an "in-descipine"</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/k-on-software-as-an-in-descipline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/k-on-software-as-an-in-descipline/</guid><description>What happened with CrowdStrike is utterly terrifying. That one software update can disrupt and cripple everything from schools, hospitals, stock exchanges, airports, etc. around the world is hard to wrap your head around it.
K (Kailash) recently wrote a post about it.</description></item><item><title>On software as an "in-discipline"</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-software-as-an-in-discipline/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-software-as-an-in-discipline/</guid><description>What happened with CrowdStrike is utterly terrifying. That one software update can disrupt and cripple everything from schools, hospitals, stock exchanges, airports, etc. around the world is hard to wrap your head around it.
K (Kailash) recently wrote a post about it.
Link to the post.</description></item><item><title>Deepfakes' impact on the future of identity verification in financial services in the AI era</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/deepfakes-impact-on-the-future-of-identity-verification-in-financial-services-in-the-ai-era/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/deepfakes-impact-on-the-future-of-identity-verification-in-financial-services-in-the-ai-era/</guid><description>The rise of AI technology and deepfakes pose a large risk to the financial services industry.
The tipping point for Indian financial services businesses was when onboarding became completely digital, thanks to Aadhaar, etc. For businesses onboarding a new customer, an important aspect is ensuring that the documents and the person opening the account are real.
The normal process that&amp;rsquo;s followed today is to fetch the ID or address proof data from the source using Digilocker and or Aadhaar.</description></item><item><title>The downsides of social media</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-downsides-of-social-media/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-downsides-of-social-media/</guid><description>This desire to build large social media followings can be a slippery slope.
People are generally curious about successful &amp;amp; famous people, so it&amp;rsquo;s easier for celebs from movies, sports, etc., maybe even some businessmen 😀, to build a social media presence quickly.
For everyone else, there is always an incentive to be loud, controversial or oversell because that&amp;rsquo;s what gets the attention. The exception to this is people who write and share high-quality things, but this is very hard.</description></item><item><title>The importance of net neutrality</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-net-neutrality/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-net-neutrality/</guid><description>Recently, there have been talks of re-visiting the idea of net neutrality in India. We enjoy some of the strongest net neutrality rules in the world, ensuring a fair and level playing field for everyone to access and innovate on the internet, no matter how big and small.
The exponential growth of our technology and startup ecosystem would not have been possible without this. Without net-neutrality, there perhaps would not have been a Zerodha.</description></item><item><title>The journey of Omnesys</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-journey-of-omnesys/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-journey-of-omnesys/</guid><description>The number of things that have to align for a business to get off the ground and do well is ridiculous. Zerodha could start with a bare minimum capital and no tech background in 2010 only because NSE India offered NOW, a free trading platform built by Omnesys.
Over the years, Omnesys has changed hands many times, and it&amp;rsquo;s finally back home, where I was invited to open their first office—the circle of life 😬</description></item><item><title>Potential impact of artificial intelligence (AI) on mankind and capitalism.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/potential-impact-of-artificial-intelligence-on-mankind-and-capitalism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/potential-impact-of-artificial-intelligence-on-mankind-and-capitalism/</guid><description>It took us ~30 mins to integrate commoditized ChatGPT, see tangible benefits, and realize that more than 20% of jobs could be automated. Now, imagine what more intelligent tools could lead to?
Dr K on what artificial intelligence (AI) could mean for capitalism and humanity</description></item></channel></rss>