<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>startups on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/startups/</link><description>Recent content in startups on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/startups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The rapid evolution of LLMs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-rapid-evolution-of-llms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-rapid-evolution-of-llms/</guid><description>2023: LLMs generate random strings of text and &amp;ldquo;hallucinate.&amp;rdquo;
2026: Linus Torvalds, creator of Linux, says LLMs can generate code better than he can write.
It&amp;rsquo;s remarkable how good these large language models have become in such a short span of time, to the point where they&amp;rsquo;re on par with, or better than, humans across numerous domains.
K (Kailash) recently wrote a brilliant post about how software development, as we&amp;rsquo;ve known it for decades, is over.</description></item><item><title>Case for building India’s own deep tech stack</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/case-for-building-indias-own-deep-tech-stack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/case-for-building-indias-own-deep-tech-stack/</guid><description>Tech seems to be getting effectively nationalized. Starting from around 2020, we’ve seen an increase in export controls on things like chips, critical minerals, restrictions on advanced manufacturing equipment, and various other trade restrictions. Supply chains have become a security issue for countries.
We’re no longer in a world where India can be okay with just exporting IT services. If we don’t build domestic deep tech capabilities, we’ll be locked out when it matters most.</description></item><item><title>If you want to build something, India has never offered better odds</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/if-you-want-to-build-something-india-has-never-offered-better-odds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/if-you-want-to-build-something-india-has-never-offered-better-odds/</guid><description>There’s a lot of pessimism about India’s growth prospects right now, amplified by the sheer amount of geopolitical drama we’re living through. But if we aren’t hopeful that India will do better, then everything becomes moot.
This isn’t to say we don’t have real problems. We do. But every successful country has had to deal with its own share of thorny challenges along its development path. What matters is how we respond.</description></item><item><title>How India’s tax structure rewards growth over profits</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-indias-tax-structure-rewards-growth-over-profits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-indias-tax-structure-rewards-growth-over-profits/</guid><description>If you take money out of a business as dividends, the effective tax rate is 52% (25% corporate tax + 35.5% on personal income). Through capital gains, it’s just 14.95% (with cess).
Why does this matter? Here’s what you should know if you invest in IPOs.
If you’re an investor (especially a VC), the math is simple: reduce corporate tax by showing minimal profits or losses. Spend (Burn) on acquiring users, build a growth narrative, and then sell shares at a higher valuation while paying much lower tax.</description></item><item><title>Indian VC ecosystem has changed quite a bit in 15 years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-vc-ecosystem-has-changed-quite-a-bit-in-15-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-vc-ecosystem-has-changed-quite-a-bit-in-15-years/</guid><description>The Indian VC ecosystem has changed quite a bit in 15 years. When we started Zerodha in 2010, &amp;ldquo;VC&amp;rdquo; was an exotic term, and there was barely any startup activity. The most popular VCs were dads, uncles and aunts.
Starting around 2010, we began seeing interest driven by India&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;opportunity size.&amp;rdquo; India&amp;rsquo;s population has done more to attract VC money than anything else 😛 &amp;ldquo;India has 120 crore people, and even if 1% buy X&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Backing The Good Doll - old-school rag dolls stitched by rural women artisans</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/backing-the-good-doll-old-school-rag-dolls-stitched-by-rural-women-artisans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/backing-the-good-doll-old-school-rag-dolls-stitched-by-rural-women-artisans/</guid><description>Three years ago, I came across a post from Suhas &amp;amp; Sunita. They had left their jobs, moved to the Nilgiris, and were working with rural women to build livelihoods through craft. We called up and offered to help. Back then, it was called Indian Yards.
Since then, they’ve pivoted to The good doll and are bringing back old-school rag dolls. The best part is that these dolls are sustainable and stitched by rural women artisans who now earn an income working from their homes, balancing family and livelihood.</description></item><item><title>SCRA rules clarified</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scra-rules-clarified/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scra-rules-clarified/</guid><description>Finally, after clarification of SCRA rules by Ministry of Finance and NSE, brokers can now invest their own funds without exchange approvals or restrictions.
This is huge for Rainmatter. We can now allocate more capital to support Indian startups directly from the brokerage entity.</description></item><item><title>How Amwoodo’s bamboo revolution is driving rural prosperity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-amwoodos-bamboo-revolution-is-driving-rural-prosperity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-amwoodos-bamboo-revolution-is-driving-rural-prosperity/</guid><description>3x increase in rural incomes (~Rs 10,000 to ~Rs 30,000). 1200 farmers and artisans are earning much more. 11 lakh bamboo trees planted. 384 metric tons of plastic were kept out of landfills. 312232 metric tons of CO2 offset.
The last few years of partnering Amwoodo and Agni Mitra have been special. And yeah, the business is for profit and quite profitable.
I really hope these numbers keep increasing as the business grows and has to deal with other pressures and competing priorities.</description></item><item><title>What’s the secret to startup success?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/whats-the-secret-to-startup-success/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/whats-the-secret-to-startup-success/</guid><description>What is critical for the success of a startup - founders&amp;rsquo; skills or the macros?
I think it&amp;rsquo;s a bit of both. You could be a great founder with excellent execution skills but still struggle in an unfavorable macro environment. Or, you could be an average founder benefiting from the economic momentum of your country and sector.
Every time I think about this, I realize how fortunate we have been in terms of macros, both as a country and through government initiatives.</description></item><item><title>Corporate growth could be hitting a plateau</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/corporate-growth-could-be-hitting-a-plateau/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/corporate-growth-could-be-hitting-a-plateau/</guid><description>Corporate growth, in both the public and private markets, seems to be plateauing across most sectors. Even in the private markets, in most cases, valuations in the earlier funding rounds were already far over the fundamental value or expected growth of startups, which is why there&amp;rsquo;s hardly any news about funding for later-stage startups.
Read more on the topic by Markets by Zerodha</description></item><item><title>Celebrating India's first national space day 🇮🇳</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/celebrating-indias-first-national-space-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/celebrating-indias-first-national-space-day/</guid><description>Today is the first National Space Day 🇮🇳
It&amp;rsquo;s a matter of pride that we have many amazing homegrown space startups, like @AgnikulCosmos and @GalaxEye, both from the @Rainmatterin portfolio.
Agnikul recently tested the world’s first 3D-printed rocket engine and is aiming to launch a satellite by 2025.
Considering the cutting-edge research and technology needed, spacetech startups, more than other startups, need patient capital. So here&amp;rsquo;s hoping we&amp;rsquo;ll have more homegrown spacetech startups that will make us proud.</description></item><item><title>Startup Mahakumbh</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/startup-mahakumbh/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/startup-mahakumbh/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s great to see the Indian startup ecosystem go from strength to strength. Events like Startup Mahakumbh, that showcase homegrown startups building for India and the world are a sign of how far we&amp;rsquo;ve come.</description></item><item><title>Growing locally with India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/growing-locally-within-india/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/growing-locally-within-india/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve said this earlier: for India to grow inclusively, wealth has to be created locally. Today, much of the success of homegrown startups goes to investors outside India.
Staying in India and incorporating at home also saves the future hassle of paying huge taxes to flip back. Also, the growing local pools of capital, ever-improving regulations, and the growth of IPO markets have made India a much more attractive destination than it ever was.</description></item><item><title>A few thoughts on this National Startup Day</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-this-national-startup-day/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-this-national-startup-day/</guid><description>Today is National Startup Day, which was started in 2016 to highlight the contribution of startups to India&amp;rsquo;s economic growth.
We&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way as a country in recognizing and celebrating the success and contribution of entrepreneurs who, in turn, have inspired more people to startup. For a long time, almost everyone in my life told me to get a real job when I was trading and running a business until Zerodha became popular.</description></item><item><title>Rethinking Investment Strategies for startups and joining the NSAC</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rethinking-investment-strategies-for-startups-and-joining-the-nsac/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rethinking-investment-strategies-for-startups-and-joining-the-nsac/</guid><description>More Indians today than ever before are aspiring to be entrepreneurs thanks to Government initiatives &amp;amp; messaging, the media coverage of the startup ecosystem, founder success stories, &amp;amp; more.
The one thing we need to work on as a nation is to unlock domestic capital for startups/MSMEs. Reduce the dependence on foreign capital and get Indians to back Indian startups.
It is maybe time for newer products or vehicles that can be used by accredited investors or those who can take higher risks to be able to invest in equity or debt in startups/MSMEs.</description></item><item><title>Indian startups will do well despite the negativity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-startups-will-do-well-despite-the-negativity/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-startups-will-do-well-despite-the-negativity/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Investment is the discipline of relative selection” - Sid Cottle.
Indian startups will most likely continue to attract foreign capital even if all the news might make it seem otherwise. This is mainly because we are the fastest-growing country in the world, and investing is about selecting the best from all the existing options. It is a relative decision, and global investors have to invest.
By the way, anecdotally talking to some international investors, Indian startups seem to be faring better in the last year or so, where the focus has been more on reducing burn &amp;amp; getting on the path to profitability.</description></item><item><title>Empowering women to join the workforce is the easiest way to increase economic growth</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/empowering-women-to-join-the-workforce-is-the-easiest-way-to-increase-economic-growth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/empowering-women-to-join-the-workforce-is-the-easiest-way-to-increase-economic-growth/</guid><description>Empowering women to join the workforce is an obvious way to increase our economic growth. Our female labor force participation rate is among the lowest in the world. One thing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make sense of is why our female labor force participation (FLFP), which was in the ~30% range in the 90s, fell to 20% and rose to 24%. We have been discussing this topic on the Rainmatter Grove and and Ashutosh from IndiaDataHub shared something interesting:</description></item><item><title>You need both physical and digital presence to reach more customers in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/you-need-both-physical-and-digital-presence-to-reach-more-customers-in-india/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/you-need-both-physical-and-digital-presence-to-reach-more-customers-in-india/</guid><description>HDFC Bank opening 4 new branches daily last year is phenomenal.
As counterintuitive as it sounds, I think the real competition for most Fintechs in India is the branches of all banks. Each bank branch sells everything from loans, investments, insurance, and more.
Other than small-value consumer loans &amp;amp; payments, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it is possible to expand the market or increase market share beyond a certain point by being digital only.</description></item><item><title>India is many countries in one</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-is-many-countries-in-one/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-is-many-countries-in-one/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;India has 140 crore people, and if X% can become customers because of Y% in a developed country,&amp;rdquo; is a dangerous line of thinking for founders and investors.
While building for up to 3% of English-speaking affluent Indians is easier, it&amp;rsquo;s much harder and complex beyond that. Something we are pondering at Zerodha as well.
I guess the right way to think of this is, India is many countries in one.</description></item><item><title>Encouraging wealthy Indian investors to invest in Indian entrepreneurs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/encouraging-wealthy-indian-investors-to-invest-in-indian-entrepreneurs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/encouraging-wealthy-indian-investors-to-invest-in-indian-entrepreneurs/</guid><description>UK offers 50% tax relief &amp;amp; capital gains exemption for startup investments. This seems a great way to incentivize wealthy to invest in startups. We maybe need similar schemes to reduce our dependency on foreign VCs &amp;amp; better use our local wealth stuck in Gold, Real estate &amp;amp; FDs.
The biggest problem to solve in India is to spread wealth inclusively &amp;amp; not just in the top 1%.
This is possible only when wealth creation can be captured by a large subset of Indians when Indian businesses do well.</description></item></channel></rss>