<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>startups on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/startups/</link><description>Recent content in startups on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/startups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Empowering women to join the workforce is the easiest way to increase economic growth</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/empowering-women-to-join-the-workforce-is-the-easiest-way-to-increase-economic-growth/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/empowering-women-to-join-the-workforce-is-the-easiest-way-to-increase-economic-growth/</guid><description>Empowering women to join the workforce is an obvious way to increase our economic growth. Our female labor force participation rate is among the lowest in the world. One thing I couldn&amp;rsquo;t make sense of is why our female labor force participation (FLFP), which was in the ~30% range in the 90s, fell to 20% and rose to 24%. We have been discussing this topic on the Rainmatter Grove and and Ashutosh from IndiaDataHub shared something interesting:</description></item><item><title>You need both physical and digital presence to reach more customers in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/you-need-both-physical-and-digital-presence-to-reach-more-customers-in-india/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/you-need-both-physical-and-digital-presence-to-reach-more-customers-in-india/</guid><description>HDFC Bank opening 4 new branches daily last year is phenomenal.
As counterintuitive as it sounds, I think the real competition for most Fintechs in India is the branches of all banks. Each bank branch sells everything from loans, investments, insurance, and more.
Other than small-value consumer loans &amp;amp; payments, I don&amp;rsquo;t think it is possible to expand the market or increase market share beyond a certain point by being digital only.</description></item><item><title>India is many countries in one</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-is-many-countries-in-one/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-is-many-countries-in-one/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;India has 140 crore people, and if X% can become customers because of Y% in a developed country,&amp;rdquo; is a dangerous line of thinking for founders and investors.
While building for up to 3% of English-speaking affluent Indians is easier, it&amp;rsquo;s much harder and complex beyond that. Something we are pondering at Zerodha as well.
I guess the right way to think of this is, India is many countries in one.</description></item><item><title>Encouraging wealthy Indian investors to invest in Indian entrepreneurs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/encouraging-wealthy-indian-investors-to-invest-in-indian-entrepreneurs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/encouraging-wealthy-indian-investors-to-invest-in-indian-entrepreneurs/</guid><description>UK offers 50% tax relief &amp;amp; capital gains exemption for startup investments. This seems a great way to incentivize wealthy to invest in startups. We maybe need similar schemes to reduce our dependency on foreign VCs &amp;amp; better use our local wealth stuck in Gold, Real estate &amp;amp; FDs.
The biggest problem to solve in India is to spread wealth inclusively &amp;amp; not just in the top 1%.
This is possible only when wealth creation can be captured by a large subset of Indians when Indian businesses do well.</description></item><item><title>Significance of MSMEs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-significance-of-msmes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-significance-of-msmes/</guid><description>I was at an amazing Micro, Small, &amp;amp; Medium enterprises (MSME) event hosted by Rajiv Talreja. One lesson I had to share. Today&amp;rsquo;s world is about the fast beating the slow, not the big beating the small like in the past. So being small &amp;amp; hence fast is an edge, not a disadvantage.
While Zerodha might seem large, we are still an MSME at heart. MSMEs today face many challenges like access to capital, credit etc.</description></item><item><title>Potential impact of artificial intelligence (AI) on mankind and capitalism.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/potential-impact-of-artificial-intelligence-on-mankind-and-capitalism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/potential-impact-of-artificial-intelligence-on-mankind-and-capitalism/</guid><description>It took us ~30 mins to integrate commoditized ChatGPT, see tangible benefits, and realize that more than 20% of jobs could be automated. Now, imagine what more intelligent tools could lead to?
Dr K on what artificial intelligence (AI) could mean for capitalism and humanity</description></item><item><title>The dark side of liquidation preferences</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-dark-side-of-liquidation-preferences/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-dark-side-of-liquidation-preferences/</guid><description>I think the number of founders and leaders, especially at late-stage startups quitting will only increase, making it harder for businesses to survive this funding winter. This is because of liquidation preferences &amp;amp; the disconnect between valuations and business fundamentals.
A liquidation preference allows investors to recover their investment before anyone else. This is how all startups raise money. Nobody thinks of it as a loan, but it is similar. The more money founders raise, the harder it is for them and their teams to see equity upside.</description></item><item><title>The best example of an Indian fintech product made for India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-example-of-an-indian-fintech-product-made-for-india/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-example-of-an-indian-fintech-product-made-for-india/</guid><description>India is unique. Copy-pasting models from the US, etc, has hardly worked. Paytm&amp;rsquo;s speaker for Indian vendors that reads out payments is one of the best examples of a product made specifically for the Indian context by an Indian fintech.</description></item><item><title>Lessons from the Silicon Valley Bank (SVB) collapse</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/lessons-from-the-svb-bank-collapse/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/lessons-from-the-svb-bank-collapse/</guid><description>It is ridiculous how many things can go wrong when running a business. Everything from rapid change to market sentiment to waking up one day and being unable to access money in the bank, like with SVB.
I think an underrated skill set for running a business is being pessimistic. Consider everything a risk and do everything you can to mitigate it. Every business will be exposed to a black swan event at some point; the idea is to survive those.</description></item><item><title>The downside of chasing higher valuations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-downside-of-chasing-valuations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-downside-of-chasing-valuations/</guid><description>We celebrate valuations, but the more I speak to founders, the more I&amp;rsquo;m convinced high valuations are detrimental. Higher valuations are mostly a result of overstating the size of the opportunity. Of course, there are outliers, but they are the exception, not the rule. Getting investors on board is like getting married: setting wrong expectations before the marriage leads to disappointments and conflicts and doesn’t usually end well. It hurts to see businesses that would&amp;rsquo;ve otherwise done well struggling because they raised money at unrealistic valuations.</description></item><item><title>Throwing money at problems creates more problems</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/throwing-money-at-problems-creates-more-problems/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/throwing-money-at-problems-creates-more-problems/</guid><description>One counterintuitive lesson I learned on the Zerodha journey, thanks to Kailash, was that throwing people and money at problems won&amp;rsquo;t solve them. They will create more, and we&amp;rsquo;re seeing this around the world now. #MCFintechConclave with Chandra R. Srikanth</description></item><item><title>The biggest asset for B2C startups</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-biggest-asset-for-b2c-startups/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-biggest-asset-for-b2c-startups/</guid><description>Startups spend a lot of effort &amp;amp; money on marketing. But I think B2C startups globally that have IPO&amp;rsquo;d in the last few years have ignored one of their biggest assets—an opportunity to turn millions of retail shareholders with influence on social media into brand ambassadors.
From the time a founder raises money from VCs and PE, they are primed to think about maximizing valuations. This means building a narrative that can price in the best-case outcome for the business.</description></item><item><title>The dark side of setting goals</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-dark-side-of-setting-goals/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-dark-side-of-setting-goals/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve never set goals at Zerodha, be it user growth, revenues, or profits. The idea has been to get up every day, improve, &amp;amp; do what&amp;rsquo;s right for users, knowing that we&amp;rsquo;ll get to wherever we have to get to. The journey is a lot more fun this way.
In any case, the range of outcomes in business is mostly driven by luck and being at the right place at the right time.</description></item><item><title>Why everyone should pay more attention to India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-everyone-should-pay-more-attention-to-india/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-everyone-should-pay-more-attention-to-india/</guid><description>Whenever students ask me for advice, I say, stay in India. Not just because we need to avoid the brain drain or that there&amp;rsquo;s an obligation to the country, but because India will most likely have the best opportunities in future.
@srajagopalan explains👇
Why is this a smart thing to do?
&amp;ldquo;Globally, one in five people below 25 is from India. 47% of Indians, about 650 million, are below the age of 25.</description></item><item><title>Slow growth vs debt fuelled fast growth</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/slow-growth-vs-debt-fuelled-fast-growth/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/slow-growth-vs-debt-fuelled-fast-growth/</guid><description>A saving mindset is what will help us in times like now when countries that have borrowed heavily are getting screwed? In a world of rising interest rates, this will probably get much worse before it gets better for them.
Isn&amp;rsquo;t slow &amp;amp; steady growth much better (like compounding in investing) than debt-fuelled explosive growth where people borrow to buy depreciating assets? Neither good for customers nor for businesses in the long run.</description></item><item><title>Silver lining from startups excesses</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/silver-lining-from-startups-excesses/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/silver-lining-from-startups-excesses/</guid><description>The silver lining of the startup world&amp;rsquo;s excesses is that, for the first time in India, there are so many aspiring to be entrepreneurs. Almost like how people want IIT, IIM, Civil Services, etc. More people building for India, in India is the only way we can get to $5 trillion+.</description></item><item><title>On web3 and buzzwords</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-web3-and-buzzwords/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-web3-and-buzzwords/</guid><description>Dr K (Kailash) on web3 and buzzwords
&amp;ldquo;We need to put human-first thinking way above technology-first thinking lest we develop a dangerous tunnel vision that reduces human problems into mere technology features &amp;amp; transactions, reduce humans to mere numbers.&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Spending on own brand keyword ads</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/spending-on-own-brand-keyword-ads/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/spending-on-own-brand-keyword-ads/</guid><description>The easiest way for startups &amp;amp; businesses to burn is by advertising on their own brand keywords to stop competitors from doing so. Hopefully, this high court order will put an end to what feels like a regressive tax by big tech, especially on SMEs.
Years ago, when our competitors first ran ads against the &amp;ldquo;Zerodha&amp;rdquo; keyword, we got influenced to run ads as well. We stopped quickly when we realized that it made no difference to our traffic &amp;amp; the ad was essentially cannibalizing our organic traffic while costing us money.</description></item><item><title>How large is the Indian market for B2C tech businesses and fintechs by revenue potential?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-large-is-the-indian-market-for-b2c-tech-businesses-and-fintechs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-large-is-the-indian-market-for-b2c-tech-businesses-and-fintechs/</guid><description>How large is the Indian market for B2C tech businesses in terms of users who can generate revenue? Maybe 15 crores max! Here&amp;rsquo;s why, with Fintech as a reference, since some data is available. I guess it is important to know this, so we can all be rationally optimistic.
I get puzzled whenever someone says India has 140cr people &amp;amp; only 9cr demat accounts (6% of the population), &amp;amp; this can grow to 40 crores (25% as in developed nations) over the next few years.</description></item><item><title>The end of growth at any cost?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-end-of-growth-at-any-cost/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-end-of-growth-at-any-cost/</guid><description>The sharp fall in the stock prices of high growth tech companies across the globe is getting crazy, feels like the dot-com boom. India has weathered the storm mostly because not many such companies are listed &amp;amp; many private ones raised a lot of money last year.
It is ridiculous how quickly the expectations changed from growth at all costs to generating free cash flows to survive the next 2 to 3 years since raising funds might be tougher.</description></item><item><title>Why are billions being invested into Indian non-profitable startups by VCs?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-are-billions-being-invested-into-indian-startups-by-vs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-are-billions-being-invested-into-indian-startups-by-vs/</guid><description>Why are billions being invested into Indian non-profitable startups by VCs when it is well known that today the cost of acquisition (CAC) is much higher than the lifetime value (LTV) of customers in most B2C businesses? They have two hypotheses:
India is at around $2K per capita GDP, and the bet is that it will be at $4K in a few years from now. $4K is when the magic is supposed to happen, as it did in China.</description></item><item><title>Is fractional share investing possible in India?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-fractional-investing-possible-in-india/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-fractional-investing-possible-in-india/</guid><description>Fractional investing or the ability to invest say $10 in Amazon at $3200 has been the biggest reason for stock market participation to go up in the US. We applied under SEBI regulatory sandbox to launch the same in India. Our learnings by Somnath Mukherjee. We made that application with a startup that had reached out to us Rainmatterin and was rejected.
In the US, stocks bought by customers are held in the street name of the broker, unlike in India, where stocks are held in a customer’s beneficiary account with a depository.</description></item><item><title>How is Zerodha profitable when most new-age startups aren't?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-is-zerodha-profitable-when-most-new-age-startups-arent/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-is-zerodha-profitable-when-most-new-age-startups-arent/</guid><description>We get asked often how is Zerodha profitable when most new-age companies aren&amp;rsquo;t. The answer is simple: our cost of acquisition (CAC) is 0. If we had to spend heavily, we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be. CAC at 0 is a philosophical decision, a bit like Dr K on hiring &amp;amp; building products. Philosophical because we aren&amp;rsquo;t in a hurry to grow or get to X valuation. We believe that if you can build products with the customers&amp;rsquo; best interests at heart and enjoy the journey as a team, we&amp;rsquo;ll continue to do okay.</description></item><item><title>Can brokerage go to 0 in India?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/can-brokerage-go-to-0-in-india/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/can-brokerage-go-to-0-in-india/</guid><description>Many people ask me if brokerage rates can go to zero like in the US, and why not flat monthly brokerage plans with unlimited trades. I don&amp;rsquo;t think so. I think, if anything, brokerage rates will go up in the future. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.
Firstly, in the US, brokers can earn in ways that SEBI rightly doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow here: Payment for order flow: selling customer orders to HFT firms. Securities lending: Unlike India, stocks are held in the street name or in the name of brokers—they can lend them to earn.</description></item><item><title>Tax arbitrage between dividends and selling a stake and startup profitability</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/tax-arbitrage-between-dividends-and-selling-stake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/tax-arbitrage-between-dividends-and-selling-stake/</guid><description>Can the tax arbitrage that exists between earning through dividends(~52%) vs earning through selling a stake (~24%) be the reason why most new-age businesses are not profitable? I think so. Money is like a river, it flows where the conditions are conducive to its flow.
The Govt capping the surcharge on LTCG when investing in unlisted companies to encourage investments in startups in the budget is a welcome move. But maybe the tax arbitrage shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be so large that everyone just focuses on valuations and not on profits &amp;amp; sustainability.</description></item><item><title>Private market valautions are weird</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/private-market-valuations-are-weird/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/private-market-valuations-are-weird/</guid><description>While listed high growth, yet to be profitable startups are seeing sharp drops, private market valuations are somehow still holding up. Weird times we live in. Btw if there was a way to short private companies, I think there are a few pair trades—shorting private &amp;amp; buying listed.</description></item><item><title>Lower volatility long term growth vs maximum short term gain</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/long-term-gain-vs-short-term-gain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/long-term-gain-vs-short-term-gain/</guid><description>The sharp drops in stock prices of listed new-age tech companies across the world is quite scary. If history is a guide, only a small % of them will maybe bounce back. Companies when projecting growth should maybe prioritize lower volatility long term vs max short term gain.
The networth of the core teams in most new-age businesses is tied to ESOPs &amp;amp; hence valuations. Most, including the founders, suffer from anchoring bias.</description></item><item><title>Building for India but incorporating outside India is a disturbing trend</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/startups-incorporating-outside-india/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/startups-incorporating-outside-india/</guid><description>New startups building for India but incorporating outside India is a disturbing trend. While even now startups are largely funded by foreign VCs, there is wealth creation in India through Founders, Angels, &amp;amp; ESOPs. Also, the taxes on realized capital gains benefit India.
Since most startups now prioritize growth over profits, there&amp;rsquo;s typically no income tax in India. Now if all wealth creation and capital gains are also captured outside, it is like that dialogue from Swades - &amp;ldquo;Apni chaukhat ka diya, giving light to neighbour&amp;rsquo;s house&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>A must watch interview of Rakesh Jhunjhunwala</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/must-watch-interview-of-rakesh-jhunjhunwala/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/must-watch-interview-of-rakesh-jhunjhunwala/</guid><description>This RJ chat is a must-watch
The common thing among successful traders &amp;amp; entrepreneurs is to always think in terms of risk to reward. They take a trade—buy a stock or take a business bet—only if they&amp;rsquo;ve made peace with the worst possible outcome
An understanding that leverage (debt) is merciless &amp;amp; a double-edged sword. If at all they need to use leverage, it&amp;rsquo;s only a small portion of their networth.</description></item><item><title>Why are we valuing ourselves at just $2 Billion</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-are-we-valuing-zerodha-at-2-billion/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-are-we-valuing-zerodha-at-2-billion/</guid><description>The only reason why we do a valuation exercise at Zerodha every year is for our ESOP buyback. I keep getting asked why are we valuing ourselves at just $2Billion currently when smaller players are raising money at far higher valuations. Here is why we&amp;rsquo;re conservative.
Some background: We don&amp;rsquo;t promise ESOPs for anyone on our team. Frankly, we never thought we were building something that could become so valuable. So we never thought of ESOPs.</description></item><item><title>On "Powered by AI / ML" marketing</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-powered-by-ai-ml-marketing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-powered-by-ai-ml-marketing/</guid><description>The note yesterday on &amp;ldquo;Powered by AI&amp;rdquo; hype got surprising amounts of attention. Here is a detailed post by Dr K that draws parallels between AI and Rumali roti when it comes to marketing hype.</description></item><item><title>The moats for banks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-moat-for-banks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-moat-for-banks/</guid><description>The moat banks have today is that it is very very tough to become a bank. Yeah, you can be a Small Finance Bank, Payments Bank, Neo Bank, but you can never compete with a full-fledged bank due to all the restrictions. But looks like there is hope that the future is different.</description></item><item><title>Right place, right time</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/right-place-right-time/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/right-place-right-time/</guid><description>And Right place, Right time. If startups IPO, &amp;amp; create wealth for Indian retail investors in long run, that will be beautiful. For this, I guess the growth has to be sustainable, for which there has to be a shift to underselling &amp;amp; overdelivering as a listed business.</description></item><item><title>Scaling with common sense</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scaling-with-commonsense/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scaling-with-commonsense/</guid><description>If there was ever a person who&amp;rsquo;s had a strong influence on me, it&amp;rsquo;s K (Kailash), the secret sauce behind Zerodha. He just published this post which is more than just tech, a must-read for anyone building or aspiring to build a business or a product.</description></item><item><title>The risk for high growth B2C tech IPOs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/high-growth-tech-ipos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/high-growth-tech-ipos/</guid><description>The risk with all the high growth B2C tech IPOs coming up is growth plateauing. Growth is usually a function of agility &amp;amp; product bets. Since these companies take more bets &amp;amp; are more agile &amp;amp; aggressive than traditional businesses, they grow faster (Zerodha as well).
The question then, will the ability of these companies to be agile (reason for growth) reduce because of all the scrutiny that comes by being publicly listed?</description></item><item><title>Why doesn't Zerodha advertise?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-doesnt-zerodha-advertise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-doesnt-zerodha-advertise/</guid><description>One thing I get asked the most and I’ve tweeted about this numerous times is that why don’t we advertise. Firstly I&amp;rsquo;d shared this sometime back.
Unlike buying a mobile phone or ordering a pizza, you don&amp;rsquo;t invest in stocks &amp;amp; MFs impulsively. Most often than not, we invest because of greed or because of our friends. And regulations don&amp;rsquo;t allow you to advertise greed.
Ads do help you create visibility and build credibility - two really important things in the business of money, especially the first few years.</description></item><item><title>Right now is probably the stupidest time for fintech firms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-stupidest-time-to-be-raising-money/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-stupidest-time-to-be-raising-money/</guid><description>Right now, is probably the stupidest time for fintech firms like @zerodhaonline to be raising money. It is quite crazy the number of folks reaching out &amp;amp; the different deals. We might regret it in the future, but we are not raising &amp;amp; here are the counterintuitive reasons why.
We don’t need the money, so there’s no point in raising money just because someone is ready to give it to you.</description></item><item><title>Market size estimates</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/maket-size-estimates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/maket-size-estimates/</guid><description>Market size estimate (Revenue), from the two reports that I just read. Stockbroking: ~$3billion according to ICRA. Gold loan: ~$162billion according to MorningContext.</description></item><item><title>Making taxes easy with Vishvajit Sonagara of Quicko</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-taxes-easy-with-vishvajit-sonagara-of-quicko/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-taxes-easy-with-vishvajit-sonagara-of-quicko/</guid><description>A misconception among traders is that you need to file ITR only if you make a profit. Many also don&amp;rsquo;t file since it&amp;rsquo;s quite complex, but Quicko has simplified it drastically. In our new Rainmatter podcast I talk to Vishvajit on their journey.</description></item><item><title>Spending on brand name keywords</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/should-you-spend-on-brand-name-keywords/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/should-you-spend-on-brand-name-keywords/</guid><description>The only time we ran Google ads was when our competition ran ads when people searched for Zerodha. We ran ads against &amp;ldquo;zerodha(.)competition(.)com&amp;rdquo;. Our lamest expenditure to date. Hoping this order is a precedent &amp;amp; helps startups save on unnecessary costs</description></item><item><title>Being at the right place at right time and surviving</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/right-place-right-time-survival/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/right-place-right-time-survival/</guid><description>Right place right timeSmiling face with open mouthBut damn it&amp;rsquo;s tough to survive &amp;amp; be there when it matters. Zerodha probably started when I started trading 15 years before 2010. It&amp;rsquo;s been 25 years of ups &amp;amp; many downs, almost gave up many times. If it works out you are called passionate, if not foolish.</description></item><item><title>Rising financial awareness among Indians</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</guid><description>Financial awareness about the importance of saving and investing in India is increasing at the fastest rate ever, especially among millennials. Of course, stock markets doing well and lower bank FD rates are helping. But there are also a few structural changes afoot here. Historically financial products have been sold hard &amp;amp; mostly in person. Products mostly sold based on promises of high returns (sales pitches in person leave no audit trail).</description></item><item><title>Shorting and Indian Capital Markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</guid><description>Can retail traders are cause a “short squeeze” in India like they did in stocks like GameStop and AMC entertainment in the US? It cannot, and I explain why in this post. Join the discussion here.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-rainmatter-foundation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-rainmatter-foundation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Why advertising doesn't work</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-advertising-doesnt-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-advertising-doesnt-work/</guid><description>https://freakonomics.com/podcast/advertising-part-2/ This is a great listen from Freakonomics on whether advertising works. The reason we could bootstrap was that we never spent on ads. With no ads, a business is forced to constantly think &amp;amp; do things to get customer love and organic growth. The only time we experimented with ads was for our brand keyword, show our website if you search &amp;ldquo;Zerodha&amp;rdquo;. We stopped immediately when we realized that it made no difference to the traffic and the ad was essentially cannibalizing our organic traffic while costing us money.</description></item><item><title>A product to get more Indians to save and invest</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</guid><description>To get the next 10 crore Indians, the traditional financial product might not work. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I think is needed to get these people to start saving and investing.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping vs Funding – a tax arbitrage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</guid><description>Promoters of businesses to professional investors, now chase “growth” and increase valuations to sell their stake in the business instead of trying to earn profits and taking the earnings out through dividends — to save on taxes and earn more efficiently.</description></item><item><title>Stock trading games &amp; copy trading platforms in India?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-trading-games-copy-trading-platforms-in/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-trading-games-copy-trading-platforms-in/</guid><description>My thoughts on copy-trading and social trading platforms and why they aren&amp;rsquo;t feasible in India right now.</description></item></channel></rss>