<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>startups on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/startups/</link><description>Recent content in startups on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/startups/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The risk for high growth B2C tech IPOs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/high-growth-tech-ipos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/high-growth-tech-ipos/</guid><description>The risk with all the high growth B2C tech IPOs coming up is growth plateauing. Growth is usually a function of agility &amp;amp; product bets. Since these companies take more bets &amp;amp; are more agile &amp;amp; aggressive than traditional businesses, they grow faster (Zerodha as well).
The question then, will the ability of these companies to be agile (reason for growth) reduce because of all the scrutiny that comes by being publicly listed?</description></item><item><title>Why doesn't Zerodha advertise?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-doesnt-zerodha-advertise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-doesnt-zerodha-advertise/</guid><description>One thing I get asked the most and I’ve tweeted about this numerous times is that why don’t we advertise. Firstly I&amp;rsquo;d shared this sometime back.
Unlike buying a mobile phone or ordering a pizza, you don&amp;rsquo;t invest in stocks &amp;amp; MFs impulsively. Most often than not, we invest because of greed or because of our friends. And regulations don&amp;rsquo;t allow you to advertise greed.
Ads do help you create visibility and build credibility - two really important things in the business of money, especially the first few years.</description></item><item><title>Market size estimates</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/maket-size-estimates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/maket-size-estimates/</guid><description>Market size estimate (Revenue), from the two reports that I just read. Stockbroking: ~$3billion according to ICRA. Gold loan: ~$162billion according to MorningContext.</description></item><item><title>Making taxes easy with Vishvajit Sonagara of Quicko</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-taxes-easy-with-vishvajit-sonagara-of-quicko/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-taxes-easy-with-vishvajit-sonagara-of-quicko/</guid><description>A misconception among traders is that you need to file ITR only if you make a profit. Many also don&amp;rsquo;t file since it&amp;rsquo;s quite complex, but Quicko has simplified it drastically. In our new Rainmatter podcast I talk to Vishvajit on their journey.</description></item><item><title>Spending on brand name keywords</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/should-you-spend-on-brand-name-keywords/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/should-you-spend-on-brand-name-keywords/</guid><description>The only time we ran Google ads was when our competition ran ads when people searched for Zerodha. We ran ads against &amp;ldquo;zerodha(.)competition(.)com&amp;rdquo;. Our lamest expenditure to date. Hoping this order is a precedent &amp;amp; helps startups save on unnecessary costs</description></item><item><title>Being at the right place at right time and surviving</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/right-place-right-time-survival/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/right-place-right-time-survival/</guid><description>Right place right timeSmiling face with open mouthBut damn it&amp;rsquo;s tough to survive &amp;amp; be there when it matters. Zerodha probably started when I started trading 15 years before 2010. It&amp;rsquo;s been 25 years of ups &amp;amp; many downs, almost gave up many times. If it works out you are called passionate, if not foolish.</description></item><item><title>Rising financial awareness among Indians</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</guid><description>Financial awareness about the importance of saving and investing in India is increasing at the fastest rate ever, especially among millennials. Of course, stock markets doing well and lower bank FD rates are helping. But there are also a few structural changes afoot here. Historically financial products have been sold hard &amp;amp; mostly in person. Products mostly sold based on promises of high returns (sales pitches in person leave no audit trail).</description></item><item><title>Shorting and Indian Capital Markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</guid><description>Can retail traders are cause a “short squeeze” in India like they did in stocks like GameStop and AMC entertainment in the US? It cannot, and I explain why in this post. Join the discussion here.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-rainmatter-foundation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-rainmatter-foundation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Why advertising doesn't work</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-advertising-doesnt-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-advertising-doesnt-work/</guid><description>https://freakonomics.com/podcast/advertising-part-2/ This is a great listen from Freakonomics on whether advertising works. The reason we could bootstrap was that we never spent on ads. With no ads, a business is forced to constantly think &amp;amp; do things to get customer love and organic growth. The only time we experimented with ads was for our brand keyword, show our website if you search &amp;ldquo;Zerodha&amp;rdquo;. We stopped immediately when we realized that it made no difference to the traffic and the ad was essentially cannibalizing our organic traffic while costing us money.</description></item><item><title>A product to get more Indians to save and invest</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</guid><description>To get the next 10 crore Indians, the traditional financial product might not work. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I think is needed to get these people to start saving and investing.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping vs Funding – a tax arbitrage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</guid><description>Promoters of businesses to professional investors, now chase “growth” and increase valuations to sell their stake in the business instead of trying to earn profits and taking the earnings out through dividends — to save on taxes and earn more efficiently.</description></item><item><title>Stock trading games &amp; copy trading platforms in India?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-trading-games-copy-trading-platforms-in/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-trading-games-copy-trading-platforms-in/</guid><description>My thoughts on copy-trading and social trading platforms and why they aren&amp;rsquo;t feasible in India right now.</description></item></channel></rss>