<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>trading on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/trading/</link><description>Recent content in trading on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/trading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why encouraging less trading leads to better outcomes for everyone</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-encouraging-less-trading-leads-to-better-outcomes-for-everyone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-encouraging-less-trading-leads-to-better-outcomes-for-everyone/</guid><description>As a % of client funds, our brokerage revenue is 20-25% of our listed peers. That means our clients trade a lot less (75% lesser) as a proportion of their capital.
Here&amp;rsquo;s something counterintuitive but true: With few exceptions, the more frequently people trade, the lower their odds of being profitable. More activity doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean better returns; it usually means a higher chance of blowing out your account.
So it&amp;rsquo;s actually in a platform&amp;rsquo;s best interest to get customers to trade less, not more.</description></item><item><title>The growing risks of trading crypto derivatives without clear rules</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-growing-risks-of-trading-crypto-derivatives-without-clear-rules/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-growing-risks-of-trading-crypto-derivatives-without-clear-rules/</guid><description>Crypto derivative exchanges exist in regulatory limbo. A bit like Schrödinger&amp;rsquo;s cat—neither fully regulated nor unregulated. This ambiguity is being exploited in dangerous ways. By the way, I am not referring to the actual buying and selling of Cryptocurrency.
The first risk with unregulated platforms is, of course, that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing you can do if something goes wrong.
The other big problem with crypto F&amp;amp;O is that you have no idea who&amp;rsquo;s on the other side of your order.</description></item><item><title>Take break from trading using Kill Switch</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-break-from-trading-using-kill-switch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-break-from-trading-using-kill-switch/</guid><description>The other common trading mistake I have seen over and over again in all my years of being a trader and running a brokerage is over-trading and revenge trading.
Sometimes, the best trade is the one you don&amp;rsquo;t take.
This is why we launched Kill Switch. If you get the urge to keep trading, you can enable it, and you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to place trades for the rest of the day.</description></item><item><title>In The Money by Zerodha podcast with Tom Sosnoff</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/in-the-money-by-zerodha-podcast-with-tom-sosnoff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/in-the-money-by-zerodha-podcast-with-tom-sosnoff/</guid><description>Most traders know that you can&amp;rsquo;t predict the markets, but they trade as if they can. This has to be the most common and costly trading mistake of all. Goes to show the difference between knowing and doing.
Sandeep Rao (musandz) recently recorded a podcast with the great Tom Sosnoff, co-founder of Thinkorswim and tastytrade, on our new YouTube channel, and here&amp;rsquo;s what Tom said:
&amp;ldquo;It takes a long time to convince yourself to learn certain things—mostly because we all have big egos and our own ideas.</description></item><item><title>My take on weekly options and what could happen next</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-take-on-weekly-options-and-what-could-happen-next/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-take-on-weekly-options-and-what-could-happen-next/</guid><description>Many people have been asking me about my view on weekly options and whether they are going away. I am as clueless as everybody else. 😃
Having said that, I would not be surprised if they were banned completely, and/or if there is some product suitability framework that makes it harder for people to trade F&amp;amp;O.
By the way, as I&amp;rsquo;ve said numerous times before, regulatory risk is by far the biggest risk for brokers like us.</description></item><item><title>Bringing down STT in cash market and futures could rebalance market activity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bringing-down-stt-in-cash-market-and-futures-could-rebalance-market-activity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bringing-down-stt-in-cash-market-and-futures-could-rebalance-market-activity/</guid><description>Securities Transaction Tax (STT) is the biggest tax that traders pay, and it&amp;rsquo;s much higher than brokerage fees. At Zerodha, the STT we collect and pass on to the government is higher than the brokerage we earn.
Trading volumes are highly sensitive to the STT. The level of STT also affects whether traders trade more in cash equities, futures, or options. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of concern that Indian options volumes have exploded; I don&amp;rsquo;t think it would be a stretch to say that STT is a big factor in this.</description></item><item><title>Stanley Druckenmiller on position sizing</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stanley-druckenmiller-on-position-sizing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stanley-druckenmiller-on-position-sizing/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;Druckenmiller: What I actually learned is that position sizing is probably 70 to 80 per cent of the equation. It&amp;rsquo;s not just about being right or wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s about how much you make when you&amp;rsquo;re right.&amp;rdquo;
Link to the full video.</description></item><item><title>Why comparing India’s and US options volumes misses the point</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-comparing-indias-and-us-options-volumes-misses-the-point/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-comparing-indias-and-us-options-volumes-misses-the-point/</guid><description>It’s ridiculous to see people comparing options trading volumes in India and the US and claiming that we’re overleveraged. For starters, the comparison itself is flawed. People often look at the number of contracts traded, not the premiums or the actual value involved.
If anything, India is significantly less leveraged than the US, even taking into account the fact that our markets are 15–20 years behind theirs.
Consider this: in the US, the margin funding market (the equivalent of MTF in India) recently crossed $1 trillion.</description></item><item><title>Varsity Live session on options trading</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/varsity-live-session-on-options-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/varsity-live-session-on-options-trading/</guid><description>In the last 4-5 months, over 60,000 people have attended Varsity Live online classes in both English and Hindi on trading, investing, taxes, etc. :) It&amp;rsquo;s fully free and open to everyone. Each class is taught by a mentor, and it&amp;rsquo;s also hands-on. You learn by doing exercises instead of long, boring gyan sessions.
All of this is free, and you don&amp;rsquo;t have excuse to join those scammy paid seminars. 😉</description></item><item><title>Risk management is the real secret behind trading success</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-is-the-real-secret-behind-trading-success/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-is-the-real-secret-behind-trading-success/</guid><description>Interesting experiment by Elm Wealth: 118 finance students were given tomorrow’s WSJ front page 24 hours before the news broke. You’d expect easy profits. Instead, half lost money and 16% went completely bust.
It wasn’t because their predictions were wrong. They called market direction correctly 51.5% of the time. That’s better than chance.
The problem? Position sizing.
Many students bet huge portions of their portfolio on a single trade. Some used 20x, even 60x leverage.</description></item><item><title>What the Jane Street probe tells us about India’s market oversight</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-the-jane-street-probe-tells-us-about-indias-market-oversight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-the-jane-street-probe-tells-us-about-indias-market-oversight/</guid><description>You’ve got to hand it to SEBI for going after Jane Street. If the allegations are true, it’s blatant market manipulation.
The shocking part? They kept at it even after receiving warnings from the exchanges. Maybe this is what happens when you&amp;rsquo;re used to the lenient U.S. regulatory regime. Think about the structure of U.S. markets: dark pools, payment for order flow, and other loopholes that allow hedge funds to make billions off retail investors.</description></item><item><title>Indian markets look sane compared to the frenzy in the US</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-markets-look-sane-compared-to-the-frenzy-in-the-us/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-markets-look-sane-compared-to-the-frenzy-in-the-us/</guid><description>Despite all the discussions about the Indian derivative turnover, we are barely 25% of US premiums.
Btw, these numbers don&amp;rsquo;t give you a full picture of the crazy levels of gambling and speculation in the US. Outside the exchange-traded derivatives, people can gamble on leveraged ETFs (these are massive), crypto, prediction markets like Polymarket, sports betting and other things.
When you look at what&amp;rsquo;s happening in the US and then look at India, our markets look so sane.</description></item><item><title>Are Tier 2 towns really driving trading growth?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/are-tier-2-towns-really-driving-trading-growth/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/are-tier-2-towns-really-driving-trading-growth/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of talk about a huge influx of traders from Tier 2 and 3 towns. This data may be a little misleading. Let me explain.
If one examines trading activity by looking at users&amp;rsquo; addresses as per their KYC, they&amp;rsquo;ll see many users from Tier 2 and 3 towns.
However, if you look at user activity by the IP addresses they use to log in, then the bulk of the activity comes from the top 20 cities.</description></item><item><title>Take a break from trading</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-a-break-from-trading/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-a-break-from-trading/</guid><description>Good time to follow this advice. Over the next 10 days, there are only 4 trading days. It’s not a bad idea to take a break from trading and recharge. Judging by what’s happening, you’re going to need it. 😬
&amp;ldquo;Trading profitably requires that you monitor the market moods and your psychological moods. When either one is not conducive to trading, it’s best to stand aside and wait for the situation to change.</description></item><item><title>First real market correction after COVID</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/first-real-market-correction-after-covid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/first-real-market-correction-after-covid/</guid><description>For investors who started investing after the pandemic, this is the first real market correction. Markets are cyclical, and given the way our markets went up from late 2020, this fall was inevitable. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how good the data is, but it seems like the number of investors stopping their SIPs has gone up. This is the wrong thing to do. What an SIP helps you do is to average your investments across different market cycles.</description></item><item><title>Markets are correcting</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/markets-are-correcting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/markets-are-correcting/</guid><description>The markets are finally correcting. Given that markets swing between extremes, they can fall more just like they rose to the peak.
I&amp;rsquo;ve no idea where the markets go from here, but I can tell you about the broking industry. We are seeing a massive drop in terms of both the number of traders and volumes.
Here is the trading volume chart. Across brokers, there&amp;rsquo;s a more than 30% drop in activity.</description></item><item><title>Sensibull explained</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sensibull-explained/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sensibull-explained/</guid><description>I first met Abid Hassan 12 years ago when he and his friends were building the first version of Sensibull. The original idea was to help traders and investors make better decisions, like helping them avoid going against the trend, being diversified, etc. In many ways, they were well ahead of their time. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to make the platform work while complying with regulations.
Abid went back to trading options for a trading desk, but I continued peddling him the idea that he should start something related to the markets.</description></item><item><title>Special live trading session on Budget day</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/special-live-trading-session-on-budget-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/special-live-trading-session-on-budget-day/</guid><description>So, the budget day is tomorrow, and yes, there is trading on a Saturday. Markets are bound to be volatile, so trade with caution.
If you are an active trader, I guess you should reduce trading size during event days. That is if you cannot stop yourself from trading.
By the way, Zerodha is probably the only broker which will allow you to do BTST (Buy today and sell tomorrow) trades on days of settlement holiday, like tomorrow.</description></item><item><title>India's trading hubs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-trading-hubs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-trading-hubs/</guid><description>Ahmedabad and Mumbai account for 80% of equity delivery trades. Let that sink in. Essentially, the real money is with Gujjus 😬
Btw, Gujarat accounts for just 8% of the total registered investors, and the share has been falling.</description></item><item><title>Impact of revision in Exchange Transaction Charges and STT</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-revision-in-exchange-transaction-charges-and-stt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-revision-in-exchange-transaction-charges-and-stt/</guid><description>Equity delivery will continue to be free at @zerodhaonline. As of now, we are not making any changes to our brokerage.
From today, Oct 1, 2024,
For options: STT increases to 0.1% from 0.0625%, and transaction charge decreases to 0.035% from 0.0495%.
This results in the cost of trades seeing a net increase of 0.02303% or Rs 2303 per crore of premium on the selling side on NSE and of 0.</description></item></channel></rss>