<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>trading on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/trading/</link><description>Recent content in trading on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/trading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Gamestop saga and lessons for retail investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</guid><description>In the Gamestop saga, the media has loved telling the story of how Retail made a lot of money from Hedge funds. The reality is entirely different, almost everyone apart from retail has probably made money or benefited from this.
Firstly, yes, a couple of Hedge funds were sitting on large losses on Gamestop shorts. Now that stock is at $50, the losses also would be a fraction, if the shorts still held.</description></item><item><title>Rising financial awareness among Indians</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</guid><description>Financial awareness about the importance of saving and investing in India is increasing at the fastest rate ever, especially among millennials. Of course, stock markets doing well and lower bank FD rates are helping. But there are also a few structural changes afoot here. Historically financial products have been sold hard &amp;amp; mostly in person. Products mostly sold based on promises of high returns (sales pitches in person leave no audit trail).</description></item><item><title>Shorting and Indian Capital Markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</guid><description>Can retail traders are cause a “short squeeze” in India like they did in stocks like GameStop and AMC entertainment in the US? It cannot, and I explain why in this post. Join the discussion here.</description></item><item><title>Is trading the markets gambling?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-trading-the-markets-gambling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-trading-the-markets-gambling/</guid><description>Is trading the markets gambling? I get asked often. My answer is that yes, you can gamble when trading, just like you can gamble with everything else in life.</description></item><item><title>A product to get more Indians to save and invest</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</guid><description>To get the next 10 crore Indians, the traditional financial product might not work. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I think is needed to get these people to start saving and investing.</description></item><item><title>Does Illiquidty like in private markets lead to good investor behavior?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-illiquidty-like-in-private-markets-lead-to/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-illiquidty-like-in-private-markets-lead-to/</guid><description>A question I have been asking institutional investors in both private and public markets is - if they could enter and exit their holdings at will like retail investors(which they cannot today), would they have actually sat through the ride of their best-performing holdings? The answer usually is no. As counterintuitive as it sounds, maybe the inability to easily enter/exit large public or illiquid private holdings forces fund managers to sit tight, which is also why they can outperform retail investors who are always trying to time the market.</description></item><item><title>Does technical analysis work?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-technical-analysis-work/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-technical-analysis-work/</guid><description>Am often asked if Technical Analysis actually works. Firstly, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing that just &amp;ldquo;works&amp;rdquo; in trading. But TA works well for retail as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t let you trade against the trend &amp;amp; defines stoploss every trade - main reasons for retail traders&amp;rsquo; losses.</description></item><item><title>Nudging people towards doing the right things</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-people-towards-doing-the-right-things/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-people-towards-doing-the-right-things/</guid><description>The penny stock Nudge introduced in March on Kite has helped us reduce penny stock trading volume significantly. It has given us hope that the bunch of new nudges we are working on will help our customers stay away from bad trading behavior.</description></item><item><title>Sitting on a profitable trade is harder than sitting on a loss making trade</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sitting-on-a-profitable-trade-is-harder-than-on-a/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sitting-on-a-profitable-trade-is-harder-than-on-a/</guid><description>Contrary to what most people think, it is much tougher to sit on a profitable trade vs loss-making. All decent traders have a defined stop to handle losing trades. When on profit, we all know we have to let our winners run, but all our biases constantly push us to book profits.</description></item><item><title>What does it take to win at trading?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</guid><description>Learnings from interactions with thousands of traders and my own successes and failures.</description></item><item><title>Introducing ‘Innerworth – Mind over markets’</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>