<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>trading on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/trading/</link><description>Recent content in trading on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/trading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Does technical analysis work?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-technical-analysis-work/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-technical-analysis-work/</guid><description>The best part about TA is that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t let us go against the trend and forces us to have a stop loss. It stops us from averaging down as the price falls. If traders follow these rules, odds of doing well go up significantly.
But can the various indicators and patterns magically help determine the right time to enter or exit? My sense is probably not.
Has the trend of people who care about TA as a % of people who trade the markets increased over the last few years?</description></item><item><title>Trading advice from Ramesh Damani</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trading-advice-from-ramesh-damani/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trading-advice-from-ramesh-damani/</guid><description>A Tradingqna user pointed to a video of Ramesh Damani where he says, Trading is always done by slip book &amp;amp; not chequebook &amp;amp; asked what it meant. Ramesh explains this other version of maybe the most important rule in trading &amp;amp; life, Cut your losers &amp;amp; Hold on to the winners.
Thanks, Ramesh, for taking the time to share the response to my cold email. 😃 Here is the link to the full post.</description></item><item><title>a few thoughts on the increase in Securities Transaction Tax (STT)</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-increase-in-stt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-increase-in-stt/</guid><description>Here are a few thoughts on the STT increase. The 25% increase in F&amp;amp;O STT will further move volumes from futures to options. The actual impact wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be much because over 80% of the volumes come from options &amp;amp; STT is on premium, not on contract value as it is in futures.
It is good that the impact will not be as much on options. But a vibrant capital market needs activity across futures and options.</description></item><item><title>SEBI cracks down on pump and dump scams on social media</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cracks-down-on-pump-and-dump-scams-on-social-media/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cracks-down-on-pump-and-dump-scams-on-social-media/</guid><description>SEBI is killing it with these enforcement orders 🔥
Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s against the pump &amp;amp; dump schemes peddled by selling greed &amp;amp; unrealistic returns through social media &amp;amp; YouTube should serve as a powerful deterrent. These scams had become the easiest game in town for manipulators.
These elaborate orders should hopefully put some fear amongst unauthorized tipsters and people offering unauthorized portfolio management services. Such actors damage the sanctity of capital markets in India.</description></item><item><title>The pitfalls of just looking at trading turnover figures to determine market activity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-pitfalls-of-just-looking-at-trading-turnover-figures-to-determine-market-activity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-pitfalls-of-just-looking-at-trading-turnover-figures-to-determine-market-activity/</guid><description>News headlines scream about options volumes overtaking cash volumes. But just looking at volumes &amp;amp; not unique users can be misleading.
Jump in options last 2 yrs is mostly due to intraday stock traders switching to options after intraday leverage restrictions in early 2021
~10% of active traders contribute ~90% of trading volumes, in mostly intraday cash and F&amp;amp;O.
Comparing trading volumes of traders to equity investors is like comparing apples to oranges or brinjals.</description></item><item><title>Overtrading is the biggest reason why traders lose money</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/overtrading-is-the-biggest-reason-why-traders-lose-money/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/overtrading-is-the-biggest-reason-why-traders-lose-money/</guid><description>The biggest reason active traders lose money is overtrading, the low brokerage doesn&amp;rsquo;t help. Traders forget that costs like STT, stamp duty, etc. are charged as a % of every trade &amp;amp; compound quickly. You&amp;rsquo;ll now see the total cost of a trade on the order form.
Ideally, we should have introduced this feature even before the SEBI circular requiring all trading platforms to display costs on the order form. This was a miss from our side.</description></item><item><title>Tracking global markets overnight isn't worth losing sleep</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/tracking-global-markets-overnight-is-not-worth-losing-sleep/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/tracking-global-markets-overnight-is-not-worth-losing-sleep/</guid><description>One of the wasteful things that most traders do is to actively track US markets at night instead of getting a good night&amp;rsquo;s sleep. Hopefully, the day-to-day divergence of our markets to the US over the last few months means traders will care lesser about the US &amp;amp; rest better. 😃</description></item><item><title>Margin penalties</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/margin-penalties/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/margin-penalties/</guid><description>Margin penalties are charged on F&amp;amp;O in case of insufficient minimum margins. Upfront penalty is on the broker if a client is allowed to trade with insufficient margins. Non-upfront is on the customer if there&amp;rsquo;s margin shortfall after entering a trade.
There&amp;rsquo;s been a debate over what&amp;rsquo;s an upfront penalty &amp;amp; what&amp;rsquo;s not.
If a broker ensures the required margin is available when entering trades, but if it goes up by EOD, is it upfront?</description></item><item><title>RBI alert list of CFD and Binary trading platforms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-alert-list-of-cfd-and-binary-trading-platforms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-alert-list-of-cfd-and-binary-trading-platforms/</guid><description>Despite all warnings, a lot of Indians trade on CFD and Binary trading platforms. RBI just published a list of such unauthorized trading platforms, warning Indians that trading on these platforms can be prosecuted under the FEMA act.
Hopefully, the payment gateways and businesses that take advertising money will also stop dealing with them. Read this post to know more about how these illegal CFDs and binary options platforms work.</description></item><item><title>Brokerage charges across the indsutry</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/brokerage-charges-across-the-industry/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/brokerage-charges-across-the-industry/</guid><description>Don’t know how to say it, but slowdown &amp;amp; all😬
We still don&amp;rsquo;t charge brokerage for equity delivery &amp;amp; charge Rs 20 or 0.03% whichever is lower for intraday.
Many of our competitors, with similar pricing, now charge for equity delivery or have a higher minimum brokerage %</description></item><item><title>Stock market scams to move money illegally</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-market-scams-to-move-money-illegally/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-market-scams-to-move-money-illegally/</guid><description>A trader was lured into sharing login credentials on a telegram group by promising high returns. Scammer created a loss &amp;amp; moved it to another account &amp;amp; disappeared. Don&amp;rsquo;t share login credentials, like a bank, there are illegal ways to move money out of a trading account.
Two ways in which money can be moved once access is compromised: Buying penny stocks which are part of a pump &amp;amp; dump scheme at high prices.</description></item><item><title>Does Option writing have higher odds of profits?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-option-writing-have-higher-odds-of-profits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-option-writing-have-higher-odds-of-profits/</guid><description>Does Option writing have higher odds of profits? Yeah, for sure, but only when risk is compared to option buying. Since max profits are limited &amp;amp; losses are unlimited, if the risk is not managed properly, option writing can be, eating like an ant &amp;amp; pooping like an elephant.
For most naked option writers, the losses in a volatile month may equal profits made over a long time period. If you&amp;rsquo;re writing options naked, risk has to be capped either in terms of capital allocated or a fixed stop loss of 1 to 5% of capital, the lower, the better.</description></item><item><title>Videos on Varsity options trading module</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/videos-on-varsity-options-trading-module/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/videos-on-varsity-options-trading-module/</guid><description>We know you&amp;rsquo;ve been waiting for a long time. Here&amp;rsquo;s the first video of the long-awaited options trading module😀 In this video, we start with the basics and understand how an option works. More importantly, we look at how options can be used to reduce risk.</description></item><item><title>The importance of money management</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-money-management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-money-management/</guid><description>The one important thing from this that I want everyone trading to know is that if traders make money quickly with bad behavior, they mostly lose it just as quickly. Money management, which most don&amp;rsquo;t focus on, is exponentially more important than buy/sell signals &amp;amp; strategies.
In the last 20yrs, I haven’t seen anyone who has kept profits from trading without good risk management. I know many who&amp;rsquo;ve lost quickly. The fastest was a client, who turned Rs 1lk to Rs 2 cr in 2 days buying deep OTM puts in 2008 but gave it all back in the next 12 months.</description></item><item><title>Unauthorised CFD and forex trading platforms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/unauthorised-cfd-and-forex-trading-platforms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/unauthorised-cfd-and-forex-trading-platforms/</guid><description>We had cautioned people about illegal CFD &amp;amp; Forex &amp;amp; Binary trading platforms a while back, but I still keep seeing those ads, which means people still losing money. Today&amp;rsquo;s RBI press release will hopefully put an end to these illegal platforms. The RBI circular also reiterates that trading derivatives on international exchanges with funds sent through LRS is not permitted.</description></item><item><title>History of F&amp;O margin requirements in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/history-of-fo-margin-requirements-in-india/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/history-of-fo-margin-requirements-in-india/</guid><description>NSE introduced F&amp;amp;O in 2000 &amp;amp; today NSE is the largest derivatives exchange in the world by volume. Trading activity was mostly in futures until 2008. Options only became popular once contract sizes &amp;amp; margins went up. A brief history of F&amp;amp;O margins.
A key impetus for us starting Zerodha in 2010 was that there were discussions in the markets on SEBI introducing margin reporting and short margin penalty for not collecting sufficient margins for overnight F&amp;amp;O positions after the market collapse in 2008.</description></item><item><title>Irresponsible influencers</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/influencers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/influencers/</guid><description>Watching famous personalities with huge fan followings trying to trigger their fans or retail investors to invest in super risky asset classes without talking about the risks, or caring about the risk profile of those who follow them is quite disgusting.
Thanks to Crypto, it&amp;rsquo;s been a case of &amp;ldquo;never meet your heroes,” with so many people I admired for peddling crypto, NFTs, etc. as safe &amp;amp; guaranteed. Nothing against Crypto, it would have been the same if stocks or even AAA-rated debt was peddled as being safe &amp;amp; guaranteed.</description></item><item><title>Why only 1% of traders make money</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-only-one-percent-traders-make-money/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-only-one-percent-traders-make-money/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m surprised that, so many are surprised that just 1% of active traders make more than bank fixed deposits over 3 years timeframe. Active trading is like running a business, only a small % succeed. The only easy bit about trading is starting trading.
Traders with an alternate source of income tend to do better or have higher odds of winning than those who rely only on trading for a living.</description></item><item><title>Physical delivery of stock F&amp;O &amp; their risks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/physical-delivery-risks-for-stock-futures-and-options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/physical-delivery-risks-for-stock-futures-and-options/</guid><description>With mandatory physical delivery for stock options and the removal of the Do Not Exercise (DNE) facility for options (Especially buy options), the risk of huge losses has gone up significantly if OTM options become ITM &amp;amp; there&amp;rsquo;s no liquidity to exit.</description></item><item><title>Fixing the tax audit requirement anomaly for trades</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fixing-the-tax-audit-requirement-anomaly-for-traders/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fixing-the-tax-audit-requirement-anomaly-for-traders/</guid><description>You need to get a CA to validate IT returns (ITR) or get a tax audit if profit when trading is&amp;lt; than 6% of turnover or if the turnover is&amp;gt; Rs 10 crores. This is an anomaly that needs to be fixed as the markets grow. Here is why it should be fixed. It may be easy too.
If you trade stocks intraday, F&amp;amp;O, or trade equity delivery very actively, you need to declare any P&amp;amp;L as business income using ITR3.</description></item><item><title>The stress of trading 24X7 crypto markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mental-health-impact-of-24x7-crypto/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mental-health-impact-of-24x7-crypto/</guid><description>I can&amp;rsquo;t even begin to imagine the mental health impact of 24X7 crypto markets on those with large crypto exposure. I&amp;rsquo;m sure stock traders will agree that a big reason they can [remain sane[(https://nithinkamath.me/blog/active-trading-and-stress/) is that the market is only open from 9 AM to 3.30 PM on weekdays.</description></item><item><title>A trading algo is as good as the person that wrote it</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-money-with-algos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-money-with-algos/</guid><description>I keep hearing often that algo traders are super profitable, which by the way isn’t true. While an algo doesn&amp;rsquo;t have emotions, it is only as good as the person who wrote it or controls (start &amp;amp; stop) it—the same person who&amp;rsquo;s riddled with fear and greed.
Every algo like any trader, strategy or stock, has ups &amp;amp; downs. Just like impatient discretionary traders constantly try to time entry &amp;amp; exit, getting in late &amp;amp; out early, trade against trends, the same happens with algo traders trying to constantly find the best algo as well.</description></item><item><title>Illiquidity premium</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/illquidity-and-the-temptation-of-selling-quick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/illquidity-and-the-temptation-of-selling-quick/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve asked a lot of successful MF, PE &amp;amp; VC managers if they would be able to resist the temptation to time the market and hold on to profitable investments if they could easily exit &amp;amp; enter investments like retail investors. The answer is almost always &amp;ldquo;hmm&amp;hellip; probably, not&amp;rdquo;.
The inability to time the market due to size constraints &amp;amp; illiquidity—especially in private markets forces fund managers to follow the fundamental investing rule—letting your winners run.</description></item><item><title>Trading is more about managing fear, greed and psychology than entry/exit strategy.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/managing-fear-and-greed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/managing-fear-and-greed/</guid><description>Trading is more about managing fear, greed and psychology than entry/exit strategy. This collection of newsletters by Marketwise on Zerodha Varsity is maybe the best out there on this topic.</description></item><item><title>Why look at notional contract value when buying options?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-look-at-notional-contract-value/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-look-at-notional-contract-value/</guid><description>Why look at notional contract value when buying options?
Yes, when you buy options the max you can lose is the premium you have paid. But to get a sense of risk and how fast or easily you can lose, you should look at the exposure or contract value, not the premium.
For eg, you have Rs 1L &amp;amp; you use it to buy 20 lots of Nifty calls = Rs 1.</description></item><item><title>Option buying - The riskiest trade</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/options-buying-the-riskiest-trade/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/options-buying-the-riskiest-trade/</guid><description>~80% of all open buy option positions at the end of every day are in losses.
Buying options ruins most retail traders. Because they don&amp;rsquo;t understand the risk of leverage, averaging down, &amp;amp; impact costs.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;re doing to help our users</description></item><item><title>Impact of trading costs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-trading-costs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-trading-costs/</guid><description>What most traders don&amp;rsquo;t realize is that they pay a good chunk of their capital as costs. If you add impact costs, the minimum return an active trader should generate to break even yearly on their portfolio is usually well above 20%. Yep, that high and that tough.
Costs include Statutory costs like STT, Stamp duty, GST Impact costs or slippages (while this doesn’t even seem like a cost, it adds up quickly.</description></item><item><title>Introducing kill switch</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-kill-switch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-kill-switch/</guid><description>When you&amp;rsquo;re in a drawdown while trading, the best thing to do is to take a break. Otherwise, the chances of you being irrational, taking large bets, overtrading &amp;amp; blowing up are high. And to nudge you to do just that, we now have a “Kill Switch”.
Enabling the Kill switch will instantly disable trading. Currently, this is manual. But we are working on automating this where you can set a maximum loss.</description></item><item><title>Nudging users to help them avoid mistakes</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-users-to-help-them-avoid-mistakes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-users-to-help-them-avoid-mistakes/</guid><description>Most people don&amp;rsquo;t spend time learning trading or forget what they&amp;rsquo;ve learnt when placing an order. The order placement step is also when users pay maximum attention. With &amp;ldquo;Nudge&amp;rdquo; we are now able to leverage that fraction of a second to educate users &amp;amp; help them avoid mistakes.
This Nudge on DHFL warning customers that the investment may go to 0 discouraged over 50% of our users from taking a trade.</description></item><item><title>Introducing tags and trading journal on Console</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-tags-on-console/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-tags-on-console/</guid><description>We are stoked about the new tagging feature on Console. Tagging your trades and maintaining a trading journal can help you become a better trader and also help you track your investment goals.
You can&amp;rsquo;t become a better trader if you don&amp;rsquo;t learn from your mistakes. But in order to learn, you need a proper journal of all your trades and the reasons you took the trades. You can then look back, review, and do more of what is working &amp;amp; less of what isn&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>How to know when odds are higher?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-to-know-when-odds-are-higher/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-to-know-when-odds-are-higher/</guid><description>Got a few questions about this tweet. How to know when odds are higher? The decision to trade should have multiple checkboxes, can’t just be one. Size has to be based on how many checkboxes a bet ticks. And this rule I think holds good not just for trading, but investing, business, &amp;amp; life. Let me explain.
Say your strategy is to buy or sell a stock every time price crosses a Moving Avg.</description></item><item><title>A nudge to stop people from losing money in Rights Entitlements</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudge-to-stop-people-from-losing-money-in-rights-entitlements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudge-to-stop-people-from-losing-money-in-rights-entitlements/</guid><description>Many retail investors buy Rights Entitlements (REs) without knowing that the value of REs will be zero if they don&amp;rsquo;t apply. Since May 2020 our clients have lost ~Rs 10cr by buying Rights entitlements &amp;amp; not applying. We now have a nudge to warn customers. Read about it here.</description></item><item><title>My view on reduction of intraday leverages</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-view-on-reduction-of-intraday-leverages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-view-on-reduction-of-intraday-leverages/</guid><description>My view on the reduction of intraday leverages is that there will be near-term pain (for Zerodha too). We&amp;rsquo;ll see a drop in trading volumes and an increase in impact cost. But in the long term, more traders will survive &amp;amp; hopefully make up for the dip.
There is an argument to be made for lesser intraday margins. VAR+ELM or SPAN+Exposure margin calculation is based on risk/volatility. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t differentiate between intraday &amp;amp; overnight risk, or that intraday is less risky and hence ideally requires lesser margins.</description></item><item><title>Trading with other people’s money</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trading-with-other-peoples-money/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trading-with-other-peoples-money/</guid><description>Managing other people&amp;rsquo;s money in ways that aren&amp;rsquo;t allowed leads to the most complaints with the regulators. There are ways to do it legally, and those that can incur significant penalties. Here&amp;rsquo;s all that you need to know about managing money. https://zerodha.com/z-connect/traders-zone/trading-with-other-peoples-money</description></item><item><title>Podcast - Nikhil Kamath on The Ranveer Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nik-on-the-ranveer-show/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nik-on-the-ranveer-show/</guid><description>Keeping your emotions in check is the most important skill as a trader. The Bro @nikhilkamathcio is a master at this. He&amp;rsquo;s never missed a trading day in last 15 yrs &amp;amp; I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen him react to P&amp;amp;L. Nik on his journey with the very sharp @BeerBicepsGuy</description></item><item><title>The Gamestop saga and lessons for retail investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</guid><description>In the Gamestop saga, the media has loved telling the story of how Retail made a lot of money from Hedge funds. The reality is entirely different, almost everyone apart from retail has probably made money or benefited from this.
Firstly, yes, a couple of Hedge funds were sitting on large losses on Gamestop shorts. Now that stock is at $50, the losses also would be a fraction, if the shorts still held.</description></item><item><title>Rising financial awareness among Indians</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</guid><description>Financial awareness about the importance of saving and investing in India is increasing at the fastest rate ever, especially among millennials. Of course, stock markets doing well and lower bank FD rates are helping. But there are also a few structural changes afoot here. Historically financial products have been sold hard &amp;amp; mostly in person. Products mostly sold based on promises of high returns (sales pitches in person leave no audit trail).</description></item><item><title>Shorting and Indian Capital Markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</guid><description>Can retail traders are cause a “short squeeze” in India like they did in stocks like GameStop and AMC entertainment in the US? It cannot, and I explain why in this post. Join the discussion here.</description></item><item><title>Is trading the markets gambling?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-trading-the-markets-gambling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-trading-the-markets-gambling/</guid><description>Is trading the markets gambling? I get asked often. My answer is that yes, you can gamble when trading, just like you can gamble with everything else in life.</description></item><item><title>A product to get more Indians to save and invest</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</guid><description>To get the next 10 crore Indians, the traditional financial product might not work. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I think is needed to get these people to start saving and investing.</description></item><item><title>Does Illiquidty like in private markets lead to good investor behavior?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-illiquidty-like-in-private-markets-lead-to/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-illiquidty-like-in-private-markets-lead-to/</guid><description>A question I have been asking institutional investors in both private and public markets is - if they could enter and exit their holdings at will like retail investors(which they cannot today), would they have actually sat through the ride of their best-performing holdings? The answer usually is no. As counterintuitive as it sounds, maybe the inability to easily enter/exit large public or illiquid private holdings forces fund managers to sit tight, which is also why they can outperform retail investors who are always trying to time the market.</description></item><item><title>Nudging people towards doing the right things</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-people-towards-doing-the-right-things/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-people-towards-doing-the-right-things/</guid><description>The penny stock Nudge introduced in March on Kite has helped us reduce penny stock trading volume significantly. It has given us hope that the bunch of new nudges we are working on will help our customers stay away from bad trading behavior.</description></item><item><title>Sitting on a profitable trade is harder than sitting on a loss making trade</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sitting-on-a-profitable-trade-is-harder-than-on-a/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sitting-on-a-profitable-trade-is-harder-than-on-a/</guid><description>Contrary to what most people think, it is much tougher to sit on a profitable trade vs loss-making. All decent traders have a defined stop to handle losing trades. When on profit, we all know we have to let our winners run, but all our biases constantly push us to book profits.</description></item><item><title>What does it take to win at trading?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</guid><description>Learnings from interactions with thousands of traders and my own successes and failures.</description></item><item><title>Introducing ‘Innerworth – Mind over markets’</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>