<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>broking on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/broking/</link><description>Recent content in broking on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/broking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How SEBIs standardised files made our systems leaner and efficient</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-sebis-standardised-files-made-our-systems-leaner-and-efficient/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-sebis-standardised-files-made-our-systems-leaner-and-efficient/</guid><description>One critical aspect of the brokerage business most people are unaware of is the sheer underlying complexity.
At a high level, we integrate with multiple stock exchanges, depositories, RTAs, banks, and others. Each of these integrations (hundreds of APIs and file exchanges) has been non-uniform and non-standard, resulting in massive amounts of technical and operational complexity. These are completely invisible to a broker&amp;rsquo;s clients.
A great example of quiet, systemic backend work yielding significant impact is the multi-year exercise SEBI undertook to standardise data exchange across market entities—the Unified Distilled File Formats (UDiFF).</description></item><item><title>What the Jane Street probe tells us about India’s market oversight</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-the-jane-street-probe-tells-us-about-indias-market-oversight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-the-jane-street-probe-tells-us-about-indias-market-oversight/</guid><description>You’ve got to hand it to SEBI for going after Jane Street. If the allegations are true, it’s blatant market manipulation.
The shocking part? They kept at it even after receiving warnings from the exchanges. Maybe this is what happens when you&amp;rsquo;re used to the lenient U.S. regulatory regime. Think about the structure of U.S. markets: dark pools, payment for order flow, and other loopholes that allow hedge funds to make billions off retail investors.</description></item><item><title>What we think about Jio-BlackRock's entry into broking</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-we-think-about-jio-blackrocks-entry-into-broking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-we-think-about-jio-blackrocks-entry-into-broking/</guid><description>Many people asked me about Jio-BlackRock getting a stockbroking license. Firstly, this is great news. The biggest issue for the Indian markets is a lack of breadth in participation. We&amp;rsquo;re largely limited to the top 10 crore Indians.
If anyone can expand the markets beyond the top 10 crore Indians, it&amp;rsquo;s probably Jio with all its distribution might. As for how many new Indian investors have the money to invest in the market, I don&amp;rsquo;t know.</description></item><item><title>Why Zerodha doesn't advertise</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-doesnt-advertise/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-doesnt-advertise/</guid><description>I watched a cricket match after a long time, and damn! Every fourth ad is that of a brokerage firm. Sign of good times for the markets😀
I often get asked, both internally and externally, why we don&amp;rsquo;t advertise.
It is a good place to be when you don&amp;rsquo;t have to look at customers in terms of acquisition costs (CAC) and lifetime value (LTV). This way, we don&amp;rsquo;t have to push customers to take a trade, we can stay spam-free, not have to sell life insurance as an investment, and more.</description></item><item><title>On SEBI's proposed changes to simplify DP processes</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-sebis-proposed-changes-to-simplify-dp-processes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-sebis-proposed-changes-to-simplify-dp-processes/</guid><description>This consultation paper, if implemented, significantly simplifies the DP operations of stock brokers. Today, when a client buys stock, it gets credited to the broker pool account, and then the broker credits it to the customer. In the new way proposed, the shares will get directly credited to the customer&amp;rsquo;s demat.
Even without this regulation, we&amp;rsquo;re probably the safest financial market in terms of the security of customer assets, given that everything is in the customer&amp;rsquo;s own demat.</description></item><item><title>Dark patterns in banking</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dark-patterns-in-banking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dark-patterns-in-banking/</guid><description>A colleague had to visit a bank branch offline to close a personal loan he took online. This branch was one of only 2 in Bangalore. It&amp;rsquo;s the same with many other banks. Making it hard to close an account is a dark pattern, and maybe there should be regulations on this.
By the way, SEBI mandates that all stockbrokers must provide a facility to close accounts online. Additionally, at Zerodha, we are maybe one of the few brokers to allow online transfer of stocks to demat accounts outside Zerodha.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on use cases of RBI's single block and multiple debits on UPI</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/thoughts-on-use-cases-of-rbis-single-block-and-multiple-debits-on-upi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/thoughts-on-use-cases-of-rbis-single-block-and-multiple-debits-on-upi/</guid><description>RBI&amp;rsquo;s announcement of allowing single block and multiple debits on UPI can potentially have some interesting outcomes for the broking industry. A few thoughts.
Why?
The broking industry has a chequered past, with a few firms misusing customer funds. The regulatory changes over the last few years have ensured that such instances are unlikely in the future. But ensuring that retails investors are protected is a top priority for SEBI.</description></item><item><title>Demat accounts in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/decline-in-growth-of-demat-accounts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/decline-in-growth-of-demat-accounts/</guid><description>Check the chart here.</description></item><item><title>Wrong estimates of trading activity, market size and market share</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/wrong-estimates-of-trading-activity-market-size-and-market-share/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/wrong-estimates-of-trading-activity-market-size-and-market-share/</guid><description>Even to this day, a lot of people misconstrue the turnover numbers declared by the exchanges. This often leads to wrong estimates of trading activity and market size &amp;amp; share. So if A buys stock X for Rs 1lk &amp;amp; B sells for Rs 1lk, the exchange turnover = Rs 1lk &amp;amp; not Rs 2lks.
To calculate market size estimates based on exchange turnovers, the right way would be to multiply the exchange turnover by 2 and then calculate the %.</description></item><item><title>Can brokerage go to 0 in India?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/can-brokerage-go-to-0-in-india/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/can-brokerage-go-to-0-in-india/</guid><description>Many people ask me if brokerage rates can go to zero like in the US, and why not flat monthly brokerage plans with unlimited trades. I don&amp;rsquo;t think so. I think, if anything, brokerage rates will go up in the future. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.
Firstly, in the US, brokers can earn in ways that SEBI rightly doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow here: Payment for order flow: selling customer orders to HFT firms. Securities lending: Unlike India, stocks are held in the street name or in the name of brokers—they can lend them to earn.</description></item><item><title>Total addressable market for brokers</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/total-addressable-market-for-brokers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/total-addressable-market-for-brokers/</guid><description>Since broking is hot post-COVID, inspite of all the spike in trading volumes and activity, the total addressable market is just ~1.5 million users. I had shared this pre-Covid. Broking is super hot now, but this TAM (Total addressable market) hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed, if anything it has reduced. Btw, the revenue-generating active day traders + F&amp;amp;O crowd is not more than ~1.5mil in spite of the spike in trading activity/volumes. This active crowd is unlikely to go up because most day and F&amp;amp;O traders stop within 6 months.</description></item></channel></rss>