<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>environment on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/environment/</link><description>Recent content in environment on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/environment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Making food packaging plastic-free with Zerocircle</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-food-packaging-plastic-free-with-zerocircle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-food-packaging-plastic-free-with-zerocircle/</guid><description>Almost all food packaging that resembles paper or cardboard, such as coffee cups, takeout boxes, and food wrappers, has a thin plastic coating. This plastic isn&amp;rsquo;t just bad for the planet; it leaches microplastics directly into your food and body.
Zerocircle (a Rainmatter Climate investment) makes coatings from 100% natural compounds. No plastic, no microplastics.
Solutions like this can only go mainstream with public awareness. Most people are unaware that a &amp;ldquo;paper&amp;rdquo; cup isn&amp;rsquo;t entirely made of paper.</description></item><item><title>Gurukula Botanical Sanctuary is quietly reviving a part of the Western Ghats</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gurukula-otanical-anctuary-is-quietly-reviving-a-part-of-the-western-ghats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gurukula-otanical-anctuary-is-quietly-reviving-a-part-of-the-western-ghats/</guid><description>In the times of shrinking forests and quick-fix plantation drives, a small community at the Gurukula Botanical Sanctuary is doing something truly special.
For the last 44 years, this small group of &amp;ldquo;gardeners in service to forests&amp;rdquo; has been patiently nurturing a part of the Western Ghats, bringing degraded lands back to life. What they have achieved is mind-boggling.
They have managed to grow and propagate over 2000 native plant species.</description></item><item><title>How Amwoodo’s bamboo revolution is driving rural prosperity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-amwoodos-bamboo-revolution-is-driving-rural-prosperity/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-amwoodos-bamboo-revolution-is-driving-rural-prosperity/</guid><description>3x increase in rural incomes (~Rs 10,000 to ~Rs 30,000). 1200 farmers and artisans are earning much more. 11 lakh bamboo trees planted. 384 metric tons of plastic were kept out of landfills. 312232 metric tons of CO2 offset.
The last few years of partnering Amwoodo and Agni Mitra have been special. And yeah, the business is for profit and quite profitable.
I really hope these numbers keep increasing as the business grows and has to deal with other pressures and competing priorities.</description></item><item><title>Turning Lantana’s destruction into opportunity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/turning-lantanas-estruction-into-opportunity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/turning-lantanas-estruction-into-opportunity/</guid><description>If you grew up in the rural parts of India or even spent some time there, you would have probably seen a Lantana plant and its colourful flowers. While it looks colourful, it has to be one of the world&amp;rsquo;s worst invasive species. It was brought to India as an ornamental shrub in the 18th century, but it has now spread like a disease across 13 million hectares of priceless forest land and pastures.</description></item></channel></rss>