<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tweet on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/tweet/</link><description>Recent content in tweet on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/tweet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>US elections, who will win?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/us-elections-who-will-win/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/us-elections-who-will-win/</guid><description>If you feel the pulse of the US through Twitter, it definitely feels like Trump. But Twitter is a bubble and doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily represent the election results, or reality for that matter.
What makes it even more skewed is that the majority of the tweets are generated by less than ~1% of Twitter’s user base.
So yeah, I don&amp;rsquo;t know. But it&amp;rsquo;s definitely not wise to form views based on your Twitter feed.</description></item><item><title>Nik's podcast amongst the top video podcasts globally</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/niks-podcast-amongst-the-top-video-podcasts-globally/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/niks-podcast-amongst-the-top-video-podcasts-globally/</guid><description>Dayum! It&amp;rsquo;s crazy that @nikhilkamathcio&amp;rsquo;s podcast is among the top video podcasts globally.
I think the reason people like the show is because Nik does it with the intent to learn and share knowledge. There&amp;rsquo;s no hidden agenda or sales pitch. More importantly, he isn&amp;rsquo;t afraid of saying &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t know&amp;rdquo; publicly. Very few people can be like this after being successful professionally.
I think the reason people like the show is because Nik does it with the intent to learn and share knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Beware of pig butchering scams</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-pig-butchering-scams/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-pig-butchering-scams/</guid><description>The scale of pig butchering scams in India runs into tens of thousands of crores. It is scary how many people fall for fake job offer scams, scammy high-return investment schemes and crypto investments, etc.
As the name implies, a pig butchering scam involves fattening the victim before butchering. Scammers gain the trust of users by using fake profiles. They use the pretense of love and friendship to gain the trust of users and then induce them to send money for jobs and high-return investments and steal the money.</description></item><item><title>Why Zerodha doesn't have a data team</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-doesnt-have-a-data-team/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-doesnt-have-a-data-team/</guid><description>How useful is collecting &amp;amp; analysing tons of data is a question I ask my peers. We have no data team at Zerodha as we believe it doesn&amp;rsquo;t give useful insights &amp;amp; also since we never upsell.
Article &amp;amp; comments on this topic are interesting 😬</description></item><item><title>Kantara is an must watch movie</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kantara-is-a-must-watch-movie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kantara-is-a-must-watch-movie/</guid><description>Just watched Kantara, &amp;amp; it is one of those moments when you feel proud to be a Kannadiga. Even more, since my roots are where the movie was shot.
Still have goosebumps from the last 30 mins. It is a must-watch.
@shetty_rishab ♥️</description></item><item><title>India FOSS - Fireside chat with Rudra Saraswat: 12 year old linux dev</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kailash-nadh-in-coversation-with-rudra-saraswat-12-year-old-linux-dev/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kailash-nadh-in-coversation-with-rudra-saraswat-12-year-old-linux-dev/</guid><description>When I was 12 years old, I was climbing trees. Talk about evolution. 😬 K (Kailash) says that the boy is special, so this coversation should definitely be interesting. Missed tagging Rudra Saraswat who probably right now is sitting in his classroom learning fractions &amp;amp; decimals. 😃</description></item><item><title>Beware of phishing attacks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-phishing-attacks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-phishing-attacks/</guid><description>One common way investors get defrauded is by sharing their login details with others. Artificial losses can be created using illiquid options or penny stocks to move money out. Just like you don&amp;rsquo;t share your bank logins, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t share your trading account logins as well.
The other way accounts get compromised is through phishing frauds. It&amp;rsquo;s Important to not enter login details anywhere apart from the official broker websites and apps.</description></item><item><title>The Gamestop saga and lessons for retail investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</guid><description>In the Gamestop saga, the media has loved telling the story of how Retail made a lot of money from Hedge funds. The reality is entirely different, almost everyone apart from retail has probably made money or benefited from this.
Firstly, yes, a couple of Hedge funds were sitting on large losses on Gamestop shorts. Now that stock is at $50, the losses also would be a fraction, if the shorts still held.</description></item><item><title>Rising financial awareness among Indians</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</guid><description>Financial awareness about the importance of saving and investing in India is increasing at the fastest rate ever, especially among millennials. Of course, stock markets doing well and lower bank FD rates are helping. But there are also a few structural changes afoot here. Historically financial products have been sold hard &amp;amp; mostly in person. Products mostly sold based on promises of high returns (sales pitches in person leave no audit trail).</description></item></channel></rss>