<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>tweet on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/tweet/</link><description>Recent content in tweet on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/tweet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>India FOSS - Fireside chat with Rudra Saraswat: 12 year old linux dev</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kailash-nadh-in-coversation-with-rudra-saraswat-12-year-old-linux-dev/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kailash-nadh-in-coversation-with-rudra-saraswat-12-year-old-linux-dev/</guid><description>When I was 12 years old, I was climbing trees. Talk about evolution. 😬 K (Kailash) says that the boy is special, so this coversation should definitely be interesting. Missed tagging Rudra Saraswat who probably right now is sitting in his classroom learning fractions &amp;amp; decimals. 😃</description></item><item><title>Beware of phishing attacks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-phishing-attacks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beware-of-phishing-attacks/</guid><description>One common way investors get defrauded is by sharing their login details with others. Artificial losses can be created using illiquid options or penny stocks to move money out. Just like you don&amp;rsquo;t share your bank logins, you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t share your trading account logins as well.
The other way accounts get compromised is through phishing frauds. It&amp;rsquo;s Important to not enter login details anywhere apart from the official broker websites and apps.</description></item><item><title>The Gamestop saga and lessons for retail investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</guid><description>In the Gamestop saga, the media has loved telling the story of how Retail made a lot of money from Hedge funds. The reality is entirely different, almost everyone apart from retail has probably made money or benefited from this.
Firstly, yes, a couple of Hedge funds were sitting on large losses on Gamestop shorts. Now that stock is at $50, the losses also would be a fraction, if the shorts still held.</description></item><item><title>Rising financial awareness among Indians</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</guid><description>Financial awareness about the importance of saving and investing in India is increasing at the fastest rate ever, especially among millennials. Of course, stock markets doing well and lower bank FD rates are helping. But there are also a few structural changes afoot here. Historically financial products have been sold hard &amp;amp; mostly in person. Products mostly sold based on promises of high returns (sales pitches in person leave no audit trail).</description></item></channel></rss>