<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>regulations on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/regulations/</link><description>Recent content in regulations on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/regulations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The nuisance of dark patterns</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-nuisance-of-dark-patterns/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-nuisance-of-dark-patterns/</guid><description>My phone like for many has become unusable because of the nuisance of unsolicited calls, SMS, and WhatsApp messages I didn’t opt-in for. I waste at least 15 minutes a day marking emails as spam because, in many cases, the unsubscribe option is hidden. Then, there are the deceptive UI/UX patterns, which make things even worse. But there seems to be hope around the corner.
The Department of Consumer Affairs recently issued draft guidelines for the prevention and regulation of dark patterns.</description></item><item><title>Dark patterns in banking</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dark-patterns-in-banking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dark-patterns-in-banking/</guid><description>A colleague had to visit a bank branch offline to close a personal loan he took online. This branch was one of only 2 in Bangalore. It&amp;rsquo;s the same with many other banks. Making it hard to close an account is a dark pattern, and maybe there should be regulations on this.
By the way, SEBI mandates that all stockbrokers must provide a facility to close accounts online. Additionally, at Zerodha, we are maybe one of the few brokers to allow online transfer of stocks to demat accounts outside Zerodha.</description></item><item><title>Addressing tax evasion</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/addressing-tax-evasion/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/addressing-tax-evasion/</guid><description>Govt has to do whatever to curb underreporting of income &amp;amp; tax evasion. Easier said than done, but maybe the better way is to deter people by increasing penalties &amp;amp; acting quickly on financial violations. Those that want to evade taxes or break rules will always find loopholes.</description></item></channel></rss>