<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Musings on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Musings on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One year of the Zerodha FLOSS fund</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/one-year-of-the-zerodha-floss-fund/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/one-year-of-the-zerodha-floss-fund/</guid><description>We started FLOSS/fund in 2024 to give up to $1 million annually to support the development of FOSS (free and open-source) projects globally.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what K said in a post reflecting on the past year, making the case for the Indian government also to fund FOSS for strategic tech sovereignty:
&amp;ldquo;Actually, no amount of material resources can enable governments to develop, nurture, and sustain complex, high-quality FOSS projects themselves in the way a community of passionate maintainers can.</description></item><item><title>Cybersecurity is as human as it is technical</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cybersecurity-is-as-human-as-it-is-technical/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cybersecurity-is-as-human-as-it-is-technical/</guid><description>So, my personal Twitter account was compromised yesterday because I fell for a phishing e-mail early in the morning while at home when browsing on my personal device.
A momentary lapse in attention. The e-mail got through all spam and phishing filters. I clicked on the &amp;lsquo;Change Your Password&amp;rsquo; link and entered the password. The attackers gained access to a single login session, using it to tweet a few scammy cryptocurrency links.</description></item><item><title>The love we get for all the content is crazy</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-love-we-get-for-all-the-content-is-crazy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-love-we-get-for-all-the-content-is-crazy/</guid><description>The love we get for all the content on Varsity, Markets by Zerodha etc. is crazy. 😀What we&amp;rsquo;ve done from day 1 is focus on sharing quality insights rather than chasing engagement, pointless optimizations, and gimmicks. The trust we&amp;rsquo;ve built over almost a decade is a direct result of that—people reading and watching us and then sharing it with their friends and family.</description></item><item><title>Open source for tech sovereignty</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-for-tech-sovereignty/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-for-tech-sovereignty/</guid><description>Tech sovereignty and self-sufficiency are national conversations now, the world over. Free and open-source software (FOSS) enables just that—tech sovereignty and, at the same time, mutually assured global collaboration and innovation. IndiaAI Mission&amp;rsquo;s recent push for sovereign open-source LLMs is a great example for this. Without FOSS, there would be no Zerodha or the global digital ecosystem as we know it today.
Here&amp;rsquo;s an article by K (Kailash) on the topic from 2021 that&amp;rsquo;s still relevant now.</description></item><item><title>Financial inclusion needs more than just digital access</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-inclusion-needs-more-than-just-digital-access/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-inclusion-needs-more-than-just-digital-access/</guid><description>The entire Indian financial services industry, including Zerodha, has been a massive beneficiary of the ease of digital onboarding via Aadhaar e-Sign, eKYC, etc. It has been a big reason for the increase in financial inclusion among Tier 2 and 3 cities and rural parts of the country; people who had not previously interacted with the formal financial system.
While many of us take the benefits of these digital systems for granted, being in a city like Bengaluru (and a position of privilege), I was surprised by the extent of challenges with OTP verification and the physical/biometric side of these systems until I read articles like these in The Times of India and elsewhere.</description></item><item><title>Real stories from parents investing through Zerodha minor accounts.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-stories-from-parents-investing-through-zerodha-minor-accounts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/real-stories-from-parents-investing-through-zerodha-minor-accounts/</guid><description>I can keep giving gyan about starting to invest early for your kids, but nothing beats hearing it from parents who are actually doing it. Here are some first-hand takes from people using a Zerodha minor account to invest for their children.
P.S. Our youngest account holder is just 64 days old. 😀</description></item><item><title>India’s $3 trillion in idle gold needs smarter financialization.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</guid><description>Indian households hold ~$3 trillion in gold (World Gold Council estimate), sitting idle in lockers. Meanwhile, equity investments fund companies that need capital to grow. We need better ways to financialize this gold beyond just gold loans.</description></item><item><title>RBI move could make LAS more popular</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-move-could-make-las-more-popular/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-move-could-make-las-more-popular/</guid><description>One good change from RBI yesterday: banks can now lend up to ₹1 crore against shares, up from the earlier ₹20 lakhs. Hopefully, this makes loan against securities (LAS) more popular.
It’s ridiculous how many people holding stocks continue taking personal loans or using credit cards at much higher rates—credit cards can go up to 40%+. Even at Zerodha Capital, we see this constantly. People just aren’t aware they can replace high-interest debt with LAS, which is one reason our book is still only ₹450 crores.</description></item><item><title>Why short-term growth is the wrong metric</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-short-term-growth-is-the-wrong-metric/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-short-term-growth-is-the-wrong-metric/</guid><description>On the question of what would we do if weekly options were removed, I suppose we&amp;rsquo;ll see another hit to our revenues in the short-term.
Having said that, when you&amp;rsquo;re building a business for the long term, focusing on quarterly or even annual growth is a poor metric. The more you focus on them, the higher the odds that you&amp;rsquo;ll do things that are bad for your customers.</description></item><item><title>15 years of Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/15-years-of-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/15-years-of-zerodha/</guid><description>From 2021, I had been tweeting about the risks to the broking business, but somehow I kept getting surprised on the upside. But starting around October last year, all the risks I was thinking about crystallised. First came the STT increase on options, then the removal of exchange transaction charge rebates, and a reduction in weekly expiries. In addition to this, there was a significant decline in market activity. Due to all these factors, our revenues and profits suffered a decline.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha Fund House crosses ₹8000 crores AUM</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-fund-house-crosses-8000-crores-aum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-fund-house-crosses-8000-crores-aum/</guid><description>Zerodha Fund House is almost 2 years old, and we have reached ~₹8,000 crores despite not talking much about it. What&amp;rsquo;s cool is that practically all of this AUM comes from individual investors.
The AMC has grown steadily even as competition has intensified, with newer AMCs entering the market and existing AMCs launching more passive funds. We could have grown our AUM faster by offering regular plans and paying commissions, but we&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to remain direct-only and focus on easy-to-understand index funds and ETFs like our recently launched multi-asset fund (link in the replies).</description></item><item><title>Ditto rebuilding trust in insurance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ditto-rebuilding-trust-in-insurance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ditto-rebuilding-trust-in-insurance/</guid><description>Historically, people haven&amp;rsquo;t bought life and health insurance because of all the scams and spam. The trust deficit in insurance is way too high. People simply don&amp;rsquo;t trust people who sell insurance.
I&amp;rsquo;m really happy that Ditto is doing whatever it can to fix this.</description></item><item><title>Rebuilding soil health with Akshayakalpa</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rebuilding-soil-health-with-akshayakalpa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rebuilding-soil-health-with-akshayakalpa/</guid><description>Soil Organic Content (SOC) is critical in farming. It determines how well soil holds water, delivers nutrients to plants, maintains structure, and supports the millions of microbes that make soil alive. When SOC drops below 0.5%, you&amp;rsquo;re looking at desert-like conditions where nothing grows without the farmer pumping in fertilisers. India&amp;rsquo;s farmland averages a shocking 0.3% SOC. Compare that to European Union cropland at 1.8%—that&amp;rsquo;s the gold standard.
A few weeks ago, Shashi Kumar, the founder of Akshayakalpa, shared something incredible from AK Farms.</description></item><item><title>What does Zerodha do differently?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-zerodha-do-differently/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-zerodha-do-differently/</guid><description>Someone on Reddit asked what does Zerodha do differently, how are we profitable, why don&amp;rsquo;t IPO etc. This is what I replied:
Hmmm&amp;hellip; so you forget that we have spent 15 years getting here. And maybe another 10 years, before Zerodha, I was involved in the markets in some form. So, 25 years in all. Things in business compound over time, especially if you like or love what you are doing and if you are lucky to be in the right place and time.</description></item><item><title>My take on weekly options and what could happen next</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-take-on-weekly-options-and-what-could-happen-next/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-take-on-weekly-options-and-what-could-happen-next/</guid><description>Many people have been asking me about my view on weekly options and whether they are going away. I am as clueless as everybody else. 😃
Having said that, I would not be surprised if they were banned completely, and/or if there is some product suitability framework that makes it harder for people to trade F&amp;amp;O.
By the way, as I&amp;rsquo;ve said numerous times before, regulatory risk is by far the biggest risk for brokers like us.</description></item><item><title>Insights from our interaction with Social Alpha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/insights-from-our-interaction-with-social-alpha/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/insights-from-our-interaction-with-social-alpha/</guid><description>We at Rainmatter finally met the Social Alpha team, and I am still thinking about everything Manoj Malgharia shared.
Set up as a non-profit, they’re solving some of the toughest social, economic, and environmental challenges by bridging the gap between science and society.
What stood out is not just the funding or grants they make, but more importantly, the way they support ideas — from testing in their labs to taking them to market, derisking for scale, and much more.</description></item><item><title>2 lakh registrations on Varsity Live</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/2-lakh-registrations-on-varsity-live/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/2-lakh-registrations-on-varsity-live/</guid><description>We just hit 2 lakh registrations on Varsity Live in a short time!
The goal with Varsity Live has always been to make high-quality, interactive financial education accessible to as many people as possible.
By live, I don’t mean boring webinars or one-way monologues. I mean fun, engaging sessions where you can interact with a mentor, learn by doing exercises, use tools, build things, take quizzes, and more.
So yeah, people are really liking what we’re doing so far.</description></item><item><title>Manage investments better with secondary demat account</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/manage-investments-better-with-secondary-demat-account/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/manage-investments-better-with-secondary-demat-account/</guid><description>When I was trading actively (before Zerodha), I had an offline demat account where I held all my investments and an online account for all my trades. This was a way to avoid the temptation of &amp;ldquo;trading&amp;rdquo; my investments 😬
If I had to sell any of my investments, there was effort involved. I had to physically fill out the delivery instruction slips and send them to the broker to move holdings to my primary demat and then sell them.</description></item><item><title>Creating safe spaces in sexual health discussions through Rainmatter</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/creating-safe-spaces-in-sexual-health-discussions-through-rainmatter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/creating-safe-spaces-in-sexual-health-discussions-through-rainmatter/</guid><description>The one important type of health we don&amp;rsquo;t talk about is sexual health for obvious reasons. But the numbers are scary:
Male infertility now accounts for 50% of infertility cases in India.
1 in 10 Indian men experience erectile dysfunction. India has one of the highest rates of untreated STIs globally, especially among youth and migrant populations. 56% of Indian women report some form of sexual dysfunction.
Over the last few years, we&amp;rsquo;ve realised that health issues among Indians have increased and will continue to increase because of poor quality food, air, water, and lifestyles in general.</description></item><item><title>Some moments from Hyrox event</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/some-moments-from-the-hyrox-event/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/some-moments-from-the-hyrox-event/</guid><description>Turns out being old at HYROX has an advantage. #3 in my age category. 😬
Seema the cancer survivor killing the circuit as well. 😶
And Nikhil’s birthday party followed by a killer WTF offline event hosted by Nik.
Tagging Dilip Kumar and peakst8</description></item></channel></rss>