<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Musings on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Musings on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Case for building India’s own deep tech stack</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/case-for-building-indias-own-deep-tech-stack/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/case-for-building-indias-own-deep-tech-stack/</guid><description>Tech seems to be getting effectively nationalized. Starting from around 2020, we’ve seen an increase in export controls on things like chips, critical minerals, restrictions on advanced manufacturing equipment, and various other trade restrictions. Supply chains have become a security issue for countries.
We’re no longer in a world where India can be okay with just exporting IT services. If we don’t build domestic deep tech capabilities, we’ll be locked out when it matters most.</description></item><item><title>Technical issue at a depository disrupting settlement</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/technical-issue-at-a-depository-disrupting-settlement/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/technical-issue-at-a-depository-disrupting-settlement/</guid><description>There was a technical issue at one of the depositories this week that disrupted settlement and had a cascading effect on the market. Since many people may not fully understand how settlement works, let me explain what happened.
When you buy or sell stocks, the trade settles on T+1. The Clearing Corporation (CC) determines the net obligations. Meaning who owes shares and who owes money and instructs the depositories (NSDL/CDSL) to move shares between sellers’ and buyers’ demat accounts via their brokers (Depository Participants).</description></item><item><title>Kite Terminal Mode is now live on beta</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kite-terminal-mode-is-now-live-on-beta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kite-terminal-mode-is-now-live-on-beta/</guid><description>Kite Terminal Mode is now live on beta!
We are quite excited about this. 😬
Check out the Kite Beta, and you can provide feedback here.</description></item><item><title>Simplifying Corporate NPS with PensionBox</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/simplifying-corporate-nps-with-pensionbox/</link><pubDate>Thu, 05 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/simplifying-corporate-nps-with-pensionbox/</guid><description>In FY25, around 72% of taxpayers chose the New Tax Regime. At Zerodha, that number was over 90%.
This shift makes sense. The new tax regime trades deductions for simpler filing and lower tax rates. For many—especially younger salaried taxpayers, avoiding paperwork-heavy exemptions matters more than maximising deductions.
With most deductions removed, salaried employees are left with the ₹75,000 standard deduction and one meaningful tax-saving option: the employer contribution to NPS, commonly called Corporate NPS.</description></item><item><title>Raising STT won’t curb speculation in F&amp;O</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/raising-stt-wont-curb-speculation-in-fo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/raising-stt-wont-curb-speculation-in-fo/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know the exact reasoning behind the increase in STT. Having said that, if the goal was to reduce speculative activity in F&amp;amp;O, then I&amp;rsquo;m not sure this will do anything.
95% of trading is already in options, and this STT increase will only push that share higher. Why? Because the impact falls mostly on futures, while options are far more speculative than futures.
If the govt wants to reduce speculation, then establishing product suitability (who can trade) criteria is the way to go.</description></item><item><title>Every budget, I hope STT comes down</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/every-budget-i-hope-stt-comes-down/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/every-budget-i-hope-stt-comes-down/</guid><description>As a market participant, I always hope the budget will reduce STT, but it keeps going up. STT was introduced when LTCG was made 0, but now that LTCG is back&amp;hellip; 😬
The 60% F&amp;amp;O STT increase from Budget 2024 (0.0125% → 0.02% on futures and 0.0625% → 0.1% on options) didn’t impact volumes much at first, the bull market continued with surging participation. But markets don’t always have bull runs; the impact showed up in the year we just had.</description></item><item><title>Women in Koraput, Odisha document the slow disappearance of the commons</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/women-in-koraput/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/women-in-koraput/</guid><description>Women from indigenous communities in Odisha’s Koraput district are mapping their commons — forests, streams, grazing land, and other shared resources they depend on daily.
They’re doing this because these commons are disappearing. Water sources are drying up, forest cover is thinning, and there’s no clear record of what existed, what’s already lost, or how the change happened.
So they went looking for answers. They pulled government records from the 1960s and walked the land, documenting what exists today.</description></item><item><title>Recent updates to make investing easier for NRIs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recent-updates-to-make-investing-easier-for-nris/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recent-updates-to-make-investing-easier-for-nris/</guid><description>We at Zerodha , have ~40k NRI customers with an average account value of ₹40L, nearly 10x our overall average of ₹3.6L for resident accounts. Most of them opened accounts the hard way, with physical paperwork. If onboarding were fully online, this base would be much larger.
SEBI recently made changes that have allowed us to significantly simplify Non-PIS NRI accounts: they now work like resident accounts, with fully online Aadhaar-based onboarding (when visiting India) and intraday, BTST, and F&amp;amp;O access with no need for a CP code.</description></item><item><title>Get realtime company updates on WhatsApp with Tijori Alerts</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/get-realtime-company-updates-on-whatsapp-with-tijori-alerts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/get-realtime-company-updates-on-whatsapp-with-tijori-alerts/</guid><description>Access to information is what drives prices in markets. While there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of information today, the real challenge is figuring out what actually matters and getting it in time.
Exchange filings, earnings, management commentary, and conference calls. When something material comes out, prices react almost instantly. The faster you get the information, the better your odds of reacting sensibly.
Institutions and high-frequency trading desks scan exchange filings the moment they&amp;rsquo;re published and act within milliseconds.</description></item><item><title>MTF has grown 5x, but broker risk models haven’t</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mtf-has-grown-5x-but-broker-risk-models-havent/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mtf-has-grown-5x-but-broker-risk-models-havent/</guid><description>MTF (margin funding) has grown ~5X in 4 years to ₹110k+ crores, especially after F&amp;amp;O margins and STT increases. But there&amp;rsquo;s something nobody&amp;rsquo;s talking about: there is no real risk model in play for brokers. 😬
Regulations allow up to 5X leverage (20% margin) on many stocks. Competition forces every broker to offer maximum permissible leverage. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, you lose business. Classic race to the bottom.
Unlike F&amp;amp;O, MTF has several risk multipliers: Clients hold positions for months vs days 1,300 stocks (many illiquid) allowed vs only the top 200 in F&amp;amp;O All buy positions vs two-way flow in F&amp;amp;O, making risk management much harder Much harder to manage risk, given all the above.</description></item><item><title>Commodity markets look very different today</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/commodity-markets-look-very-different-today/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/commodity-markets-look-very-different-today/</guid><description>Up until a few years ago, commodity trading was more or less an afterthought. Most traders didn&amp;rsquo;t bother with it because liquidity was thin relative to NSE F&amp;amp;O.
But that&amp;rsquo;s changed dramatically, thanks to the spectacular rally in gold and silver. If you look at gold and silver as a percentage of total MCX trading volumes today, the numbers are kind of crazy. A lot of this increase has come at the expense of other commodities like crude.</description></item><item><title>Inspiration from Tata Mumbai Marathon</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/inspiration-from-tata-mumbai-marathon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/inspiration-from-tata-mumbai-marathon/</guid><description>The excitement and enthusiasm among people with disabilities running the Tata Mumbai Marathon today were beyond words. Makes you think about what right you have to complain about anything in life.
On a personal note, Seema ran 10km in ~57 minutes, about 2.5 years after surviving cancer. 😃</description></item><item><title>If you want to build something, India has never offered better odds</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/if-you-want-to-build-something-india-has-never-offered-better-odds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/if-you-want-to-build-something-india-has-never-offered-better-odds/</guid><description>There’s a lot of pessimism about India’s growth prospects right now, amplified by the sheer amount of geopolitical drama we’re living through. But if we aren’t hopeful that India will do better, then everything becomes moot.
This isn’t to say we don’t have real problems. We do. But every successful country has had to deal with its own share of thorny challenges along its development path. What matters is how we respond.</description></item><item><title>Why a local election shuts India’s markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-a-local-election-shuts-indias-markets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-a-local-election-shuts-indias-markets/</guid><description>Indian stock exchanges are closed today for Mumbai’s municipal elections.
The fact that our exchanges, which have international linkages, are shut down for a local municipal election shows poor planning and a serious lack of appreciation for second-order effects.
As Munger said: “Show me the incentive, and I will show you the outcome.”
The holiday exists because no one who matters has any incentive to oppose the market holiday.
It also tells you how far we have to go before global investors take us seriously.</description></item><item><title>Financial literacy helped these women break free from debt</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-literacy-helped-these-women-break-free-from-debt/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-literacy-helped-these-women-break-free-from-debt/</guid><description>Two years ago, we met a group of women in Chikkodi, Belgaum. Many were in debt. Some had never thought about savings or budgeting. We spent 2 days together learning the basics of financial literacy through Varsity with the help of Svatah Foundation and Pankh India.
But instead of stopping there, we kept in touch and continued helping them for 2 years. Today, most of these women are debt-free. For someone from a low-income background, that&amp;rsquo;s true financial independence.</description></item><item><title>Check IPO lock-in period expiry on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-ipo-lock-in-period-expiry-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-ipo-lock-in-period-expiry-on-kite/</guid><description>When a company goes for an IPO, not all shareholders can sell their shares immediately. Certain categories of shareholders like promoters, early investors and ESOP holders have to wait anywhere between 30 days to 18 months before they can sell their shares.
Since these are large shareholders, whenever they sell, there can often be a downward move in the stock price. So if you are buying shares of companies that IPO&amp;rsquo;d recently, you should track when the lock-in period expires.</description></item><item><title>The broking business has a hard growth ceiling</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-broking-business-has-a-hard-growth-ceiling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-broking-business-has-a-hard-growth-ceiling/</guid><description>Broking is a unique business because there&amp;rsquo;s a hard ceiling on how much we can grow and the rate at which we can grow. What most people don&amp;rsquo;t realise is that SEBI has set a 15% open interest (OI) cap at the broker level.
No single broker can hold more than 15% of the total market OI. This restriction exists to mitigate the risk of concentration from any single broker becoming too large.</description></item><item><title>Open-source projects from Zerodha Tech team</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-projects-from-zerodha-tech-team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-projects-from-zerodha-tech-team/</guid><description>The number of full-fledged Free and open-source software (FOSS) products and initiatives coming out of the 4th Phase, JP Nagar (Zerodha Tech), must be unprecedented for a team of its size globally.
All of these projects started as a way to solve problems we faced internally and were then open sourced. We use them at scale in our stack, and several large organisations and even government departments globally use many of these tools today.</description></item><item><title>A year of MTF launch and product growth</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-year-of-mtf-launch-and-product-growth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-year-of-mtf-launch-and-product-growth/</guid><description>We launched our MTF product a year ago. Despite being one of the last brokers to offer this and without actively promoting it on the order screen or elsewhere, we captured ~5% of the market. But growth has plateaued along with the broader industry.
One surprising thing I have noticed is that customers don&amp;rsquo;t seem to care about MTF brokerage or know what they&amp;rsquo;re being charged. Our current brokerage is 0.</description></item><item><title>Interoperability on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/interoperability-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/interoperability-on-kite/</guid><description>A feature that many people are unaware of.
You can buy a stock for intraday on NSE and sell it on BSE (or vice versa) to capture arbitrage opportunities if you spot any. Just select the exit exchange from your positions page. Margins get released immediately.
And it can be done regardless of whether you are trading for intraday or holding a stock.</description></item></channel></rss>