<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Musings on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Musings on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A trading algo is as good as the person that wrote it</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-money-with-algos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-money-with-algos/</guid><description>I keep hearing often that algo traders are super profitable, which by the way isn’t true. While an algo doesn&amp;rsquo;t have emotions, it is only as good as the person who wrote it or controls (start &amp;amp; stop) it—the same person who&amp;rsquo;s riddled with fear and greed.
Every algo like any trader, strategy or stock, has ups &amp;amp; downs. Just like impatient discretionary traders constantly try to time entry &amp;amp; exit, getting in late &amp;amp; out early, trade against trends, the same happens with algo traders trying to constantly find the best algo as well.</description></item><item><title>Algo trading platforms and regulations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/algo-trading-platforms-and-regulations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/algo-trading-platforms-and-regulations/</guid><description>Algo trading platforms are becoming popular of late, many of them claim to make you quick &amp;amp; easy money. We thought it&amp;rsquo;s a good time to highlight the risks, regulations, difference b/w APIs &amp;amp; Algos, &amp;amp; the fact that we&amp;rsquo;ve no partnerships with these platforms</description></item><item><title>Organic farming</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/adoption-of-organic-farming/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/adoption-of-organic-farming/</guid><description>I keep asking everyone who’s adopted organic farming if yields drop after they stopped using chemicals. In a world where short term gains trump long term improvements, it&amp;rsquo;s tough to see how the shift to organic — even if good for the planet, would happen if yields are lower
In May, Sri Lanka banned chemical fertiliser and pesticides &amp;amp; went fully organic. There&amp;rsquo;s been an uproar over this move. Some people and groups have even blamed this move for the food crisis there.</description></item><item><title>In-Principle approval for our AMC</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/valuations-of-global-brokerages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/valuations-of-global-brokerages/</guid><description>I am pessimistic about the valuations of brokerages around the world, including that of Zerodha. This is because the performance of broking is directly tied to market performance. If people aren’t making money or there is no greed, activity usually drops off a cliff.
The best tech, products &amp;amp; low pricing won&amp;rsquo;t help.
A new report from JP Morgan on Robinhood (RH) said that app downloads are down by 78% QOQ and active users by 40% QOQ.</description></item><item><title>FOSS (Free &amp; Open Source Software) at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/foss-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/foss-at-zerodha/</guid><description>We use Listmonk built by our very own Dr K Smiling face with open mouth, to send 30mil emails/month at ~$200. It would have cost us tens of 000&amp;rsquo;s $/month otherwise. One of the main reasons for our high margins, profitability, &amp;amp; hence ability to bootstrap is because almost everything we use is FOSS.
K &amp;amp; our tech team also contribute back to FOSS (Free &amp;amp; Open Source Software) significantly. K built Listmonk as a hobby project to solve our email problems.</description></item><item><title>Illiquidity premium</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/illquidity-and-the-temptation-of-selling-quick/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/illquidity-and-the-temptation-of-selling-quick/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve asked a lot of successful MF, PE &amp;amp; VC managers if they would be able to resist the temptation to time the market and hold on to profitable investments if they could easily exit &amp;amp; enter investments like retail investors. The answer is almost always &amp;ldquo;hmm&amp;hellip; probably, not&amp;rdquo;.
The inability to time the market due to size constraints &amp;amp; illiquidity—especially in private markets forces fund managers to follow the fundamental investing rule—letting your winners run.</description></item><item><title>Online nomination and dormant account alerts</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/online-nomination/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/online-nomination/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s at least Rs 80,000 crores of unclaimed money across Banks, Mutual funds, Demats, &amp;amp; more.
We are hoping this alert feature which notifies nominees when accounts become dormant &amp;amp; they don&amp;rsquo;t reKYC, can help in solving this problem.
Hopefully, the Banks &amp;amp; others follow.</description></item><item><title>Who can disrupt new-age online brokers or even exchanges?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/who-can-disrupt-brokers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/who-can-disrupt-brokers/</guid><description>I get asked often, who out there do you think can disrupt the new-age online brokers or even exchanges? Me: I don’t think it will be another stock brokerage firm or a new stock exchange. It will most likely be an outsider, maybe Crypto. Here is why.
In broking or exchange business, both on pricing and product, there is not much left to disrupt. Unless of course, someone figures a way to pay people money for trading (-ve brokerage not allowed by regulation) or figures a way to help all customers make money (very tough)</description></item><item><title>Partnership with Organic Mandya</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/partnership-with-organic-mandya/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/partnership-with-organic-mandya/</guid><description>Our focus at Rainmatter foundation is to help create green jobs, livelihoods &amp;amp; help preserve the environment using sustainable agri practices. In that journey, we&amp;rsquo;re super delighted to join Madhu Chandan &amp;amp; Organic Mandya on their mission to change farming &amp;amp; improve lives of farmers.
Organic Mandya has helped create kitchen gardens with fruit tree saplings in 5,000+ homes. Through Sunday Santhes in Mandya, they&amp;rsquo;re creating direct farmer to consumer relationships.</description></item><item><title>In-Principle approval for our AMC</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/in-principle-approval-for-our-amc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/in-principle-approval-for-our-amc/</guid><description>So, we just got our in-principle approval for our AMC (MF) license. I guess now comes the hard part.</description></item><item><title>Get fit challenge at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/get-fit-challenge-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/get-fit-challenge-at-zerodha/</guid><description>Post the first lockdown, like everywhere, our team Zerodha as a whole was probably the unhealthiest ever, due to the lack of physical activity, work-life imbalance, bad diet, &amp;amp; more. We thought of a way to nudge the team to get healthy and the results are phenomenal.
On our internal @discourse forum, we asked everyone to set a 12-month get-healthy goal &amp;amp; update the progress every month, to create accountability. To increase participation, we said everyone who reaches the goal will get a 1-month salary as bonus &amp;amp; 1 lucky draw for Rs 10lks.</description></item><item><title>Freak trades in options</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/freak-trades-in-futures-and-options/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/freak-trades-in-futures-and-options/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve been getting a lot of questions about freak trades in options with huge slippages recently. Here is everything you need to know, why you should use limit orders, &amp;amp; how Zerodha internal dynamic execution range will help you avoid such scenarios.</description></item><item><title>Meet zero</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/featuring-zero/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/featuring-zero/</guid><description>Zero&amp;rsquo;s featured 😍 She sits in on all meetings at Zerodha from regulatory to tech to everything else, quietly assimilating. I&amp;rsquo;ve had dreams, where I come to the office and Zero says &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m the CEO, you can leave now.&amp;ldquo;😬</description></item><item><title>Zerodha's 11th birthday.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-turns-eleven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-turns-eleven/</guid><description>Happy Independence day 🇮🇳. Coincidentally it&amp;rsquo;s Zerodha&amp;rsquo;s 11th birthday today too.😀 If I were to look back, we are most proud of building a business that continues to innovate, &amp;amp; prioritise customer interest over business growth constantly.
We&amp;rsquo;re also proud of the part we continue to play in growing the capital market ecosystem in India through Rainmatterin and give back to society through our foundation RainmatterOrg.
There&amp;rsquo;s plenty for us to get better at, especially around our support.</description></item><item><title>Financial freedom.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-freedom/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-freedom/</guid><description>Financial freedom isn’t X amount. Luxuries soon become necessities, X constantly grows. In a world where everyone is triggering you to borrow &amp;amp; buy what you don’t need, being content &amp;amp; debt-free is true financial freedom. Common sense stuff, rarely said.</description></item><item><title>Scaling with common sense</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scaling-with-commonsense/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scaling-with-commonsense/</guid><description>If there was ever a person who&amp;rsquo;s had a strong influence on me, it&amp;rsquo;s K (Kailash), the secret sauce behind Zerodha. He just published this post which is more than just tech, a must-read for anyone building or aspiring to build a business or a product.</description></item><item><title>Podcast with vasanth, Rohan and Anugrah of smallcase.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-podcast-smallcase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-podcast-smallcase/</guid><description>It was in 2016 when Vasanth, Anugrah, and Rohan pitched smallcase. We were quickly sold on their idea of getting users to invest in diversified baskets of stocks or ideas they understood vs single stocks, which reduced their risk.
We had just opened up Kite APIs. The idea was to enable startups to build platforms that could grow the shallow Indian capital market ecosystem.
Today, they&amp;rsquo;ve built an amazing ecosystem of products.</description></item><item><title>My favorite song</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-favourite-song/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-favourite-song/</guid><description>I got asked what my favourite song of all time was. So I decided to sing &amp;amp; share it. Peak WFH!</description></item><item><title>I've stopped giving random gifts. Only been gifting stocks &amp; ETFs for a while now.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-gift-you-can-give/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-gift-you-can-give/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve stopped giving random gifts. Only been gifting stocks &amp;amp; ETFs for a while now. Don&amp;rsquo;t have to waste hours choosing the right gift and the best bit: several of my family &amp;amp; friends have started investing because of this.
The only challenge now is with convincing the wife that Sovereign Gold bonds is the best form of gold on her birthday.</description></item><item><title>How will the broking industry perform next few years? This is a question I get asked often, more recently.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-will-the-broking-industry-perform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-will-the-broking-industry-perform/</guid><description>How will the broking industry perform next few years? This is a question I get asked often, more recently. I usually say, if you can tell me the Nifty direction or volatility, I can tell you what the broking industry will do. Because both are positively correlated.
User growth depends on whether the markets (Nifty) go up or not. It took &amp;gt;10 years to reach the high made in 2008 in terms of new user addition (total NSDL + CDSL Demat).</description></item><item><title>Almost 20% of all Zomato applications are through Zerodha.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zomato-ipo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zomato-ipo/</guid><description>Almost 20% of all Zomato applications are through Zerodha. Deepinder, returning the favour from everyone at Zerodha for all the tasty food Zomato delivered when we were hungry. Face savouring food Wishing you and the team at Zomato a blockbuster listing.</description></item><item><title>The last 18 months at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/user-growth-in-the-last-18-months/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/user-growth-in-the-last-18-months/</guid><description>The last 18 months at Zerodha have been eventful, to say the least. Historically, market crashes caused panic &amp;amp; reduced activity. But this crisis led to a rush of new customers looking to buy into stocks on sale. Free time due to lockdowns &amp;amp; low bank deposit rates helped.
Once this younger bunch of first-time investors saw quick profits, they started spreading the word and got their friends &amp;amp; family to invest.</description></item><item><title>The risk for high growth B2C tech IPOs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/high-growth-tech-ipos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/high-growth-tech-ipos/</guid><description>The risk with all the high growth B2C tech IPOs coming up is growth plateauing. Growth is usually a function of agility &amp;amp; product bets. Since these companies take more bets &amp;amp; are more agile &amp;amp; aggressive than traditional businesses, they grow faster (Zerodha as well).
The question then, will the ability of these companies to be agile (reason for growth) reduce because of all the scrutiny that comes by being publicly listed?</description></item><item><title>Trading is more about managing fear, greed and psychology than entry/exit strategy.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/managing-fear-and-greed/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/managing-fear-and-greed/</guid><description>Trading is more about managing fear, greed and psychology than entry/exit strategy. This collection of newsletters by Marketwise on Zerodha Varsity is maybe the best out there on this topic.</description></item><item><title>Why look at notional contract value when buying options?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-look-at-notional-contract-value/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-look-at-notional-contract-value/</guid><description>Why look at notional contract value when buying options?
Yes, when you buy options the max you can lose is the premium you have paid. But to get a sense of risk and how fast or easily you can lose, you should look at the exposure or contract value, not the premium.
For eg, you have Rs 1L &amp;amp; you use it to buy 20 lots of Nifty calls = Rs 1.</description></item><item><title>Option buying - The riskiest trade</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/options-buying-the-riskiest-trade/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/options-buying-the-riskiest-trade/</guid><description>~80% of all open buy option positions at the end of every day are in losses.
Buying options ruins most retail traders. Because they don&amp;rsquo;t understand the risk of leverage, averaging down, &amp;amp; impact costs.
Here&amp;rsquo;s what we&amp;rsquo;re doing to help our users</description></item><item><title>Impact of trading costs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-trading-costs/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-trading-costs/</guid><description>What most traders don&amp;rsquo;t realize is that they pay a good chunk of their capital as costs. If you add impact costs, the minimum return an active trader should generate to break even yearly on their portfolio is usually well above 20%. Yep, that high and that tough.
Costs include Statutory costs like STT, Stamp duty, GST Impact costs or slippages (while this doesn’t even seem like a cost, it adds up quickly.</description></item><item><title>Introducing kill switch</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-kill-switch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-kill-switch/</guid><description>When you&amp;rsquo;re in a drawdown while trading, the best thing to do is to take a break. Otherwise, the chances of you being irrational, taking large bets, overtrading &amp;amp; blowing up are high. And to nudge you to do just that, we now have a “Kill Switch”.
Enabling the Kill switch will instantly disable trading. Currently, this is manual. But we are working on automating this where you can set a maximum loss.</description></item><item><title>Nudging users to help them avoid mistakes</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-users-to-help-them-avoid-mistakes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-users-to-help-them-avoid-mistakes/</guid><description>Most people don&amp;rsquo;t spend time learning trading or forget what they&amp;rsquo;ve learnt when placing an order. The order placement step is also when users pay maximum attention. With &amp;ldquo;Nudge&amp;rdquo; we are now able to leverage that fraction of a second to educate users &amp;amp; help them avoid mistakes.
This Nudge on DHFL warning customers that the investment may go to 0 discouraged over 50% of our users from taking a trade.</description></item><item><title>Introducing tags and trading journal on Console</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-tags-on-console/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-tags-on-console/</guid><description>We are stoked about the new tagging feature on Console. Tagging your trades and maintaining a trading journal can help you become a better trader and also help you track your investment goals.
You can&amp;rsquo;t become a better trader if you don&amp;rsquo;t learn from your mistakes. But in order to learn, you need a proper journal of all your trades and the reasons you took the trades. You can then look back, review, and do more of what is working &amp;amp; less of what isn&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>On the noise about our salaries</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-the-noise-about-our-salaries/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-the-noise-about-our-salaries/</guid><description>I’m surprised by the unwanted noise around this whole salary news of Nikhil, Seema (my wife), &amp;amp; me. The headlines are misleading. We are a private company &amp;amp; no obligations to clarify, but we thought maybe we should, as there are folks who are misinterpreting this.
Firstly the reported figure isn’t the actual salary being drawn. This is an enabling resolution that allows us as working promoters to draw salaries up to the number in case of liquidity requirements.</description></item><item><title>A few thoughts on the Zerodha journey so far</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-zerodha-journey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-zerodha-journey/</guid><description>Last 2 years have been spectacular for Zerodha . Lucky to be at right place right time, ready with products &amp;amp; initiatives when there was a surge in retail participation. With success, what I say gets valued more Grimacing faceHere are a few questions that we get asked frequently.
Why haven’t we raised any external capital, especially at times like these when we could get some crazy valuation? I had talked about it earlier</description></item><item><title>The biggest wealth destroyer when investing</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/biggest-wealth-destroyer-when-investing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/biggest-wealth-destroyer-when-investing/</guid><description>What is the biggest wealth destroyer when investing?
Averaging down or buying more of an asset, be it stock or crypto, as the price keeps going down and hoping that the price bounces to recover losses or make profits faster. Common behaviour among retail investors.
While it is tempting to average down, the odds of this strategy working are significantly low in the long run. All it takes is one large move on the other side for things to go wrong.</description></item><item><title>The risk of offering high leverages</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-of-offering-high-leverages/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-of-offering-high-leverages/</guid><description>When a platform offers leverage or funds the customer to buy for more than the money in the account, the platform takes a credit risk. With Crypto exchanges offering 10 to 100x leverage (futures), on days like today, I wonder who monitors liquidity position of these platforms.
In regulated space, even with all checks &amp;amp; balances, brokerage firms once in a while on days of extreme volatility go bust. If exchange offers 50x leverage &amp;amp; say Bitcoin goes down 4% in one tick, a customer with $1K, can lose $2K.</description></item><item><title>On the Panic With Friends podcast with Howard Lindzon</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/panic-with-friends-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/panic-with-friends-podcast/</guid><description>This was a really fun conversation with Howard.</description></item><item><title>Helping people take care of mental health during</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/taking-care-of-yourself/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/taking-care-of-yourself/</guid><description>While we figure ways to help those directly affected by Corona, I think it is also super important that all of us take care of ourselves. We thought we should do something to nudge as many as possible to take some action.</description></item><item><title>Worklife balance at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/worklife-balance-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/worklife-balance-at-zerodha/</guid><description>At Zerodha, we have just killed all work-related chats post 6 pm &amp;amp; holidays. Also trying to get as many conversations to be asynchronous, moving them from chat to our internal instance of Discourse. Curious to see if this helps reduce the feeling of burnt out &amp;amp; brain fried. Apparently, multitasking hurts performance and may even damage the brain (check the link below). Being part of multiple discussions on different topics in different chat groups simultaneously (Multitasking) has gone up exponentially post WFH.</description></item><item><title>The pandemic has shown us it's the right time to move away from cities</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/moving-away-from-large-cities/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/moving-away-from-large-cities/</guid><description>While we all work together to figure out what we can do to help in the current situation, I think the only long-term fix is for as many of us to move away from large cities. This is the answer to many of India’s problems. And now is probably the right time to work towards it.
Large cities are choking &amp;amp; will continue to break down every time we&amp;rsquo;re tested, COVID today, could be water shortages, pollution, floods, etc.</description></item><item><title>Why FOSS?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-foss/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-foss/</guid><description>Every time we share a post on the Zerodha tech blog, we get a lot of love from the tech community, but also questions like - Why FOSS? Why be so transparent? No security concerns sharing all this info? So yeah, answers from the man behind the scene - Dr. K
Why Free &amp;amp; Open source software?
Superior utility: Pretty much everything in the known universe uses FOSS, from the Mars rovers to our phones to washing machines.</description></item><item><title>Why doesn't Zerodha advertise?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-doesnt-zerodha-advertise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-doesnt-zerodha-advertise/</guid><description>One thing I get asked the most and I’ve tweeted about this numerous times is that why don’t we advertise. Firstly I&amp;rsquo;d shared this sometime back.
Unlike buying a mobile phone or ordering a pizza, you don&amp;rsquo;t invest in stocks &amp;amp; MFs impulsively. Most often than not, we invest because of greed or because of our friends. And regulations don&amp;rsquo;t allow you to advertise greed.
Ads do help you create visibility and build credibility - two really important things in the business of money, especially the first few years.</description></item><item><title>Podcast with Prateek Singh, the founder of LearnApp</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-with-prateek-learnapp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-with-prateek-learnapp/</guid><description>From the start at Zerodha, we&amp;rsquo;ve constantly shared things to educate people about the capital markets. Zerodha Varsity was our first formal attempt in text. But we knew that video was also important, &amp;amp; that people trust content delivered by experts.
This was the reason behind partnering with LearnApp through Rainmatter. The amazing bit in the journey has been that some of the best folks in our industry have been incredibly generous with their time to share their knowledge with no expectations.</description></item><item><title>Why you shouldn't raise money just because you can</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stupidest-time-for-fintech-firms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stupidest-time-for-fintech-firms/</guid><description>Right now, is probably the stupidest time for fintech firms like @zerodhaonline to be raising money. It is quite crazy the number of folks reaching out &amp;amp; the different deals. We might regret it in the future, but we are not raising &amp;amp; here are the counterintuitive reasons why.
We don’t need the money, so there’s no point in raising money just because someone is ready to give it to you.</description></item><item><title>Risks of running a brokerage firm</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risks-of-running-a-brokerage-firm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risks-of-running-a-brokerage-firm/</guid><description>The big news from last week was the blow-up of a leveraged hedge fund Archegos &amp;amp; how it caused $billions in losses to its bank/broker. A primer to what it means to be a brokerage for such trades, the risk to reward, and more.
Being a broker is almost like running an insurance business, you keep earning brokerage income (like premium) &amp;amp; are always one black swan or mega volatile day away from giving it all back and more if one large client or many small clients default at the same time.</description></item><item><title>Mis-selling is a systemic issue.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/misselling-is-a-systemic-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/misselling-is-a-systemic-issues/</guid><description>This is a more systemic issue, not with one bank but across the board, banks to ed-tech to fintech. As long as you give revenue targets &amp;amp; push employees to get there, products that generate more revenue for the business over what is right for the customer will be mis-sold.
Easier for employees of banks, brokerages, wealth management firms to mis-sell as relationships are already established &amp;amp; there is trust with the brand, which is why the customer has allowed them to be custodians of their assets.</description></item><item><title>How to know when odds are higher?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-to-know-when-odds-are-higher/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-to-know-when-odds-are-higher/</guid><description>Got a few questions about this tweet. How to know when odds are higher? The decision to trade should have multiple checkboxes, can’t just be one. Size has to be based on how many checkboxes a bet ticks. And this rule I think holds good not just for trading, but investing, business, &amp;amp; life. Let me explain.
Say your strategy is to buy or sell a stock every time price crosses a Moving Avg.</description></item><item><title>Market size estimates</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/maket-size-estimates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/maket-size-estimates/</guid><description>Market size estimate (Revenue), from the two reports that I just read. Stockbroking: ~$3billion according to ICRA. Gold loan: ~$162billion according to MorningContext.</description></item><item><title>a career highpoint</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-career-highpoint/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-career-highpoint/</guid><description>Dad&amp;rsquo;s first time on screen. Seeing him so proud is a career highpoint. Super lucky to have parents who stood by through all my stupidity regardless of what people told them, that&amp;rsquo;s how I survived. Until Zerodha, I was always told to go get a real job.</description></item><item><title>CNBC India business leader award</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cnbc-india-business-leader-awards/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cnbc-india-business-leader-awards/</guid><description>2014: CNBC Young Turks, our first time on TV 2021: CNBC India business leader awards Some year 2020 has been for Zerodha &amp;amp; the capital markets. The challenge though is to help clients avoid making trading mistakes. We are attempting with Nudge &amp;amp; Zerodha Varsity.</description></item><item><title>A nudge to stop people from losing money in Rights Entitlements</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudge-to-stop-people-from-losing-money-in-rights-entitlements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudge-to-stop-people-from-losing-money-in-rights-entitlements/</guid><description>Many retail investors buy Rights Entitlements (REs) without knowing that the value of REs will be zero if they don&amp;rsquo;t apply. Since May 2020 our clients have lost ~Rs 10cr by buying Rights entitlements &amp;amp; not applying. We now have a nudge to warn customers. Read about it here.</description></item><item><title>My view on reduction of intraday leverages</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-view-on-reduction-of-intraday-leverages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-view-on-reduction-of-intraday-leverages/</guid><description>My view on the reduction of intraday leverages is that there will be near-term pain (for Zerodha too). We&amp;rsquo;ll see a drop in trading volumes and an increase in impact cost. But in the long term, more traders will survive &amp;amp; hopefully make up for the dip.
There is an argument to be made for lesser intraday margins. VAR+ELM or SPAN+Exposure margin calculation is based on risk/volatility. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t differentiate between intraday &amp;amp; overnight risk, or that intraday is less risky and hence ideally requires lesser margins.</description></item><item><title>Trading with other people’s money</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trading-with-other-peoples-money/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trading-with-other-peoples-money/</guid><description>Managing other people&amp;rsquo;s money in ways that aren&amp;rsquo;t allowed leads to the most complaints with the regulators. There are ways to do it legally, and those that can incur significant penalties. Here&amp;rsquo;s all that you need to know about managing money. https://zerodha.com/z-connect/traders-zone/trading-with-other-peoples-money</description></item><item><title>Enabling women to start making financial decisions</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/enabling-women-to-start-making-financial-decisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/enabling-women-to-start-making-financial-decisions/</guid><description>This video from Paytm captures what we need to do most as a country - educate &amp;amp; enable as many women as possible to start making financial decisions. In my personal experience, women manage risk better than men, so they&amp;rsquo;ll probably take better financial decisions #womensday2021</description></item><item><title>Making taxes easy with Vishvajit Sonagara of Quicko</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-taxes-easy-with-vishvajit-sonagara-of-quicko/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-taxes-easy-with-vishvajit-sonagara-of-quicko/</guid><description>A misconception among traders is that you need to file ITR only if you make a profit. Many also don&amp;rsquo;t file since it&amp;rsquo;s quite complex, but Quicko has simplified it drastically. In our new Rainmatter podcast I talk to Vishvajit on their journey.</description></item><item><title>Spending on brand name keywords</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/should-you-spend-on-brand-name-keywords/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/should-you-spend-on-brand-name-keywords/</guid><description>The only time we ran Google ads was when our competition ran ads when people searched for Zerodha. We ran ads against &amp;ldquo;zerodha(.)competition(.)com&amp;rdquo;. Our lamest expenditure to date. Hoping this order is a precedent &amp;amp; helps startups save on unnecessary costs</description></item><item><title>Yearly demat account growth for the last 20 years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/yearly-demat-account-growth-for-20-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/yearly-demat-account-growth-for-20-years/</guid><description>Consider the yearly demat addition for the last 20yrs. Stockbroking is as high beta as it can get. When someone asks for my view on the future, I usually ask them for their view on Nifty. The last boom &amp;amp; bust was in 2007-08, took 10 yrs to get back to those numbers. A high beta business is one that has a higher sensitivity to the market (Nifty). If Nifty does well, business outperforms the market by a fair bit, and if Nifty doesn&amp;rsquo;t, it underperforms the market by a fair bit.</description></item><item><title>How big was Jan 2021 for the broking industry?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-big-was-jan-2021-for-broking/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-big-was-jan-2021-for-broking/</guid><description>How big was Jan 2021 for the broking industry? The best year for the markets since 2010 was by far 2014. Nifty was up more than 30% and the industry added 13 lakh new Demat accounts in 1 year. And, Jan 2021, just in 1 month 17 lakh new Demat accounts were added. Water buffaloGrimacing face</description></item><item><title>Being at the right place at right time and surviving</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/right-place-right-time-survival/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/right-place-right-time-survival/</guid><description>Right place right timeSmiling face with open mouthBut damn it&amp;rsquo;s tough to survive &amp;amp; be there when it matters. Zerodha probably started when I started trading 15 years before 2010. It&amp;rsquo;s been 25 years of ups &amp;amp; many downs, almost gave up many times. If it works out you are called passionate, if not foolish.</description></item><item><title>Podcast - Nikhil Kamath on The Ranveer Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nik-on-the-ranveer-show/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nik-on-the-ranveer-show/</guid><description>Keeping your emotions in check is the most important skill as a trader. The Bro @nikhilkamathcio is a master at this. He&amp;rsquo;s never missed a trading day in last 15 yrs &amp;amp; I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen him react to P&amp;amp;L. Nik on his journey with the very sharp @BeerBicepsGuy</description></item><item><title>The Gamestop saga and lessons for retail investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</guid><description>In the Gamestop saga, the media has loved telling the story of how Retail made a lot of money from Hedge funds. The reality is entirely different, almost everyone apart from retail has probably made money or benefited from this.
Firstly, yes, a couple of Hedge funds were sitting on large losses on Gamestop shorts. Now that stock is at $50, the losses also would be a fraction, if the shorts still held.</description></item><item><title>Rising financial awareness among Indians</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</guid><description>Financial awareness about the importance of saving and investing in India is increasing at the fastest rate ever, especially among millennials. Of course, stock markets doing well and lower bank FD rates are helping. But there are also a few structural changes afoot here. Historically financial products have been sold hard &amp;amp; mostly in person. Products mostly sold based on promises of high returns (sales pitches in person leave no audit trail).</description></item><item><title>Free &amp; open-source software (FOSS) — one of the reasons behind Zerodha's success</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/foss-the-reason-for-zerodhas-success/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/foss-the-reason-for-zerodhas-success/</guid><description>Free &amp;amp; open-source software (FOSS) is the main reason for the success of Zerodha as K writes.
https://nadh.in/blog/the-atmanirbhartha-of-open-source-software</description></item><item><title>Shorting and Indian Capital Markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</guid><description>Can retail traders are cause a “short squeeze” in India like they did in stocks like GameStop and AMC entertainment in the US? It cannot, and I explain why in this post. Join the discussion here.</description></item><item><title>Beyond misleading trading turnover numbers — the actual size of Indian capital markets?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beyond-misleading-trading-turnover-numbers-the-actual-size-of-indian-capital-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beyond-misleading-trading-turnover-numbers-the-actual-size-of-indian-capital-markets/</guid><description>Looking at trading turnover to estimate capital market size is misleading. Most trades are leveraged &amp;amp; ideally we should look at the margins being traded, not the trade value. Turnover this way will be less than 10% of the trading turnover declared.
The best way to estimate the size of the Indian capital markets is by checking the revenue pool. This I think, is less than Rs 50k crores across 1500+ brokers, exchanges, &amp;amp; depositories.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-rainmatter-foundation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-rainmatter-foundation/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The fallacy of predictions</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-fallacy-of-predictions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-fallacy-of-predictions/</guid><description>Even after all my years of experience, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more wrong in predicting the direction of our business in 2020. These expert predictions should be taken with a pinch of salt, most of times the odds are equal to tossing a coin.</description></item><item><title>Is trading the markets gambling?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-trading-the-markets-gambling/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-trading-the-markets-gambling/</guid><description>Is trading the markets gambling? I get asked often. My answer is that yes, you can gamble when trading, just like you can gamble with everything else in life.</description></item><item><title>The twisted world of illegal CFDs &amp; binary options</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Total addressable market for brokers</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/total-addressable-market-for-brokers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/total-addressable-market-for-brokers/</guid><description>Since broking is hot post-COVID, inspite of all the spike in trading volumes and activity, the total addressable market is just ~1.5 million users. I had shared this pre-Covid. Broking is super hot now, but this TAM (Total addressable market) hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed, if anything it has reduced. Btw, the revenue-generating active day traders + F&amp;amp;O crowd is not more than ~1.5mil in spite of the spike in trading activity/volumes. This active crowd is unlikely to go up because most day and F&amp;amp;O traders stop within 6 months.</description></item><item><title>Robinhood pays $65M to settle SEC charges on payment for order flow disclosures</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-pays-65m-to-settle-sec-charges-on-for/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-pays-65m-to-settle-sec-charges-on-for/</guid><description>The Robinhood SEC settlement over order flow disclosures grabbed some headlines even in India. Since people might be wondering if this happens here, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. Unlike the US, all order in India are matched and executed on the exchanges. We have no concept of order flow here.</description></item><item><title>Why advertising doesn't work</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-advertising-doesnt-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-advertising-doesnt-work/</guid><description>https://freakonomics.com/podcast/advertising-part-2/ This is a great listen from Freakonomics on whether advertising works. The reason we could bootstrap was that we never spent on ads. With no ads, a business is forced to constantly think &amp;amp; do things to get customer love and organic growth. The only time we experimented with ads was for our brand keyword, show our website if you search &amp;ldquo;Zerodha&amp;rdquo;. We stopped immediately when we realized that it made no difference to the traffic and the ad was essentially cannibalizing our organic traffic while costing us money.</description></item><item><title>Podcast: Sandeep Parekh on the evolution of the Indian market and securities regulations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-sandeep-parekh-on-the-evolution-of-the-and/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-sandeep-parekh-on-the-evolution-of-the-and/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EihRbTTLLy0&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be This is a must-watch for those interested in the Indian securities market. @SandeepParekh we need to find a way to get you to do more of this. :)</description></item><item><title>A product to get more Indians to save and invest</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</guid><description>To get the next 10 crore Indians, the traditional financial product might not work. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I think is needed to get these people to start saving and investing.</description></item><item><title>Does Illiquidty like in private markets lead to good investor behavior?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-illiquidty-like-in-private-markets-lead-to/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-illiquidty-like-in-private-markets-lead-to/</guid><description>A question I have been asking institutional investors in both private and public markets is - if they could enter and exit their holdings at will like retail investors(which they cannot today), would they have actually sat through the ride of their best-performing holdings? The answer usually is no. As counterintuitive as it sounds, maybe the inability to easily enter/exit large public or illiquid private holdings forces fund managers to sit tight, which is also why they can outperform retail investors who are always trying to time the market.</description></item><item><title>The flipside of effecient companies</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-flipside-of-effecient-companies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-flipside-of-effecient-companies/</guid><description>https://zenx.medium.com/the-six-dots-problem-re-imagining-india-b7d81b223827 The flip side of tech-first businesses like ours is that we don&amp;rsquo;t create as many jobs. We are around the same number of employees today at 3.8mn clients as we were when we had 1mn clients. As @kunalb11 says, inefficiency is the biggest employer in the world. A way to solve this employment problem is to enable jobs(economy) not just in the top 6 cities, but maybe 600 towns/villages. The only +ve this year has been that maybe some it is happening.</description></item><item><title>Why Zerodha with Nithin</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-with-nithin/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-with-nithin/</guid><description>Me answering the most frequently asked question aroung why Zerodha is the broker for you.</description></item><item><title>Downside of working from home</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/downside-of-working-from-home/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/downside-of-working-from-home/</guid><description>This year has been ridiculous, I now have &amp;ldquo;spending time with my 5-year-old son&amp;rdquo; scheduled on my calendar. WTF! I was wondering if I was the only insane one until I read this article. https://moretothat.com/the-omnipresence-of-work &amp;ldquo;We are now living amidst the omnipresence of work. Even if we aren’t sitting down working, we are prone to continue thinking about it since the physical environment no longer reminds us to shift our mind state.</description></item><item><title>Forbes cover</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/forbes-cover/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/forbes-cover/</guid><description>https://tradingqna.com/t/personal-lessons-from-20-years-of-trading-broking-working/94600
Almost unreal that we could represent Zerodha on the cover of Forbes. Some personal lessons from the many highs &amp;amp; many lows in this 20-year journey working, trading, trying to build different types of businesses, &amp;amp; more.
Businesses can be built in multiple ways. Don&amp;rsquo;t try to cut-copy-paste what others are doing - it mostly won’t work. Do what feels right to you. Your instincts on what is right will work better when you build a business/career around what you love.</description></item><item><title>The real hockey stick growth worth chasing</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-real-hockey-stick-growth-worth-chasing/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-real-hockey-stick-growth-worth-chasing/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;The real hockey curve growth we all need to be chasing - seeds (maybe not companies)&amp;quot;. @zenx said while handing over these 50 odd seeds. Seeds that can turn into trees, and in turn result in many more seeds and trees, providing for food and helping the planet for 100&amp;rsquo;s of years.</description></item><item><title>Does technical analysis work?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-technical-analysis-work/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-technical-analysis-work/</guid><description>Am often asked if Technical Analysis actually works. Firstly, there&amp;rsquo;s nothing that just &amp;ldquo;works&amp;rdquo; in trading. But TA works well for retail as it doesn&amp;rsquo;t let you trade against the trend &amp;amp; defines stoploss every trade - main reasons for retail traders&amp;rsquo; losses.</description></item><item><title>CRED curious: Nithin Kamath in conversation with Kunal Shah</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cred-curious-nithin-kamath-in-conversation-with/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cred-curious-nithin-kamath-in-conversation-with/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nudging people towards doing the right things</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-people-towards-doing-the-right-things/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-people-towards-doing-the-right-things/</guid><description>The penny stock Nudge introduced in March on Kite has helped us reduce penny stock trading volume significantly. It has given us hope that the bunch of new nudges we are working on will help our customers stay away from bad trading behavior.</description></item><item><title>The best way of investing in gold</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-of-investing-in-gold/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-best-way-of-investing-in-gold/</guid><description>https://tradingqna.com/t/whats-the-best-option-to-invest-in-gold/93314 Seems like everyone is selling digital gold. On digital gold, you lose 3% as GST, upto 2% in commissions, &amp;amp; a spread &amp;gt;5% (buy-sell difference). If you are looking at gold as an investment, Sovereign gold bonds followed by Gold ETF/MFs are the best option.</description></item><item><title>Sitting on a profitable trade is harder than sitting on a loss making trade</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sitting-on-a-profitable-trade-is-harder-than-on-a/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sitting-on-a-profitable-trade-is-harder-than-on-a/</guid><description>Contrary to what most people think, it is much tougher to sit on a profitable trade vs loss-making. All decent traders have a defined stop to handle losing trades. When on profit, we all know we have to let our winners run, but all our biases constantly push us to book profits.</description></item><item><title>Evolution of the Indian stock broking industry since the Harshad Mehta scam - Scam92 TV Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/evolution-of-the-indian-stock-broking-industry-the/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/evolution-of-the-indian-stock-broking-industry-the/</guid><description>#Scam1992TheHarshadMehtaStory - a thread on everything that has changed since then in the world of Indian stockbroking.
Today the settlement cycle is 2 days &amp;amp; SEBI is hinting at a 1-day cycle soon (first few countries in the world). Back then, it was 14 days (the time within which you have to pay full money and take delivery of stocks or deliver stocks if sold).
Today, a customer can’t buy stocks without the minimum money in the account or sell without stocks in Demat.</description></item><item><title>Generalists vs specialists</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/generalists-vs-specialists/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/generalists-vs-specialists/</guid><description>My view on Generalist vs Specialist? Being a jack of all trades helps you grow intellectually &amp;amp; increases odds of finding what you love. But as a business, I think going after one problem(What u love &amp;amp; Core competency) has a much higher chance of success than to spray &amp;amp; hope.</description></item><item><title>Sense of time post-COVID</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sense-of-time-post-covid/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sense-of-time-post-covid/</guid><description>https://behavioralscientist.org/time-confetti-and-the-broken-promise-of-leisure Have been wondering why the post-COVID world seems more Busy-ness than Business. This article explains why beautifully - &amp;ldquo;We have more time for leisure than we did fifty years ago. But leisure has never been less relaxing&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Nikhil and Me on SNFConversations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nikhil-and-me-on-snfconversations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nikhil-and-me-on-snfconversations/</guid><description>They say it is tough to be in business with family. @kamath_nikhil &amp;amp; I have been doing stuff together forever, never a fight &amp;amp; couldn&amp;rsquo;t have had a better partner. Btw, it helps when you are like the role modelWinking face. Weirdly first time together on an interview https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oiC-CuyUAK4&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be</description></item><item><title>Nikhil Kamath &amp; Nithin Kamath, Founders of Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nikhil-kamath-nithin-kamath-founders-of-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nikhil-kamath-nithin-kamath-founders-of-zerodha/</guid><description/></item><item><title>ESOP buyback - one of the highlights of the Zerodha journey</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/esop-buyback-one-of-the-highlights-of-the-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/esop-buyback-one-of-the-highlights-of-the-zerodha/</guid><description>We just provided liquidity to everyone on the team through an ESOP buyback. My most satisfying day as CEO of @zerodhaonline .</description></item><item><title>Has there been a surge in investors from tier 2 and 3 cities?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/has-there-been-a-surge-in-investors-from-tier-2-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/has-there-been-a-surge-in-investors-from-tier-2-3/</guid><description>The reason for the noise around markets growing in tier 2/3 cities is because everyone tracks users based on address proof. Lot of people migrate from small towns to cities for jobs but address proof remains the same, hence misleading. By IP address for us: 75% from top 20 cities. Everyone = Financial services firms Map= Google analytics</description></item><item><title>On Zerodha IPO</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-zerodha-ipo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-zerodha-ipo/</guid><description>Thanks for the love @rajeshsawhney , our edge as a business is the agility, it helps us compete against those with deep pockets. IPO invariably will mean losing some of that agility. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if we&amp;rsquo;d want to IPO especially in times like now when everyone seems deep pockets.Grimacing face</description></item><item><title>The Success Story Of Zerodha's SMART Business Journey ft. Nithin Kamath | The Ranveer Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-success-story-of-zerodhas-smart-business-ft/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-success-story-of-zerodhas-smart-business-ft/</guid><description>An interaction with Ranveer from Beer Biceps talking about building Zerodha, how to do business, and life.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping vs Funding – a tax arbitrage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</guid><description>Promoters of businesses to professional investors, now chase “growth” and increase valuations to sell their stake in the business instead of trying to earn profits and taking the earnings out through dividends — to save on taxes and earn more efficiently.</description></item><item><title>Direct Market Access (DMA) for retail investors?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/direct-market-access-dma-for-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/direct-market-access-dma-for-retail-investors/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Stock trading games &amp; copy trading platforms in India?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-trading-games-copy-trading-platforms-in/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-trading-games-copy-trading-platforms-in/</guid><description>My thoughts on copy-trading and social trading platforms and why they aren&amp;rsquo;t feasible in India right now.</description></item><item><title>The Success Story Of Zerodha's SMART Business Journey ft. Nithin Kamath | The Ranveer Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beer-biceps-zerodha-interview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beer-biceps-zerodha-interview/</guid><description/></item><item><title>What does it take to win at trading?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</guid><description>Learnings from interactions with thousands of traders and my own successes and failures.</description></item><item><title>Learning Sessions: Unfiltered deep dive with Nithin Kamath, Founder and CEO, Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/learning-sessions-unfiltered-deep-dive-with-nithin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/learning-sessions-unfiltered-deep-dive-with-nithin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Introducing ‘Innerworth – Mind over markets’</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The race to Zero – Can the Indian brokerage industry survive?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-race-to-zero-can-the-indian-brokerage-industry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-race-to-zero-can-the-indian-brokerage-industry/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Zerodha story: Nithin Kamath shares his bootstrapped entrepreneurial journey</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-zerodha-story-nithin-kamath-shares-his-journey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-zerodha-story-nithin-kamath-shares-his-journey/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>