<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Musings on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Musings on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The growing risks of trading crypto derivatives without clear rules</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-growing-risks-of-trading-crypto-derivatives-without-clear-rules/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-growing-risks-of-trading-crypto-derivatives-without-clear-rules/</guid><description>Crypto derivative exchanges exist in regulatory limbo. A bit like Schrödinger&amp;rsquo;s cat—neither fully regulated nor unregulated. This ambiguity is being exploited in dangerous ways. By the way, I am not referring to the actual buying and selling of Cryptocurrency.
The first risk with unregulated platforms is, of course, that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing you can do if something goes wrong.
The other big problem with crypto F&amp;amp;O is that you have no idea who&amp;rsquo;s on the other side of your order.</description></item><item><title>Take break from trading using Kill Switch</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-break-from-trading-using-kill-switch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-break-from-trading-using-kill-switch/</guid><description>The other common trading mistake I have seen over and over again in all my years of being a trader and running a brokerage is over-trading and revenge trading.
Sometimes, the best trade is the one you don&amp;rsquo;t take.
This is why we launched Kill Switch. If you get the urge to keep trading, you can enable it, and you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to place trades for the rest of the day.</description></item><item><title>In The Money by Zerodha podcast with Tom Sosnoff</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/in-the-money-by-zerodha-podcast-with-tom-sosnoff/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/in-the-money-by-zerodha-podcast-with-tom-sosnoff/</guid><description>Most traders know that you can&amp;rsquo;t predict the markets, but they trade as if they can. This has to be the most common and costly trading mistake of all. Goes to show the difference between knowing and doing.
Sandeep Rao (musandz) recently recorded a podcast with the great Tom Sosnoff, co-founder of Thinkorswim and tastytrade, on our new YouTube channel, and here&amp;rsquo;s what Tom said:
&amp;ldquo;It takes a long time to convince yourself to learn certain things—mostly because we all have big egos and our own ideas.</description></item><item><title>Teaching finance and markets online with Varsity Live</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/teaching-finance-and-markets-online-with-varsity-live/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/teaching-finance-and-markets-online-with-varsity-live/</guid><description>I think we&amp;rsquo;ve finally found a way to teach finance and markets online with both quality and scale with Varsity Live.
We&amp;rsquo;ve had 2.3 lakh registrations so far, with about 3,000 new people signing up every week. By the way, this Sunday, the 23rd, we&amp;rsquo;re hosting a finance boot camp for kids. Most of this is a result of people discovering Varsity Live and sharing it with their friends and family.</description></item><item><title>Portfolio update of a colleague at work</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/portfolio-update-of-a-colleague-at-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/portfolio-update-of-a-colleague-at-work/</guid><description>Portfolio update of a colleague at work. He&amp;rsquo;s now invested in 3,100 stocks (it was 2,100 last time), taking diversification to its logical extreme. 😀
At least he&amp;rsquo;s beating G-Secs.
Btw, you can check your account’s performance on Console.</description></item><item><title>Accessibility has always been core to how we build</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/accessibility-has-always-been-core-to-how-we-build/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/accessibility-has-always-been-core-to-how-we-build/</guid><description>In November 2024, the Supreme Court ruled that accessibility is a fundamental right, directing businesses to ensure their digital platforms are accessible to people with disabilities. The Court essentially said that in a digital-first world, denying digital access means denying basic rights. It’s not just about compliance, it’s about constitutional equality.
Accessibility has been core to how we build at Zerodha. The mandate didn’t change our approach, it just gave us a deadline.</description></item><item><title>Indian companies have reported strong Q2 results</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-companies-have-reported-strong-q2-results/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-companies-have-reported-strong-q2-results/</guid><description>3500+ companies have reported earnings, and there&amp;rsquo;s a broad-based recovery across sectors.
&amp;ldquo;Aggregate revenues have risen 8.2% year-on-year, while EBITDA and PAT climbed 14.1% and 16.0%, respectively. Excluding Financial Services, profit growth accelerated to 22.5%&amp;rdquo;
Perhaps this explains why indices are holding up much better than most bears had expected. Hoping this earnings strength sustains 🤞
Data from IndiaDataHub
Link to the article here.</description></item><item><title>Shaping healthier habits through participatory sport</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shaping-healthier-habits-through-participatory-sport/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shaping-healthier-habits-through-participatory-sport/</guid><description>At Rainmatter Health, we&amp;rsquo;re experimenting with something beyond just writing checks.
We&amp;rsquo;re creating participatory sports events through an initiative called Peakst8 Club. We&amp;rsquo;ve been going around the country with Founders Peak—getting health founders (and others) to participate, not just network over coffee.
Last weekend was our first grand event: &amp;ldquo;No Parking.&amp;rdquo; Booked the entire basement at Brigade, Orion Mall (thanks, Nirupa Shankar!), Bengaluru. Around 1,000 runners representing 38 corporates, 45 communities, and 43 run clubs were participating in various activities, including running, rowing, cycling, and more.</description></item><item><title>Understanding taxation on share buybacks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/understanding-taxation-on-share-buybacks/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/understanding-taxation-on-share-buybacks/</guid><description>Infy is one of the most highly held stocks by investors, and the record date for their massive buyback is November 14th, the biggest buyback ever in India. That is, you can participate in the buyback if you hold the shares in your demat account as of November 14.
I think it is essential to understand how you will be taxed on this. If you participate in the buyback at Rs 1800 (current price is ~Rs 1550), here&amp;rsquo;s the taxation:</description></item><item><title>SEBI cautions against investing in digital gold</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cautions-against-investing-in-digital-gold/</link><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cautions-against-investing-in-digital-gold/</guid><description>Digital gold is unregulated. A timely reminder from SEBI.
Most people don’t realize that nobody regulates digital gold, and if something were to happen to the platforms or companies selling it, there’s not much you can do.
It’s also a subpar way to get exposure to gold. You pay 3% GST the moment you buy. Then there are spreads of another 2–3%, which means as soon as you purchase digital gold, you’re already down about 6%, and that’s before even factoring in regulatory risk.</description></item><item><title>Robinhood makes $150 million a year just from instant withdrawal fee</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-makes-150-million-a-year-just-from-instant-withdrawal-fee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-makes-150-million-a-year-just-from-instant-withdrawal-fee/</guid><description>I just discovered that Robinhood will generate approximately $150 million (~₹1,300 crores) in revenue from the fees it charges for processing instant client withdrawals. Their cost to process these is around $35–40 million, which means a clean $100 million to the bottom line, and that’s just from instant withdrawals. 😬
As an Indian startup with some scale, founders dream of generating revenue like this from non-core products. Hence the rush to introduce everything: loans, insurance, payments, and other financial services.</description></item><item><title>Discussion with Adnan from Devils Circuit on fitness and health</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/discussion-with-adnan-from-devils-circuit-on-fitness-and-health/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/discussion-with-adnan-from-devils-circuit-on-fitness-and-health/</guid><description>Of everyone I’ve met, Adnan has to be one of the most passionate advocates for fitness and getting Indians to participate in active sports. His company, Devils Circuit, has faced its fair share of obstacles and ups and downs — but the mission remains strong: inspiring Indians to take a greater interest in their health and fitness.
And my gut tells me, the time when we truly start caring more about our health is coming soon.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha LIQUIDCASE grows to ₹6,000 crore AUM in under two years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-liquidcase-grows-to-6000-crore-aum-in-under-two-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-liquidcase-grows-to-6000-crore-aum-in-under-two-years/</guid><description>Zerodha LIQUIDCASE is India&amp;rsquo;s first liquid ETF with a growth NAV, and we launched it in January 2024. In just under two years, it&amp;rsquo;s incredible that the AUM has reached almost ₹6,000 crores.
All of this growth is organic, from traders and investors discovering the ETF and investing in it. We haven&amp;rsquo;t really spoken about it much, and you can&amp;rsquo;t pay commissions on an ETF anyway.
The innovation here was simple: no dividends, because they were tax-inefficient and a pain to redeem and track.</description></item><item><title>Congrats to the Groww team on the IPO</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/congrats-to-the-groww-team-on-their-ipo/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/congrats-to-the-groww-team-on-their-ipo/</guid><description>Congrats on the IPO Lalit Keshre &amp;amp; team, and best of luck.
Btw, about 20% of all Groww IPO applications are from Zerodha customers. 😛</description></item><item><title>How India’s tax structure rewards growth over profits</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-indias-tax-structure-rewards-growth-over-profits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-indias-tax-structure-rewards-growth-over-profits/</guid><description>If you take money out of a business as dividends, the effective tax rate is 52% (25% corporate tax + 35.5% on personal income). Through capital gains, it’s just 14.95% (with cess).
Why does this matter? Here’s what you should know if you invest in IPOs.
If you’re an investor (especially a VC), the math is simple: reduce corporate tax by showing minimal profits or losses. Spend (Burn) on acquiring users, build a growth narrative, and then sell shares at a higher valuation while paying much lower tax.</description></item><item><title>Didn’t expect our support for FFmpeg to get this much love</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/didnt-expect-our-support-for-ffmpeg-to-get-this-much-love/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/didnt-expect-our-support-for-ffmpeg-to-get-this-much-love/</guid><description>The amount of love this has gotten is quite crazy. I was just asking K, &amp;lsquo;How does it make sense that there are tech companies worth billions and trillions of dollars who use these pieces of open source software without which they could not exist, and yet are unwilling to fund them?&amp;rsquo;
We’ve been funding open source projects from ~2018 on and off before setting up FLOSS/fund in 2024. We run on open source, so supporting is a no-brainer.</description></item><item><title>The one thing I wish I’d done differently after my stroke</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-one-thing-i-wish-id-done-differently-after-my-stroke/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-one-thing-i-wish-id-done-differently-after-my-stroke/</guid><description>If there’s one thing I wish I had done differently when I was hit by a stroke last January, it would be to go to the hospital immediately, within the Golden Hour (&amp;lt;4.5 hours), instead of thinking I could just sleep it off.
This “nothing will happen to me” attitude is common, especially among those under 50. But the truth is, strokes are rising sharply, up to nearly 30% of all strokes in the last few years, among 30 to 50-year-olds.</description></item><item><title>AMA with Zerodha's core team</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ama-with-zerodhas-core-team/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ama-with-zerodhas-core-team/</guid><description>A bunch of you asked us questions about our revenues, regulations, international investing, AI, and more. Nikhil, Kailash, Karthik Rangappa, Venu, and I answered a lot of those questions in this AMA.
Since there were several questions about US investing: we didn&amp;rsquo;t offer it until now because the regulations were unclear, but now there&amp;rsquo;s clarity. In May, SEBI and IFSCA allowed brokers to operate in GIFT City, and in June, the exchanges allowed brokers to offer third-party products.</description></item><item><title>Indian VC ecosystem has changed quite a bit in 15 years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-vc-ecosystem-has-changed-quite-a-bit-in-15-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-vc-ecosystem-has-changed-quite-a-bit-in-15-years/</guid><description>The Indian VC ecosystem has changed quite a bit in 15 years. When we started Zerodha in 2010, &amp;ldquo;VC&amp;rdquo; was an exotic term, and there was barely any startup activity. The most popular VCs were dads, uncles and aunts.
Starting around 2010, we began seeing interest driven by India&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;opportunity size.&amp;rdquo; India&amp;rsquo;s population has done more to attract VC money than anything else 😛 &amp;ldquo;India has 120 crore people, and even if 1% buy X&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>1929 by Andrew Ross Sorkin is a must-read for anyone in the markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/1929-by-andrew-ross-sorkin-is-a-must-read-for-anyone-in-the-markets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/1929-by-andrew-ross-sorkin-is-a-must-read-for-anyone-in-the-markets/</guid><description>1929 by Andrew Ross Sorkin is a must-read for anyone in the markets—stocks, commodities, or crypto.
He quotes US President Hoover (1929):
“The only problem with capitalism is capitalists. They’re too damn greedy.”
Every crash, 1907, 1929, 1987, 2001 (Dotcom), 2008 (GFC), and so many more, follows the same script.
Greed drives markets higher, inflating bubbles that draw in even those who don’t understand the risks. As euphoria builds, leverage accumulates quietly somewhere in the system: loans, margins, complex derivatives.</description></item></channel></rss>