<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>products on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/products/</link><description>Recent content in products on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/products/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing the Stock research platform powered by Tijori</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-stock-research-platform-powered-by-tijori/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-stock-research-platform-powered-by-tijori/</guid><description>We just launched fundamental stock pages powered by Tijori. If you are tracking a stock and want to get a quick snapshot of the financials, news, peer comparisons, and any potential red flags, then this will help.
To dive deeper, you can always go to Tijori&amp;rsquo;s site.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Portfolio Performance Curve on Console</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-portfolio-performance-curve/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-portfolio-performance-curve/</guid><description>We, just launched Portfolio Performance Curve on Console. This allows you to visualize your account performance, and you can compare it to a benchmark like Nifty 50. We&amp;rsquo;re probably the only broker to offer this feature in India and possibly worldwide.
The performance curve is calculated in a similar way to the NAV of mutual funds. The daily NAV is calculated using the P&amp;amp;L of all trades across equity intraday and delivery, F&amp;amp;O, commodities, MTF, and mutual funds based on the cash in the account.</description></item><item><title>Important updates on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/important-updates-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/important-updates-on-kite/</guid><description>Some important updates on Kite by Zerodha.
Order slicing – You can now easily place large orders without having to worry about exchange freeze limits.
Available margin – Instantly know your available funds on the Kite order window.
Market depth – Now easily access market depth on the order window itself.
Remember F&amp;amp;O quantity – Kite remembers the quantity you entered for a contract and automatically fill it in when you open the order window next time.</description></item><item><title>All-new options chain on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/all-new-options-chain-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/all-new-options-chain-on-kite/</guid><description>We just launched the all-new options chain on Kite. It has pretty much everything you need to trade options from a single screen from order placement to tracking positions.
You can also check the blog post for more information.</description></item><item><title>Sensibull explained</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sensibull-explained/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sensibull-explained/</guid><description>I first met Abid Hassan 12 years ago when he and his friends were building the first version of Sensibull. The original idea was to help traders and investors make better decisions, like helping them avoid going against the trend, being diversified, etc. In many ways, they were well ahead of their time. We couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to make the platform work while complying with regulations.
Abid went back to trading options for a trading desk, but I continued peddling him the idea that he should start something related to the markets.</description></item><item><title>Introducing MTF on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-mtf-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-mtf-on-kite/</guid><description>I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it is a good time with the fall in the markets 😬, but we are finally launching MTF (margin trading facility) which allows you to buy stocks for delivery by borrowing money from us.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t been sure about this product for a long time because of obvious reasons. Customers who trade for delivery tend to ignore the impact of the cost of borrowing, and there&amp;rsquo;s always the risk of the trade going against them, which leads to a bigger loss.</description></item><item><title>Search by brand feature on Kite web</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/search-by-brand-feature-on-kite-web/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/search-by-brand-feature-on-kite-web/</guid><description>We just added the Search by Brands feature on Zerodha. Currently available on Kite web and soon on mobile. 😀</description></item><item><title>Introducing notes feature on Kite Web</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-notes-feature-on-kite-web/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-notes-feature-on-kite-web/</guid><description>Have you checked out the notes feature on Kite Web? Read more on how to add notes on Kite.</description></item></channel></rss>