<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>products on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/products/</link><description>Recent content in products on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/products/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Our Loan Against Shares (LAS) business just crossed Rs. 500 crores</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/our-loan-against-shares-las-business-just-crossed-rs-500-crores/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/our-loan-against-shares-las-business-just-crossed-rs-500-crores/</guid><description>Our Loan Against Shares (LAS) business just crossed Rs 500 crores.
It&amp;rsquo;s a business that we hadn&amp;rsquo;t spoken about much for a long time, for a variety of reasons, including regulatory. But the reason why we offer LAS via Zerodha Capital is that it&amp;rsquo;s a secured product.
The other reason is that I think it&amp;rsquo;s a good way to help clients clear their high-interest loans, like personal loans, credit card dues, etc.</description></item><item><title>Kite Terminal Mode is now live on beta</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kite-terminal-mode-is-now-live-on-beta/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/kite-terminal-mode-is-now-live-on-beta/</guid><description>Kite Terminal Mode is now live on beta!
We are quite excited about this. 😬
Check out the Kite Beta, and you can provide feedback here.</description></item><item><title>Get realtime company updates on WhatsApp with Tijori Alerts</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/get-realtime-company-updates-on-whatsapp-with-tijori-alerts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/get-realtime-company-updates-on-whatsapp-with-tijori-alerts/</guid><description>Access to information is what drives prices in markets. While there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of information today, the real challenge is figuring out what actually matters and getting it in time.
Exchange filings, earnings, management commentary, and conference calls. When something material comes out, prices react almost instantly. The faster you get the information, the better your odds of reacting sensibly.
Institutions and high-frequency trading desks scan exchange filings the moment they&amp;rsquo;re published and act within milliseconds.</description></item><item><title>MTF has grown 5x, but broker risk models haven’t</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mtf-has-grown-5x-but-broker-risk-models-havent/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mtf-has-grown-5x-but-broker-risk-models-havent/</guid><description>MTF (margin funding) has grown ~5X in 4 years to ₹110k+ crores, especially after F&amp;amp;O margins and STT increases. But there&amp;rsquo;s something nobody&amp;rsquo;s talking about: there is no real risk model in play for brokers. 😬
Regulations allow up to 5X leverage (20% margin) on many stocks. Competition forces every broker to offer maximum permissible leverage. If you don&amp;rsquo;t, you lose business. Classic race to the bottom.
Unlike F&amp;amp;O, MTF has several risk multipliers: Clients hold positions for months vs days 1,300 stocks (many illiquid) allowed vs only the top 200 in F&amp;amp;O All buy positions vs two-way flow in F&amp;amp;O, making risk management much harder Much harder to manage risk, given all the above.</description></item><item><title>Check IPO lock-in period expiry on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-ipo-lock-in-period-expiry-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-ipo-lock-in-period-expiry-on-kite/</guid><description>When a company goes for an IPO, not all shareholders can sell their shares immediately. Certain categories of shareholders like promoters, early investors and ESOP holders have to wait anywhere between 30 days to 18 months before they can sell their shares.
Since these are large shareholders, whenever they sell, there can often be a downward move in the stock price. So if you are buying shares of companies that IPO&amp;rsquo;d recently, you should track when the lock-in period expires.</description></item><item><title>A year of MTF launch and product growth</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-year-of-mtf-launch-and-product-growth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-year-of-mtf-launch-and-product-growth/</guid><description>We launched our MTF product a year ago. Despite being one of the last brokers to offer this and without actively promoting it on the order screen or elsewhere, we captured ~5% of the market. But growth has plateaued along with the broader industry.
One surprising thing I have noticed is that customers don&amp;rsquo;t seem to care about MTF brokerage or know what they&amp;rsquo;re being charged. Our current brokerage is 0.</description></item><item><title>Why we don't provide personal and credit card loans through Zerodha Capital</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-we-dont-provide-personal-and-credit-card-loans-through-zerodha-capital/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-we-dont-provide-personal-and-credit-card-loans-through-zerodha-capital/</guid><description>Someone on our team recently asked, &amp;ldquo;Why do we only offer Loan Against Securities on Zerodha Capital?&amp;rdquo; Why not personal loans or credit cards with their higher interest rates?
The simple answer is we can&amp;rsquo;t do anything different there. And our cost of funds doesn&amp;rsquo;t work. We&amp;rsquo;re at ~8.5%, while banks raise money at ~3.5%, and large NBFCs around ~7%.
Can&amp;rsquo;t compete on rates, and usually the best borrowers go where the rates are the lowest.</description></item><item><title>Alar’s new update makes the dictionary faster and easier to build on</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alars-new-update-makes-the-dictionary-faster-and-easier-to-build-on/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/alars-new-update-makes-the-dictionary-faster-and-easier-to-build-on/</guid><description>In 2020, we did something very odd. Well, K (Kailash, CTO) did. He helped open-source Alar, a Kannada–English dictionary. It&amp;rsquo;s a little absurd, considering we&amp;rsquo;re a stockbroking company, but the project itself is one of monumental importance.
The story of how Alar came to be is even more inspiring. It was essentially the life&amp;rsquo;s work of one man: V. Krishna. Alar is the online version of what he had built over 40 years—researching, writing, and cataloguing more than 150,000 Kannada words and 240,000 English definitions, complete with all their attendant details.</description></item><item><title>10 years of zero brokerage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/10-years-of-zero-brokerage/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/10-years-of-zero-brokerage/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s been 10 years since we went zero brokerage on stocks, ETFs, and more. Back in 2015, if you had asked whether Zerodha would keep brokerage on investing at zero in 2025, I would&amp;rsquo;ve probably said no.
The backstory of how we decided to go zero is a bit funny. K(Kailash, CTO) and I were sitting at Bengaluru airport on our way to Kochi, talking about the need to change Zerodha&amp;rsquo;s image of being meant only for traders.</description></item><item><title>Take break from trading using Kill Switch</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-break-from-trading-using-kill-switch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-break-from-trading-using-kill-switch/</guid><description>The other common trading mistake I have seen over and over again in all my years of being a trader and running a brokerage is over-trading and revenge trading.
Sometimes, the best trade is the one you don&amp;rsquo;t take.
This is why we launched Kill Switch. If you get the urge to keep trading, you can enable it, and you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to place trades for the rest of the day.</description></item><item><title>Portfolio update of a colleague at work</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/portfolio-update-of-a-colleague-at-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/portfolio-update-of-a-colleague-at-work/</guid><description>Portfolio update of a colleague at work. He&amp;rsquo;s now invested in 3,100 stocks (it was 2,100 last time), taking diversification to its logical extreme. 😀
At least he&amp;rsquo;s beating G-Secs.
Btw, you can check your account’s performance on Console.</description></item><item><title>Accessibility has always been core to how we build</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/accessibility-has-always-been-core-to-how-we-build/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/accessibility-has-always-been-core-to-how-we-build/</guid><description>In November 2024, the Supreme Court ruled that accessibility is a fundamental right, directing businesses to ensure their digital platforms are accessible to people with disabilities. The Court essentially said that in a digital-first world, denying digital access means denying basic rights. It’s not just about compliance, it’s about constitutional equality.
Accessibility has been core to how we build at Zerodha. The mandate didn’t change our approach, it just gave us a deadline.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha LIQUIDCASE grows to ₹6,000 crore AUM in under two years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-liquidcase-grows-to-6000-crore-aum-in-under-two-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-liquidcase-grows-to-6000-crore-aum-in-under-two-years/</guid><description>Zerodha LIQUIDCASE is India&amp;rsquo;s first liquid ETF with a growth NAV, and we launched it in January 2024. In just under two years, it&amp;rsquo;s incredible that the AUM has reached almost ₹6,000 crores.
All of this growth is organic, from traders and investors discovering the ETF and investing in it. We haven&amp;rsquo;t really spoken about it much, and you can&amp;rsquo;t pay commissions on an ETF anyway.
The innovation here was simple: no dividends, because they were tax-inefficient and a pain to redeem and track.</description></item><item><title>RBI move could make LAS more popular</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-move-could-make-las-more-popular/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-move-could-make-las-more-popular/</guid><description>One good change from RBI yesterday: banks can now lend up to ₹1 crore against shares, up from the earlier ₹20 lakhs. Hopefully, this makes loan against securities (LAS) more popular.
It’s ridiculous how many people holding stocks continue taking personal loans or using credit cards at much higher rates—credit cards can go up to 40%+. Even at Zerodha Capital, we see this constantly. People just aren’t aware they can replace high-interest debt with LAS, which is one reason our book is still only ₹450 crores.</description></item><item><title>Manage investments better with secondary demat account</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/manage-investments-better-with-secondary-demat-account/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/manage-investments-better-with-secondary-demat-account/</guid><description>When I was trading actively (before Zerodha), I had an offline demat account where I held all my investments and an online account for all my trades. This was a way to avoid the temptation of &amp;ldquo;trading&amp;rdquo; my investments 😬
If I had to sell any of my investments, there was effort involved. I had to physically fill out the delivery instruction slips and send them to the broker to move holdings to my primary demat and then sell them.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Kite Backup - A WhatsApp-based emergency mode</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-kite-backup-a-whatsapp-based-emergency-mode/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-kite-backup-a-whatsapp-based-emergency-mode/</guid><description>Trading platforms are ridiculously complex. One hiccup anywhere from exchange connections to cloud servers can create an issue. Over the years, we&amp;rsquo;ve built tons of safeguards and redundancies, but we&amp;rsquo;re still paranoid.
Apart from all of this, we&amp;rsquo;ve built a new emergency trading mode using WhatsApp. In case of a disaster scenario, which we hope never happens, and the Kite web and mobile both become inaccessible during market hours, this backup mode will allow you to cancel orders and exit positions.</description></item><item><title>Why India needs easier short selling for better price discovery</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-india-needs-easier-short-selling-for-better-price-discovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-india-needs-easier-short-selling-for-better-price-discovery/</guid><description>The lack of short selling in Indian markets is causing potential market distortions.
Unless we make shorting of stocks easy in the Indian markets, price discovery will be impaired. India has been a structurally long-only market with almost no shorting activity, because borrowing stock to short is really hard and is an offline process.
Because of this long-only bias, there&amp;rsquo;s probably very little short-selling talent as well, even if large funds want to start shorting.</description></item><item><title>Dark patterns in finance apps</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dark-patterns-in-finance-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dark-patterns-in-finance-apps/</guid><description>One of the biggest challenges in building a financial services business is that the incentives are often skewed toward doing what’s good for the business and not for the customer. It’s very hard to consistently put customers first.
This is one of the main reasons why finance apps are full of dark patterns, more than almost any other category. Dark patterns are design tricks used in apps and websites to make you do things that are not in your best interest.</description></item><item><title>Latest MTF improvements on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/latest-mtf-improvements-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/latest-mtf-improvements-on-kite/</guid><description>Our MTF (Margin Trading Facility) book grown to ~Rs 3,000 crores within 6 months of launch. Half the time, we were in a bear market-like conditions.
The good news is that our clients are sitting on a combined profit on their MTF position. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if it will eventually be like this, but at least for now, they are profitable.
By the way, the MTF component of a business, which we had resisted for so long, has acted as a revenue hedge for the business against a drop in options business and a drop in transaction charge revenue.</description></item><item><title>Updates to the Portfolio Performance Curve on Console.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/updates-to-the-portfolio-performance-curve-on-console/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/updates-to-the-portfolio-performance-curve-on-console/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve added more equity and debt indices for comparison on the Portfolio Performance Curve on Console.
Fun fact: This screenshot is the actual portfolio performance of a colleague. He has 2100 stocks (~Rs 21lks) in his portfolio, and with great effort and smarts, he&amp;rsquo;s managed to underperform a government bond index. 😬</description></item></channel></rss>