<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>money on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/money/</link><description>Recent content in money on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/money/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Zerodha's growing AUM and investor profits</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodhas-growing-aum-and-investor-profits/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodhas-growing-aum-and-investor-profits/</guid><description>Equity investors at Zerodha have realized a profit of Rs 50,000 crores over the last 4+ years and are sitting on unrealized profits of Rs 1,00,000 crores on an AUM of Rs 4,50,000 crores.
By the way, most of the AUM was added in the last four years.</description></item><item><title>Rise in shady illegal loan apps</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rise-in-shady-illegal-loan-apps/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rise-in-shady-illegal-loan-apps/</guid><description>Finance apps that ask for full access to contacts, messages, photos, etc. are a red flag, especially if it&amp;rsquo;s a loan app. A lot of these lending apps are digital avatars of predatory moneylenders (Sudakhor in Hindi).
The number of people getting fleeced by shady and illegal loan apps has gone up significantly. Many individuals caught up in the web of these apps frequently resort to drastic actions, such as suicide.</description></item><item><title>SEBI's proposal to offer affordable corporate bonds and increase retail investor participation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-proposal-to-offer-affordable-corporate-bonds-and-increase-retail-investor-participation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-proposal-to-offer-affordable-corporate-bonds-and-increase-retail-investor-participation/</guid><description>The latest consultation proposal by SEBI to reduce corporate bonds&amp;rsquo; face value to Rs 10,000 can lead to greater retail participation in the bond markets.
I think for the majority of our country, i.e. beyond the top 5 to 10% of the country yet to start investing, equities may not be the right instruments because they can be scary because of the volatility. A bad market phase or losses when they start will end with investors permanently leaving the markets.</description></item><item><title>Managing risk and growth in Financial services firms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/managing-risk-and-growth-in-financial-services-firms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/managing-risk-and-growth-in-financial-services-firms/</guid><description>The mishaps at large financial institutions of crediting funds to the wrong persons serve as a reminder about one of the most significant risks of running a financial services firm.
Whether you are a broker, a bank, or any entity that directly settles with end customers, once securities or funds are sent to the wrong person, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to get them back. This risk is like a hanging sword for these businesses.</description></item><item><title>Phishing frauds have gone thorugh the roof</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/phishing-frauds-have-gone-through-the-roof/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/phishing-frauds-have-gone-through-the-roof/</guid><description>The number of phishing frauds has gone through the roof, and everybody is being targeted. The only way to protect yourself is to not trust anybody asking for money or offering something that seems too good to be true. Here are a few types of frauds I have come across recently.
Impersonating Govt officials and other higher authorities and asking for charitable donations or money for other things. Many folks on our team have received social media and WhatsApp messages saying I was in some urgent need of money from fake accounts.</description></item><item><title>Financial freedom.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-freedom/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-freedom/</guid><description>Financial freedom isn’t X amount. Luxuries soon become necessities, X constantly grows. In a world where everyone is triggering you to borrow &amp;amp; buy what you don’t need, being content &amp;amp; debt-free is true financial freedom. Common sense stuff, rarely said.</description></item><item><title>The twisted world of illegal CFDs &amp; binary options</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>