<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>money on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/money/</link><description>Recent content in money on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/money/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Managing risk and growth in Financial services firms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/managing-risk-and-growth-in-financial-services-firms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/managing-risk-and-growth-in-financial-services-firms/</guid><description>The mishaps at large financial institutions of crediting funds to the wrong persons serve as a reminder about one of the most significant risks of running a financial services firm.
Whether you are a broker, a bank, or any entity that directly settles with end customers, once securities or funds are sent to the wrong person, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to get them back. This risk is like a hanging sword for these businesses.</description></item><item><title>Phishing frauds have gone thorugh the roof</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/phishing-frauds-have-gone-through-the-roof/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/phishing-frauds-have-gone-through-the-roof/</guid><description>The number of phishing frauds has gone through the roof, and everybody is being targeted. The only way to protect yourself is to not trust anybody asking for money or offering something that seems too good to be true. Here are a few types of frauds I have come across recently.
Impersonating Govt officials and other higher authorities and asking for charitable donations or money for other things. Many folks on our team have received social media and WhatsApp messages saying I was in some urgent need of money from fake accounts.</description></item><item><title>Financial freedom.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-freedom/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-freedom/</guid><description>Financial freedom isn’t X amount. Luxuries soon become necessities, X constantly grows. In a world where everyone is triggering you to borrow &amp;amp; buy what you don’t need, being content &amp;amp; debt-free is true financial freedom. Common sense stuff, rarely said.</description></item><item><title>The twisted world of illegal CFDs &amp; binary options</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>