<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>climate on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/climate/</link><description>Recent content in climate on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/climate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Boson White Water with its wastewater solutions</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/boson-white-water-with-its-wastewater-solutions/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/boson-white-water-with-its-wastewater-solutions/</guid><description>It just took one bad rainy season for Bengaluru to face a massive water shortage crisis. Given that extreme weather conditions will only become more common, this probably won&amp;rsquo;t be the last time we face this crisis.
I learned recently that wastewater could be part of the solution. Bengaluru&amp;rsquo;s total freshwater demand is ~2632 (million litres a day) MLD, and it generates ~2000 MLD of wastewater. Of this, centralized sewage treatment plants treat ~1,300 MLD, and this water is used for agricultural purposes.</description></item><item><title>Wheels in motion, a short film on Rainmatter</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/wheels-in-motion-a-short-film-on-rainmatter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/wheels-in-motion-a-short-film-on-rainmatter/</guid><description>The more I interact with Sameer Shisodia, who heads Rainmatter Foundation, our foundation team, and people from social organizations, the more I appreciate the need for a vibrant social sector.
Like how startups can help solve some problems that larger companies can’t due to legacy reasons or because of their size, which makes getting things done harder, the social sector can attempt to experiment with solutions that can benefit society but are hard for the Government &amp;amp; bureaucracy to attempt given its sheer size.</description></item><item><title>Pollution's impact on Indian Health and Economy</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/pollutions-impact-on-indian-health-and-economy/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/pollutions-impact-on-indian-health-and-economy/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s growing evidence to show that air and water pollution increases the risk of type 2 diabetes among Indians.
If the quality of life deteriorates, there will be a tipping point where people just give up and start moving from large cities to places with better living conditions. If this happens, it will cause serious economic damage from reduced tax revenues, falling land values, and further degradation of civic infrastructure among other issues.</description></item><item><title>The importance of long-term support for philanthropy in the social sector</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-long-term-support-for-philanthropy-in-the-social-sector/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-long-term-support-for-philanthropy-in-the-social-sector/</guid><description>As part of Rainmatter, I get to be in meetings &amp;amp; learn from the smartest people in the social sector, like #ClimateRISE today. The thing I still don&amp;rsquo;t understand is why Philanthropy/CSR is oriented toward funding projects &amp;amp; not supporting organizations over the long-term.
In both profit and non-profit organizations, the odds of creating returns or impact are highest when you find the right founders and give them enough runway to experiment.</description></item><item><title>The many benfits of hemp</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-many-benfits-of-hemp/</link><pubDate>Sat, 22 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-many-benfits-of-hemp/</guid><description>Hemp belongs to the Cannabis sativa family—the same as marijuana. They look similar, but hemp is versatile and has multiple uses, including as a superfood. It&amp;rsquo;s also good for the planet. Unlike its notorious cousin, hemp doesn&amp;rsquo;t get you high 😬. Partly why it isn&amp;rsquo;t popular.
Because they look alike and come from the same family, hemp is often mistaken for marijuana, which is one reason why it isn&amp;rsquo;t mainstream.</description></item><item><title>Electric vehicles vs. internal combustion engines</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/electric-vehicles-versus-internal-combustion-engines/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/electric-vehicles-versus-internal-combustion-engines/</guid><description>I assumed, like many, that electric vehicles (EVs) weren&amp;rsquo;t as green since most electricity in India is generated by burning coal, plus the transmission losses and emissions from battery production. Tarun Mehta recently explained why EVs are still much better emissions-wise.
This is mainly because of the internal combustion engine&amp;rsquo;s (ICE) inefficiency. You can read the entire discussion here.</description></item><item><title>Small change big impact</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/small-change-big-impact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/small-change-big-impact/</guid><description>88% homes have a fan while 72% have a mattress. 97% of fans are energy inefficient, this can now change with a new rating system. If Indians switched to efficient fans, Govt can save ₹575Cr &amp;amp; homes ₹6000/year Small change, big impact. Even for our planet</description></item><item><title>A little more forest everywhere</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-little-more-forrest-everywhere/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-little-more-forrest-everywhere/</guid><description>Through Rainmatter Organisation, we support organizations working on climate change issues. But we understand that the biggest impact can be made by individuals. Planting trees is a good start &amp;amp; we have been trying to help by giving free saplings. Karthik Rangappa&amp;rsquo;s Deverakadu.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Rainmatter Foundation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-rainmatter-foundation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-rainmatter-foundation/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>