<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>ipos on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/ipos/</link><description>Recent content in ipos on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/ipos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Check IPO lock-in period expiry on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-ipo-lock-in-period-expiry-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-ipo-lock-in-period-expiry-on-kite/</guid><description>When a company goes for an IPO, not all shareholders can sell their shares immediately. Certain categories of shareholders like promoters, early investors and ESOP holders have to wait anywhere between 30 days to 18 months before they can sell their shares.
Since these are large shareholders, whenever they sell, there can often be a downward move in the stock price. So if you are buying shares of companies that IPO&amp;rsquo;d recently, you should track when the lock-in period expires.</description></item><item><title>Why some IPOs keep rising even after listing day</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-some-ipos-keep-rising-even-after-listing-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-some-ipos-keep-rising-even-after-listing-day/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been noticing many recent IPOs continue running up for 2-3 days after listing. While demand and supply factors (limited free float) are obvious reasons, there may also be technical factors at play.
Let me explain the technical factor.
Many traders attempt to short these stocks intraday, expecting a fall, but if the stock hits the upper circuit, they get trapped with no buyers to sell to. This leads to what’s called a short delivery.</description></item><item><title>India's growing IPO landscape</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-growing-ipo-landscape/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-growing-ipo-landscape/</guid><description>Congrats to Swiggy on the listing.
I had tweeted this in 2019 when we had very few aspirational brands worth investing in. But since then, it&amp;rsquo;s crazy how much the Indian markets have changed in terms of the companies, the investor base, etc.
I hope we see more homegrown brands IPO in the coming years.</description></item><item><title>Advancements in capital market regulations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/advancements-in-capital-market-regulations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/advancements-in-capital-market-regulations/</guid><description>After a long time, we have had massive activity in the IPO market, with Rs 2.6lk cr blocked in bank accounts for IPOs worth Rs 7.6k cr.
If this was 2003, it would take 16 working days (or ~1 month), and the entire money would have moved to investment bankers and cost investors (an interest forego) at least 0.5% (assuming 6% pa) or Rs 1300 crores.
T+16 became T+12, T+6, and from Sep 2023 it is T+3 (~1week).</description></item></channel></rss>