<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>business on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/business/</link><description>Recent content in business on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why everyone should pay more attention to India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-everyone-should-pay-more-attention-to-india/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-everyone-should-pay-more-attention-to-india/</guid><description>Whenever students ask me for advice, I say, stay in India. Not just because we need to avoid the brain drain or that there&amp;rsquo;s an obligation to the country, but because India will most likely have the best opportunities in future.
@srajagopalan explains👇
Why is this a smart thing to do?
&amp;ldquo;Globally, one in five people below 25 is from India. 47% of Indians, about 650 million, are below the age of 25.</description></item><item><title>Word of mouth is more valuable than anything paid</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/word-of-mouth-is-more-valuable-than-anything-paid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/word-of-mouth-is-more-valuable-than-anything-paid/</guid><description>In my limited startup experience, paid is much easier than earned or owned, &amp;amp; super addictive. If businesses spend to grow, they rarely pivot from paid to focus on earned or owned unless, of course, they&amp;rsquo;re running out of funds. Word of mouth is more valuable than anything paid.</description></item><item><title>Valuation of stock brokerages around the world</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/valuations-of-global-brokerages/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/valuations-of-global-brokerages/</guid><description>I am pessimistic about the valuations of brokerages around the world, including that of Zerodha. This is because the performance of broking is directly tied to market performance. If people aren’t making money or there is no greed, activity usually drops off a cliff.
The best tech, products &amp;amp; low pricing won&amp;rsquo;t help.
A new report from JP Morgan on Robinhood (RH) said that app downloads are down by 78% QOQ and active users by 40% QOQ.</description></item><item><title>Who can disrupt new-age online brokers or even exchanges?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/who-can-disrupt-brokers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/who-can-disrupt-brokers/</guid><description>I get asked often, who out there do you think can disrupt the new-age online brokers or even exchanges? Me: I don’t think it will be another stock brokerage firm or a new stock exchange. It will most likely be an outsider, maybe Crypto. Here is why.
In broking or exchange business, both on pricing and product, there is not much left to disrupt. Unless of course, someone figures a way to pay people money for trading (-ve brokerage not allowed by regulation) or figures a way to help all customers make money (very tough)</description></item><item><title>Zerodha's 11th birthday.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-turns-eleven/</link><pubDate>Sun, 15 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-turns-eleven/</guid><description>Happy Independence day 🇮🇳. Coincidentally it&amp;rsquo;s Zerodha&amp;rsquo;s 11th birthday today too.😀 If I were to look back, we are most proud of building a business that continues to innovate, &amp;amp; prioritise customer interest over business growth constantly.
We&amp;rsquo;re also proud of the part we continue to play in growing the capital market ecosystem in India through Rainmatterin and give back to society through our foundation RainmatterOrg.
There&amp;rsquo;s plenty for us to get better at, especially around our support.</description></item><item><title>Scaling with common sense</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scaling-with-commonsense/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scaling-with-commonsense/</guid><description>If there was ever a person who&amp;rsquo;s had a strong influence on me, it&amp;rsquo;s K (Kailash), the secret sauce behind Zerodha. He just published this post which is more than just tech, a must-read for anyone building or aspiring to build a business or a product.</description></item><item><title>How will the broking industry perform next few years? This is a question I get asked often, more recently.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-will-the-broking-industry-perform/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-will-the-broking-industry-perform/</guid><description>How will the broking industry perform next few years? This is a question I get asked often, more recently. I usually say, if you can tell me the Nifty direction or volatility, I can tell you what the broking industry will do. Because both are positively correlated.
User growth depends on whether the markets (Nifty) go up or not. It took &amp;gt;10 years to reach the high made in 2008 in terms of new user addition (total NSDL + CDSL Demat).</description></item><item><title>Almost 20% of all Zomato applications are through Zerodha.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zomato-ipo/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zomato-ipo/</guid><description>Almost 20% of all Zomato applications are through Zerodha. Deepinder, returning the favour from everyone at Zerodha for all the tasty food Zomato delivered when we were hungry. Face savouring food Wishing you and the team at Zomato a blockbuster listing.</description></item><item><title>The last 18 months at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/user-growth-in-the-last-18-months/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/user-growth-in-the-last-18-months/</guid><description>The last 18 months at Zerodha have been eventful, to say the least. Historically, market crashes caused panic &amp;amp; reduced activity. But this crisis led to a rush of new customers looking to buy into stocks on sale. Free time due to lockdowns &amp;amp; low bank deposit rates helped.
Once this younger bunch of first-time investors saw quick profits, they started spreading the word and got their friends &amp;amp; family to invest.</description></item><item><title>The risk for high growth B2C tech IPOs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/high-growth-tech-ipos/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/high-growth-tech-ipos/</guid><description>The risk with all the high growth B2C tech IPOs coming up is growth plateauing. Growth is usually a function of agility &amp;amp; product bets. Since these companies take more bets &amp;amp; are more agile &amp;amp; aggressive than traditional businesses, they grow faster (Zerodha as well).
The question then, will the ability of these companies to be agile (reason for growth) reduce because of all the scrutiny that comes by being publicly listed?</description></item><item><title>On the noise about our salaries</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-the-noise-about-our-salaries/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-the-noise-about-our-salaries/</guid><description>I’m surprised by the unwanted noise around this whole salary news of Nikhil, Seema (my wife), &amp;amp; me. The headlines are misleading. We are a private company &amp;amp; no obligations to clarify, but we thought maybe we should, as there are folks who are misinterpreting this.
Firstly the reported figure isn’t the actual salary being drawn. This is an enabling resolution that allows us as working promoters to draw salaries up to the number in case of liquidity requirements.</description></item><item><title>A few thoughts on the Zerodha journey so far</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-zerodha-journey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-zerodha-journey/</guid><description>Last 2 years have been spectacular for Zerodha . Lucky to be at right place right time, ready with products &amp;amp; initiatives when there was a surge in retail participation. With success, what I say gets valued more Grimacing faceHere are a few questions that we get asked frequently.
Why haven’t we raised any external capital, especially at times like these when we could get some crazy valuation? I had talked about it earlier</description></item><item><title>Worklife balance at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/worklife-balance-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/worklife-balance-at-zerodha/</guid><description>At Zerodha, we have just killed all work-related chats post 6 pm &amp;amp; holidays. Also trying to get as many conversations to be asynchronous, moving them from chat to our internal instance of Discourse. Curious to see if this helps reduce the feeling of burnt out &amp;amp; brain fried. Apparently, multitasking hurts performance and may even damage the brain (check the link below). Being part of multiple discussions on different topics in different chat groups simultaneously (Multitasking) has gone up exponentially post WFH.</description></item><item><title>Why doesn't Zerodha advertise?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-doesnt-zerodha-advertise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-doesnt-zerodha-advertise/</guid><description>One thing I get asked the most and I’ve tweeted about this numerous times is that why don’t we advertise. Firstly I&amp;rsquo;d shared this sometime back.
Unlike buying a mobile phone or ordering a pizza, you don&amp;rsquo;t invest in stocks &amp;amp; MFs impulsively. Most often than not, we invest because of greed or because of our friends. And regulations don&amp;rsquo;t allow you to advertise greed.
Ads do help you create visibility and build credibility - two really important things in the business of money, especially the first few years.</description></item><item><title>Podcast with Prateek Singh, the founder of LearnApp</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-with-prateek-learnapp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-with-prateek-learnapp/</guid><description>From the start at Zerodha, we&amp;rsquo;ve constantly shared things to educate people about the capital markets. Zerodha Varsity was our first formal attempt in text. But we knew that video was also important, &amp;amp; that people trust content delivered by experts.
This was the reason behind partnering with LearnApp through Rainmatter. The amazing bit in the journey has been that some of the best folks in our industry have been incredibly generous with their time to share their knowledge with no expectations.</description></item><item><title>Right now is probably the stupidest time for fintech firms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-stupidest-time-to-be-raising-money/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-stupidest-time-to-be-raising-money/</guid><description>Right now, is probably the stupidest time for fintech firms like @zerodhaonline to be raising money. It is quite crazy the number of folks reaching out &amp;amp; the different deals. We might regret it in the future, but we are not raising &amp;amp; here are the counterintuitive reasons why.
We don’t need the money, so there’s no point in raising money just because someone is ready to give it to you.</description></item><item><title>Risks of running a brokerage firm</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risks-of-running-a-brokerage-firm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risks-of-running-a-brokerage-firm/</guid><description>The big news from last week was the blow-up of a leveraged hedge fund Archegos &amp;amp; how it caused $billions in losses to its bank/broker. A primer to what it means to be a brokerage for such trades, the risk to reward, and more.
Being a broker is almost like running an insurance business, you keep earning brokerage income (like premium) &amp;amp; are always one black swan or mega volatile day away from giving it all back and more if one large client or many small clients default at the same time.</description></item><item><title>Market size estimates</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/maket-size-estimates/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/maket-size-estimates/</guid><description>Market size estimate (Revenue), from the two reports that I just read. Stockbroking: ~$3billion according to ICRA. Gold loan: ~$162billion according to MorningContext.</description></item><item><title>CNBC India business leader award</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cnbc-india-business-leader-awards/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cnbc-india-business-leader-awards/</guid><description>2014: CNBC Young Turks, our first time on TV 2021: CNBC India business leader awards Some year 2020 has been for Zerodha &amp;amp; the capital markets. The challenge though is to help clients avoid making trading mistakes. We are attempting with Nudge &amp;amp; Zerodha Varsity.</description></item><item><title>Making taxes easy with Vishvajit Sonagara of Quicko</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-taxes-easy-with-vishvajit-sonagara-of-quicko/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-taxes-easy-with-vishvajit-sonagara-of-quicko/</guid><description>A misconception among traders is that you need to file ITR only if you make a profit. Many also don&amp;rsquo;t file since it&amp;rsquo;s quite complex, but Quicko has simplified it drastically. In our new Rainmatter podcast I talk to Vishvajit on their journey.</description></item><item><title>Spending on brand name keywords</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/should-you-spend-on-brand-name-keywords/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/should-you-spend-on-brand-name-keywords/</guid><description>The only time we ran Google ads was when our competition ran ads when people searched for Zerodha. We ran ads against &amp;ldquo;zerodha(.)competition(.)com&amp;rdquo;. Our lamest expenditure to date. Hoping this order is a precedent &amp;amp; helps startups save on unnecessary costs</description></item><item><title>Yearly demat account growth for the last 20 years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/yearly-demat-account-growth-for-20-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/yearly-demat-account-growth-for-20-years/</guid><description>Consider the yearly demat addition for the last 20yrs. Stockbroking is as high beta as it can get. When someone asks for my view on the future, I usually ask them for their view on Nifty. The last boom &amp;amp; bust was in 2007-08, took 10 yrs to get back to those numbers. A high beta business is one that has a higher sensitivity to the market (Nifty). If Nifty does well, business outperforms the market by a fair bit, and if Nifty doesn&amp;rsquo;t, it underperforms the market by a fair bit.</description></item><item><title>How big was Jan 2021 for the broking industry?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-big-was-jan-2021-for-broking/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-big-was-jan-2021-for-broking/</guid><description>How big was Jan 2021 for the broking industry? The best year for the markets since 2010 was by far 2014. Nifty was up more than 30% and the industry added 13 lakh new Demat accounts in 1 year. And, Jan 2021, just in 1 month 17 lakh new Demat accounts were added. Water buffaloGrimacing face</description></item><item><title>Being at the right place at right time and surviving</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/right-place-right-time-survival/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/right-place-right-time-survival/</guid><description>Right place right timeSmiling face with open mouthBut damn it&amp;rsquo;s tough to survive &amp;amp; be there when it matters. Zerodha probably started when I started trading 15 years before 2010. It&amp;rsquo;s been 25 years of ups &amp;amp; many downs, almost gave up many times. If it works out you are called passionate, if not foolish.</description></item><item><title>Free &amp; open-source software (FOSS) — one of the reasons behind Zerodha's success</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/foss-the-reason-for-zerodhas-success/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/foss-the-reason-for-zerodhas-success/</guid><description>Free &amp;amp; open-source software (FOSS) is the main reason for the success of Zerodha as K writes.
https://nadh.in/blog/the-atmanirbhartha-of-open-source-software</description></item><item><title>The fallacy of predictions</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-fallacy-of-predictions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-fallacy-of-predictions/</guid><description>Even after all my years of experience, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more wrong in predicting the direction of our business in 2020. These expert predictions should be taken with a pinch of salt, most of times the odds are equal to tossing a coin.</description></item><item><title>The twisted world of illegal CFDs &amp; binary options</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Total addressable market for brokers</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/total-addressable-market-for-brokers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/total-addressable-market-for-brokers/</guid><description>Since broking is hot post-COVID, inspite of all the spike in trading volumes and activity, the total addressable market is just ~1.5 million users. I had shared this pre-Covid. Broking is super hot now, but this TAM (Total addressable market) hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed, if anything it has reduced. Btw, the revenue-generating active day traders + F&amp;amp;O crowd is not more than ~1.5mil in spite of the spike in trading activity/volumes. This active crowd is unlikely to go up because most day and F&amp;amp;O traders stop within 6 months.</description></item><item><title>Why advertising doesn't work</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-advertising-doesnt-work/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-advertising-doesnt-work/</guid><description>https://freakonomics.com/podcast/advertising-part-2/ This is a great listen from Freakonomics on whether advertising works. The reason we could bootstrap was that we never spent on ads. With no ads, a business is forced to constantly think &amp;amp; do things to get customer love and organic growth. The only time we experimented with ads was for our brand keyword, show our website if you search &amp;ldquo;Zerodha&amp;rdquo;. We stopped immediately when we realized that it made no difference to the traffic and the ad was essentially cannibalizing our organic traffic while costing us money.</description></item><item><title>The flipside of effecient companies</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-flipside-of-effecient-companies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-flipside-of-effecient-companies/</guid><description>https://zenx.medium.com/the-six-dots-problem-re-imagining-india-b7d81b223827 The flip side of tech-first businesses like ours is that we don&amp;rsquo;t create as many jobs. We are around the same number of employees today at 3.8mn clients as we were when we had 1mn clients. As @kunalb11 says, inefficiency is the biggest employer in the world. A way to solve this employment problem is to enable jobs(economy) not just in the top 6 cities, but maybe 600 towns/villages. The only +ve this year has been that maybe some it is happening.</description></item><item><title>Forbes cover</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/forbes-cover/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/forbes-cover/</guid><description>https://tradingqna.com/t/personal-lessons-from-20-years-of-trading-broking-working/94600
Almost unreal that we could represent Zerodha on the cover of Forbes. Some personal lessons from the many highs &amp;amp; many lows in this 20-year journey working, trading, trying to build different types of businesses, &amp;amp; more.
Businesses can be built in multiple ways. Don&amp;rsquo;t try to cut-copy-paste what others are doing - it mostly won’t work. Do what feels right to you. Your instincts on what is right will work better when you build a business/career around what you love.</description></item><item><title>CRED curious: Nithin Kamath in conversation with Kunal Shah</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cred-curious-nithin-kamath-in-conversation-with/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/cred-curious-nithin-kamath-in-conversation-with/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Nikhil and Me on SNFConversations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nikhil-and-me-on-snfconversations/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nikhil-and-me-on-snfconversations/</guid><description>They say it is tough to be in business with family. @kamath_nikhil &amp;amp; I have been doing stuff together forever, never a fight &amp;amp; couldn&amp;rsquo;t have had a better partner. Btw, it helps when you are like the role modelWinking face. Weirdly first time together on an interview https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oiC-CuyUAK4&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be</description></item><item><title>ESOP buyback - one of the highlights of the Zerodha journey</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/esop-buyback-one-of-the-highlights-of-the-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/esop-buyback-one-of-the-highlights-of-the-zerodha/</guid><description>We just provided liquidity to everyone on the team through an ESOP buyback. My most satisfying day as CEO of @zerodhaonline .</description></item><item><title>Has there been a surge in investors from tier 2 and 3 cities?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/has-there-been-a-surge-in-investors-from-tier-2-3/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/has-there-been-a-surge-in-investors-from-tier-2-3/</guid><description>The reason for the noise around markets growing in tier 2/3 cities is because everyone tracks users based on address proof. Lot of people migrate from small towns to cities for jobs but address proof remains the same, hence misleading. By IP address for us: 75% from top 20 cities. Everyone = Financial services firms Map= Google analytics</description></item><item><title>On Zerodha IPO</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-zerodha-ipo/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-zerodha-ipo/</guid><description>Thanks for the love @rajeshsawhney , our edge as a business is the agility, it helps us compete against those with deep pockets. IPO invariably will mean losing some of that agility. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if we&amp;rsquo;d want to IPO especially in times like now when everyone seems deep pockets.Grimacing face</description></item><item><title>The Success Story Of Zerodha's SMART Business Journey ft. Nithin Kamath | The Ranveer Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-success-story-of-zerodhas-smart-business-ft/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-success-story-of-zerodhas-smart-business-ft/</guid><description>An interaction with Ranveer from Beer Biceps talking about building Zerodha, how to do business, and life.</description></item><item><title>Bootstrapping vs Funding – a tax arbitrage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bootstrapping-vs-funding-a-tax-arbitrage/</guid><description>Promoters of businesses to professional investors, now chase “growth” and increase valuations to sell their stake in the business instead of trying to earn profits and taking the earnings out through dividends — to save on taxes and earn more efficiently.</description></item><item><title>Direct Market Access (DMA) for retail investors?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/direct-market-access-dma-for-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/direct-market-access-dma-for-retail-investors/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Stock trading games &amp; copy trading platforms in India?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-trading-games-copy-trading-platforms-in/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-trading-games-copy-trading-platforms-in/</guid><description>My thoughts on copy-trading and social trading platforms and why they aren&amp;rsquo;t feasible in India right now.</description></item><item><title>The Success Story Of Zerodha's SMART Business Journey ft. Nithin Kamath | The Ranveer Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beer-biceps-zerodha-interview/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beer-biceps-zerodha-interview/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Learning Sessions: Unfiltered deep dive with Nithin Kamath, Founder and CEO, Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/learning-sessions-unfiltered-deep-dive-with-nithin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/learning-sessions-unfiltered-deep-dive-with-nithin/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The race to Zero – Can the Indian brokerage industry survive?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-race-to-zero-can-the-indian-brokerage-industry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-race-to-zero-can-the-indian-brokerage-industry/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The Zerodha story: Nithin Kamath shares his bootstrapped entrepreneurial journey</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-zerodha-story-nithin-kamath-shares-his-journey/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-zerodha-story-nithin-kamath-shares-his-journey/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>