<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>business on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/business/</link><description>Recent content in business on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The broking business has a hard growth ceiling</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-broking-business-has-a-hard-growth-ceiling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-broking-business-has-a-hard-growth-ceiling/</guid><description>Broking is a unique business because there&amp;rsquo;s a hard ceiling on how much we can grow and the rate at which we can grow. What most people don&amp;rsquo;t realise is that SEBI has set a 15% open interest (OI) cap at the broker level.
No single broker can hold more than 15% of the total market OI. This restriction exists to mitigate the risk of concentration from any single broker becoming too large.</description></item><item><title>Open-source projects from Zerodha Tech team</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-projects-from-zerodha-tech-team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/open-source-projects-from-zerodha-tech-team/</guid><description>The number of full-fledged Free and open-source software (FOSS) products and initiatives coming out of the 4th Phase, JP Nagar (Zerodha Tech), must be unprecedented for a team of its size globally.
All of these projects started as a way to solve problems we faced internally and were then open sourced. We use them at scale in our stack, and several large organisations and even government departments globally use many of these tools today.</description></item><item><title>Why most brokers don’t build their own OMS/RMS</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-most-brokers-dont-build/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-most-brokers-dont-build/</guid><description>One of the lesser-known things about stock brokers is that most brokers don&amp;rsquo;t actually own their entire tech stack. There&amp;rsquo;s usually a third-party vendor providing the core order management system (OMS) and risk management system (RMS). Think of OMS/RMS as being similar to the core banking systems that Infosys or Oracle provides for banks.
The OMS/RMS is basically the heart of a broking operation. If this breaks, trading stops. Vendors in our business include Omennest, Kambala, 63 Moons, Rupeeseed, etc.</description></item><item><title>On today’s issue caused by the Cloudflare outage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-today-issue-caused-by-the-cloudflare-outage/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/on-today-issue-caused-by-the-cloudflare-outage/</guid><description>Cloudflare powers approximately 20-25% of all internet traffic globally. It&amp;rsquo;s the infrastructure behind millions of websites and apps—from content delivery and DDoS protection to DNS services. When Cloudflare has an outage, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t just affect one company; it impacts a significant chunk of the internet simultaneously.
Today, they had a brief outage that affected Kite along with numerous other brokers, fintech platforms, and online services worldwide.
This is why we built Kite Backup on WhatsApp.</description></item><item><title>Robinhood makes $150 million a year just from instant withdrawal fee</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-makes-150-million-a-year-just-from-instant-withdrawal-fee/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-makes-150-million-a-year-just-from-instant-withdrawal-fee/</guid><description>I just discovered that Robinhood will generate approximately $150 million (~₹1,300 crores) in revenue from the fees it charges for processing instant client withdrawals. Their cost to process these is around $35–40 million, which means a clean $100 million to the bottom line, and that’s just from instant withdrawals. 😬
As an Indian startup with some scale, founders dream of generating revenue like this from non-core products. Hence the rush to introduce everything: loans, insurance, payments, and other financial services.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha LIQUIDCASE grows to ₹6,000 crore AUM in under two years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-liquidcase-grows-to-6000-crore-aum-in-under-two-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodha-liquidcase-grows-to-6000-crore-aum-in-under-two-years/</guid><description>Zerodha LIQUIDCASE is India&amp;rsquo;s first liquid ETF with a growth NAV, and we launched it in January 2024. In just under two years, it&amp;rsquo;s incredible that the AUM has reached almost ₹6,000 crores.
All of this growth is organic, from traders and investors discovering the ETF and investing in it. We haven&amp;rsquo;t really spoken about it much, and you can&amp;rsquo;t pay commissions on an ETF anyway.
The innovation here was simple: no dividends, because they were tax-inefficient and a pain to redeem and track.</description></item><item><title>How India’s tax structure rewards growth over profits</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-indias-tax-structure-rewards-growth-over-profits/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-indias-tax-structure-rewards-growth-over-profits/</guid><description>If you take money out of a business as dividends, the effective tax rate is 52% (25% corporate tax + 35.5% on personal income). Through capital gains, it’s just 14.95% (with cess).
Why does this matter? Here’s what you should know if you invest in IPOs.
If you’re an investor (especially a VC), the math is simple: reduce corporate tax by showing minimal profits or losses. Spend (Burn) on acquiring users, build a growth narrative, and then sell shares at a higher valuation while paying much lower tax.</description></item><item><title>Didn’t expect our support for FFmpeg to get this much love</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/didnt-expect-our-support-for-ffmpeg-to-get-this-much-love/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/didnt-expect-our-support-for-ffmpeg-to-get-this-much-love/</guid><description>The amount of love this has gotten is quite crazy. I was just asking K, &amp;lsquo;How does it make sense that there are tech companies worth billions and trillions of dollars who use these pieces of open source software without which they could not exist, and yet are unwilling to fund them?&amp;rsquo;
We’ve been funding open source projects from ~2018 on and off before setting up FLOSS/fund in 2024. We run on open source, so supporting is a no-brainer.</description></item><item><title>Do old brand strategies still work?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/do-old-brand-strategies-still-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/do-old-brand-strategies-still-work/</guid><description>Question for founders &amp;amp; marketing folks: Can brands still rely on the same tactics and strategies that worked in the past, or do changing times demand new strategies?
Here&amp;rsquo;s the context: Our AUM share is growing (people with more money trust us), but our demat share is shrinking (fewer new accounts). The people with money are sticking with us, but many others aren&amp;rsquo;t opening accounts with us 😬. Most likely, the newer and younger, and people from tier 2 and 3 towns, are probably investing elsewhere.</description></item><item><title>About MCP and the future of investing and trading in a world of AI</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/about-mcp-and-the-future-of-investing-and-trading-in-a-world-of-ai/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/about-mcp-and-the-future-of-investing-and-trading-in-a-world-of-ai/</guid><description>I keep asking K about what all this progress in AI means for our business. It feels to me like we&amp;rsquo;re at the very beginning of a massive shift in how financial services will work.
At some point, I think all of it, from investing and trading to banking and payments, will happen through custom AI-powered apps built by users themselves using natural language instructions.
In that world, what&amp;rsquo;s the role of a broker?</description></item><item><title>What we think about Jio-BlackRock's entry into broking</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-we-think-about-jio-blackrocks-entry-into-broking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-we-think-about-jio-blackrocks-entry-into-broking/</guid><description>Many people asked me about Jio-BlackRock getting a stockbroking license. Firstly, this is great news. The biggest issue for the Indian markets is a lack of breadth in participation. We&amp;rsquo;re largely limited to the top 10 crore Indians.
If anyone can expand the markets beyond the top 10 crore Indians, it&amp;rsquo;s probably Jio with all its distribution might. As for how many new Indian investors have the money to invest in the market, I don&amp;rsquo;t know.</description></item><item><title>At the EY's World Entrepreneur event</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/at-the-eys-world-entrepreneur-event/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/at-the-eys-world-entrepreneur-event/</guid><description>Spent the last week in Monaco at the EY World Entrepreneur of the Year event — the first time I’ve ever been part of something like this. And yes, I was “judged” for the first time since school — group discussions and all. 😬
I didn’t win. As Zerodha, we’re building only for India, with a single source of revenue. I guess the judges were looking for something more global, more diversified.</description></item><item><title>Are Play Store and App Store ratings truly reliable?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/are-play-store-and-app-store-ratings-truly-reliable/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/are-play-store-and-app-store-ratings-truly-reliable/</guid><description>I wonder how many Google Play Store and Apple App Store reviews are genuine. I was going through Zerodha&amp;rsquo;s reviews and compared them with those of other financial services apps in India. Most of the 5-star reviews seem fake—many even read like AI-generated content.
I&amp;rsquo;m guessing many apps are either willingly or forcibly buying ratings to rank higher in their category. So there&amp;rsquo;s probably an entire parallel economy selling app ratings.</description></item><item><title>Why Zerodha chose no Ads</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-chose-no-ads/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-zerodha-chose-no-ads/</guid><description>Over 1.6 crore Indians trade and invest with us. Almost 30% of these investors came to us through referrals by other Zerodha customers. Today, all Zerodha investors trust us with 6 lakh crores of their assets.
We may be the only B2C company to have reached this scale without ever advertising. In hindsight, not advertising has helped us stay true to our philosophy of not pushing people to trade, no spam, etc.</description></item><item><title>Why we chose CDSL</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-we-chose-cdsl/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-we-chose-cdsl/</guid><description>We started our business as a depository participant in 2016, and we had to choose between NSDL &amp;amp; CDSL. We only went ahead with CDSL because they had a local representative, Harisha, in Bengaluru.
After that, pretty much all the other new brokers also chose CDSL. Of course, this only worked because CDSL ensured that their tech could handle the scale of all this new business.
The increase in CDSL demats from 2016 was almost entirely due to Harisha and the butterfly effect🦋 😀</description></item><item><title>Regulations are like a double-edged sword</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/regulations-are-like-a-double-edged-sword/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/regulations-are-like-a-double-edged-sword/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a saying, &amp;ldquo;You live by the sword, you die by the sword.&amp;rdquo; For regulated business, it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;you live by regulations and die by regulations.&amp;rdquo;
Regulations are like a double-edged sword. They can be a moat for the business, but at the same time, they can make your business model invalid overnight. Regulations are easier when explicit (SEBI) than implicit (RBI), but I guess it is because RBI has to regulate a wide variety of intermediaries.</description></item><item><title>SEBI's new rules for direct payout of securities</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-new-rules-for-direct-payout-of-securities/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebis-new-rules-for-direct-payout-of-securities/</guid><description>While SEBI is tightening rules to make the markets safer on the one hand, it is also making things simple on the other.
Starting from October 14th, shares bought will be directly credited to the customer&amp;rsquo;s Demat account through net settlement. This significantly simplifies our DP process, which today involves receiving shares for the entire group of clients and then allocating them based on purchases made, i.e., gross settlement.
And this is much safer, too.</description></item><item><title>Impact of SEBI's on new rules for index derivatives</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-sebis-cirular-on-new-rules-for-index-derivatives/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-sebis-cirular-on-new-rules-for-index-derivatives/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the potential impact of only one weekly expiry of index derivatives per exchange and contract sizes going up by around 2.5 times.
As things stand, assuming that those trading weekly don&amp;rsquo;t move on to trading monthly, the impact will be ~60% of overall F&amp;amp;O trades and ~30% of our overall orders.
I guess things will become much clearer from November 20th. We will then decide on our change in pricing structure, based on the impact on the business.</description></item><item><title>Impact of revision in Exchange Transaction Charges and STT</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-revision-in-exchange-transaction-charges-and-stt/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-revision-in-exchange-transaction-charges-and-stt/</guid><description>Equity delivery will continue to be free at @zerodhaonline. As of now, we are not making any changes to our brokerage.
From today, Oct 1, 2024,
For options: STT increases to 0.1% from 0.0625%, and transaction charge decreases to 0.035% from 0.0495%.
This results in the cost of trades seeing a net increase of 0.02303% or Rs 2303 per crore of premium on the selling side on NSE and of 0.</description></item><item><title>14-years of Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/14-years-of-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/14-years-of-zerodha/</guid><description>A few highlights from FY2023/24 @zerodhaonline
For years now, I&amp;rsquo;d been talking about regulatory risk in running a brokerage, and this was the year when all the risks materialized at the same time.
We had plenty of positives.
Content
Today, we have some of the best content on all things stock market with @ZerodhaVarsity videos, Varsity Live, Zero1, @zerodhamarkets and more. All this is not just in English but also Hindi.</description></item></channel></rss>