<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>markets on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/markets/</link><description>Recent content in markets on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/markets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Volatility in silver prices shows why position sizing matters more than direction</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/volatility-in-silver-prices-shows-why-position-sizing-matters-more-than-direction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/volatility-in-silver-prices-shows-why-position-sizing-matters-more-than-direction/</guid><description>This is the chart of MCX Silver Futures. This type of move is what every trader dreams of capturing, but it can also be a nightmare to manage without a good understanding of how to size your positions. Especially when something moves ~10% intraday.
On a side note, there seems to be a sharp increase in commodity trading volumes.</description></item><item><title>Risk management lessons from Tom Basso</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-lessons-from-tom-basso/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-lessons-from-tom-basso/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been noticing many recent IPOs continue running up for 2-3 days after listing. While demand and supply factors (limited free float) are obvious reasons, there may also be technical factors at play.
One common reason why traders blow up is because of poor position sizing. In other words, how much do you bet on a trade.
You can be right on direction 60% of the time and still lose everything if you size your positions poorly.</description></item><item><title>Why some IPOs keep rising even after listing day</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-some-ipos-keep-rising-even-after-listing-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-some-ipos-keep-rising-even-after-listing-day/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been noticing many recent IPOs continue running up for 2-3 days after listing. While demand and supply factors (limited free float) are obvious reasons, there may also be technical factors at play.
Let me explain the technical factor.
Many traders attempt to short these stocks intraday, expecting a fall, but if the stock hits the upper circuit, they get trapped with no buyers to sell to. This leads to what’s called a short delivery.</description></item><item><title>Unlisted market hype is blinding people to basic risks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/unlisted-market-hype-is-blinding-people-to-basic-risks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/unlisted-market-hype-is-blinding-people-to-basic-risks/</guid><description>Given how hot the IPO market is, I&amp;rsquo;m hearing some phenomenally stupid stories from the unlisted market. People are blindly punting on so-called &amp;ldquo;pre-IPO&amp;rdquo; companies hoping they&amp;rsquo;ll make bigger gains than during the actual IPO.
The greed is causing people to ignore some hard realities: these shares already come with 100–500% markups, ridiculous commissions, and terrible pricing. The biggest risk? There have been numerous cases where the IPO price ended up lower than the price at which people bought shares in the unlisted market.</description></item><item><title>India’s $3 trillion in idle gold needs smarter financialization.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</guid><description>Indian households hold ~$3 trillion in gold (World Gold Council estimate), sitting idle in lockers. Meanwhile, equity investments fund companies that need capital to grow. We need better ways to financialize this gold beyond just gold loans.</description></item><item><title>Why comparing India’s and US options volumes misses the point</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-comparing-indias-and-us-options-volumes-misses-the-point/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-comparing-indias-and-us-options-volumes-misses-the-point/</guid><description>It’s ridiculous to see people comparing options trading volumes in India and the US and claiming that we’re overleveraged. For starters, the comparison itself is flawed. People often look at the number of contracts traded, not the premiums or the actual value involved.
If anything, India is significantly less leveraged than the US, even taking into account the fact that our markets are 15–20 years behind theirs.
Consider this: in the US, the margin funding market (the equivalent of MTF in India) recently crossed $1 trillion.</description></item><item><title>What the Jane Street probe tells us about India’s market oversight</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-the-jane-street-probe-tells-us-about-indias-market-oversight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-the-jane-street-probe-tells-us-about-indias-market-oversight/</guid><description>You’ve got to hand it to SEBI for going after Jane Street. If the allegations are true, it’s blatant market manipulation.
The shocking part? They kept at it even after receiving warnings from the exchanges. Maybe this is what happens when you&amp;rsquo;re used to the lenient U.S. regulatory regime. Think about the structure of U.S. markets: dark pools, payment for order flow, and other loopholes that allow hedge funds to make billions off retail investors.</description></item><item><title>First real market correction after COVID</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/first-real-market-correction-after-covid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/first-real-market-correction-after-covid/</guid><description>For investors who started investing after the pandemic, this is the first real market correction. Markets are cyclical, and given the way our markets went up from late 2020, this fall was inevitable. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how good the data is, but it seems like the number of investors stopping their SIPs has gone up. This is the wrong thing to do. What an SIP helps you do is to average your investments across different market cycles.</description></item><item><title>Markets are correcting</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/markets-are-correcting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/markets-are-correcting/</guid><description>The markets are finally correcting. Given that markets swing between extremes, they can fall more just like they rose to the peak.
I&amp;rsquo;ve no idea where the markets go from here, but I can tell you about the broking industry. We are seeing a massive drop in terms of both the number of traders and volumes.
Here is the trading volume chart. Across brokers, there&amp;rsquo;s a more than 30% drop in activity.</description></item><item><title>Nifty drawdown, is this time different?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nifty-drawdown-is-this-time-different/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nifty-drawdown-is-this-time-different/</guid><description>A 15-20% fall in a year is quite common. The question is: is this time different? 😬</description></item><item><title>Special live trading session on Budget day</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/special-live-trading-session-on-budget-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/special-live-trading-session-on-budget-day/</guid><description>So, the budget day is tomorrow, and yes, there is trading on a Saturday. Markets are bound to be volatile, so trade with caution.
If you are an active trader, I guess you should reduce trading size during event days. That is if you cannot stop yourself from trading.
By the way, Zerodha is probably the only broker which will allow you to do BTST (Buy today and sell tomorrow) trades on days of settlement holiday, like tomorrow.</description></item><item><title>Bear market ahead?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bear-market-ahead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bear-market-ahead/</guid><description>Link</description></item><item><title>Looking back on 2024</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/looking-back-on-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/looking-back-on-2024/</guid><description>Looking back, 2024 was probably the best year for the brokerage industry, and it&amp;rsquo;s starting to look like the best is behind us, at least for the foreseeable future. 😬
In terms of options turnover, we are back to 2022–23 levels. This is even before the impact of the increased lot sizes, which take effect in January 2025.
We just published a post reviewing 2024 at both Zerodha and across the broking industry.</description></item><item><title>New investor demographics in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/new-investor-demographics-in-india/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/new-investor-demographics-in-india/</guid><description>For the longest time, most of the investors in the Indian markets were more or less from the major metro cities. But this has changed dramatically after COVID. The bulk of new investors are from North India, and we&amp;rsquo;ve kinda missed out on getting them to invest with us.
This was something interesting that came up when I was catching up withAshish Chauhan as he shared the NSE India coffee table book.</description></item><item><title>SEBI order on scams</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-order-on-scams/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-order-on-scams/</guid><description>SEBI recently passed two orders related to two different scams.
In the first scam, an SME company raised Rs 44 crores through an SME-IPO to buy software, among other things. But the company that it was buying software from was a shell company complete with fake financials and a fake list of clients.
The second order was against a popular finfluencer who collected Rs 17 crores by selling courses, seminars, etc.</description></item><item><title>Money mistakes are the best form of financial literacy</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/money-mistakes-are-best-form-of-financial-literacy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/money-mistakes-are-best-form-of-financial-literacy/</guid><description>One good thing about all the post-pandemic excess in the stock market is that the Indian stock market has become a lot younger.
Of course, many of these young investors are doing a lot of things they shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be doing. But they are better off making all the mistakes when they are young and have very little to lose, than later in life when they have more money and responsibilities.</description></item><item><title>Impact of SEBI's on new rules for index derivatives</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-sebis-cirular-on-new-rules-for-index-derivatives/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-sebis-cirular-on-new-rules-for-index-derivatives/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s the potential impact of only one weekly expiry of index derivatives per exchange and contract sizes going up by around 2.5 times.
As things stand, assuming that those trading weekly don&amp;rsquo;t move on to trading monthly, the impact will be ~60% of overall F&amp;amp;O trades and ~30% of our overall orders.
I guess things will become much clearer from November 20th. We will then decide on our change in pricing structure, based on the impact on the business.</description></item><item><title>What changes due to a settlemet holiday?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-changes-at-zerodha-due-to-settlement-holiday/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-changes-at-zerodha-due-to-settlement-holiday/</guid><description>Today is a settlement holiday, and thus, settlements of funds and stocks don&amp;rsquo;t happen. This happens when banks in Maharashtra are closed, but trading on exchanges is open.
Most brokers don&amp;rsquo;t allow shares bought on Friday to be sold on Monday because of this. We @zerodhaonline are among the few brokers that allow you to sell stocks bought on Friday.
By the way, due to the settlement holiday, your equity intraday profit credits and F&amp;amp;O credits aren&amp;rsquo;t included in your trading balance or are not available for withdrawal today.</description></item><item><title>Indian companies returning home to capitalize on investor growth</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-companies-returning-home-to-capitalize-on-investor-growth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-companies-returning-home-to-capitalize-on-investor-growth/</guid><description>The number of companies with a market cap &amp;gt;$1 billion is at an all-time high. Along with this, the allocation of Indian households&amp;rsquo; investments in the stock market has also increased substantially. There are now 10 crore unique investors, compared to 3 crore in 2020. Thanks to the bull market and the ease of going public, there&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;lsquo;ghar-wapsi&amp;rsquo; of Indian companies incorporated outside.
To add to this, the Ministry of Corporate Affairs (MCA) formally opened the doors of &amp;lsquo;reverse flipping&amp;rsquo; or coming home to India yesterday.</description></item><item><title>SEBI study on investor behavior in IPOs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-study-on-investor-behavior-in-ipos/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-study-on-investor-behavior-in-ipos/</guid><description>Gujarat accounts for about 9% of the total investor customer base, but they account for 40% of IPO participation in both retail and HNI categories.
IPO flipping (trading) in the Gujju genes. 😀
This data is from SEBI&amp;rsquo;s study on IPOs.
Read the entire study here.</description></item></channel></rss>