<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>markets on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/markets/</link><description>Recent content in markets on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/markets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Yearly demat account growth for the last 20 years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/yearly-demat-account-growth-for-20-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/yearly-demat-account-growth-for-20-years/</guid><description>Consider the yearly demat addition for the last 20yrs. Stockbroking is as high beta as it can get. When someone asks for my view on the future, I usually ask them for their view on Nifty. The last boom &amp;amp; bust was in 2007-08, took 10 yrs to get back to those numbers. A high beta business is one that has a higher sensitivity to the market (Nifty). If Nifty does well, business outperforms the market by a fair bit, and if Nifty doesn&amp;rsquo;t, it underperforms the market by a fair bit.</description></item><item><title>How big was Jan 2021 for the broking industry?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-big-was-jan-2021-for-broking/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-big-was-jan-2021-for-broking/</guid><description>How big was Jan 2021 for the broking industry? The best year for the markets since 2010 was by far 2014. Nifty was up more than 30% and the industry added 13 lakh new Demat accounts in 1 year. And, Jan 2021, just in 1 month 17 lakh new Demat accounts were added. Water buffaloGrimacing face</description></item><item><title>Podcast - Nikhil Kamath on The Ranveer Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nik-on-the-ranveer-show/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nik-on-the-ranveer-show/</guid><description>Keeping your emotions in check is the most important skill as a trader. The Bro @nikhilkamathcio is a master at this. He&amp;rsquo;s never missed a trading day in last 15 yrs &amp;amp; I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen him react to P&amp;amp;L. Nik on his journey with the very sharp @BeerBicepsGuy</description></item><item><title>The Gamestop saga and lessons for retail investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</guid><description>In the Gamestop saga, the media has loved telling the story of how Retail made a lot of money from Hedge funds. The reality is entirely different, almost everyone apart from retail has probably made money or benefited from this.
Firstly, yes, a couple of Hedge funds were sitting on large losses on Gamestop shorts. Now that stock is at $50, the losses also would be a fraction, if the shorts still held.</description></item><item><title>Rising financial awareness among Indians</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</guid><description>Financial awareness about the importance of saving and investing in India is increasing at the fastest rate ever, especially among millennials. Of course, stock markets doing well and lower bank FD rates are helping. But there are also a few structural changes afoot here. Historically financial products have been sold hard &amp;amp; mostly in person. Products mostly sold based on promises of high returns (sales pitches in person leave no audit trail).</description></item><item><title>Shorting and Indian Capital Markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</guid><description>Can retail traders are cause a “short squeeze” in India like they did in stocks like GameStop and AMC entertainment in the US? It cannot, and I explain why in this post. Join the discussion here.</description></item><item><title>Beyond misleading trading turnover numbers — the actual size of Indian capital markets?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beyond-misleading-trading-turnover-numbers-the-actual-size-of-indian-capital-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beyond-misleading-trading-turnover-numbers-the-actual-size-of-indian-capital-markets/</guid><description>Looking at trading turnover to estimate capital market size is misleading. Most trades are leveraged &amp;amp; ideally we should look at the margins being traded, not the trade value. Turnover this way will be less than 10% of the trading turnover declared.
The best way to estimate the size of the Indian capital markets is by checking the revenue pool. This I think, is less than Rs 50k crores across 1500+ brokers, exchanges, &amp;amp; depositories.</description></item><item><title>The fallacy of predictions</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-fallacy-of-predictions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-fallacy-of-predictions/</guid><description>Even after all my years of experience, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more wrong in predicting the direction of our business in 2020. These expert predictions should be taken with a pinch of salt, most of times the odds are equal to tossing a coin.</description></item><item><title>The twisted world of illegal CFDs &amp; binary options</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Total addressable market for brokers</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/total-addressable-market-for-brokers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/total-addressable-market-for-brokers/</guid><description>Since broking is hot post-COVID, inspite of all the spike in trading volumes and activtity, the total addressable market is just ~1.5 million users. I had shared this pre-Covid. Broking is super hot now, but this TAM (Total addressable market) hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed, if anything it has reduced. Btw, the revenue-generating active day traders + F&amp;amp;O crowd is not more than ~1.5mil in spite of the spike in trading activity/volumes. This active crowd is unlikely to go up because most day and F&amp;amp;O traders stop within 6 months.</description></item><item><title>Robinhood pays $65M to settle SEC charges on payment for order flow disclosures</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-pays-65m-to-settle-sec-charges-on-for/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-pays-65m-to-settle-sec-charges-on-for/</guid><description>The Robinhood SEC settlement over order flow disclosures grabbed some headlines even in India. Since people might be wondering if this happens here, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. Unlike the US, all order in India are matched and executed on the exchanges. We have no concept of order flow here.</description></item><item><title>Podcast: Sandeep Parekh on the evolution of the Indian market and securities regulations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-sandeep-parekh-on-the-evolution-of-the-and/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-sandeep-parekh-on-the-evolution-of-the-and/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EihRbTTLLy0&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be This is a must-watch for those interested in the Indian securities market. @SandeepParekh we need to find a way to get you to do more of this. :)</description></item><item><title>A product to get more Indians to save and invest</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</guid><description>To get the next 10 crore Indians, the traditional financial product might not work. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I think is needed to get these people to start saving and investing.</description></item><item><title>Evolution of the Indian stock broking industry since the Harshad Mehta scam - Scam92 TV Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/evolution-of-the-indian-stock-broking-industry-the/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/evolution-of-the-indian-stock-broking-industry-the/</guid><description>#Scam1992TheHarshadMehtaStory - a thread on everything that has changed since then in the world of Indian stockbroking.
Today the settlement cycle is 2 days &amp;amp; SEBI is hinting at a 1-day cycle soon (first few countries in the world). Back then, it was 14 days (the time within which you have to pay full money and take delivery of stocks or deliver stocks if sold).
Today, a customer can’t buy stocks without the minimum money in the account or sell without stocks in Demat.</description></item><item><title>Direct Market Access (DMA) for retail investors?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/direct-market-access-dma-for-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/direct-market-access-dma-for-retail-investors/</guid><description/></item><item><title>What does it take to win at trading?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</guid><description>Learnings from interactions with thousands of traders and my own successes and failures.</description></item><item><title>Introducing ‘Innerworth – Mind over markets’</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The race to Zero – Can the Indian brokerage industry survive?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-race-to-zero-can-the-indian-brokerage-industry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-race-to-zero-can-the-indian-brokerage-industry/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>