<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>markets on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/markets/</link><description>Recent content in markets on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/markets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Recent updates to make investing easier for NRIs</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recent-updates-to-make-investing-easier-for-nris/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/recent-updates-to-make-investing-easier-for-nris/</guid><description>We at Zerodha , have ~40k NRI customers with an average account value of ₹40L, nearly 10x our overall average of ₹3.6L for resident accounts. Most of them opened accounts the hard way, with physical paperwork. If onboarding were fully online, this base would be much larger.
SEBI recently made changes that have allowed us to significantly simplify Non-PIS NRI accounts: they now work like resident accounts, with fully online Aadhaar-based onboarding (when visiting India) and intraday, BTST, and F&amp;amp;O access with no need for a CP code.</description></item><item><title>Get realtime company updates on WhatsApp with Tijori Alerts</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/get-realtime-company-updates-on-whatsapp-with-tijori-alerts/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/get-realtime-company-updates-on-whatsapp-with-tijori-alerts/</guid><description>Access to information is what drives prices in markets. While there&amp;rsquo;s no shortage of information today, the real challenge is figuring out what actually matters and getting it in time.
Exchange filings, earnings, management commentary, and conference calls. When something material comes out, prices react almost instantly. The faster you get the information, the better your odds of reacting sensibly.
Institutions and high-frequency trading desks scan exchange filings the moment they&amp;rsquo;re published and act within milliseconds.</description></item><item><title>Commodity markets look very different today</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/commodity-markets-look-very-different-today/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/commodity-markets-look-very-different-today/</guid><description>Up until a few years ago, commodity trading was more or less an afterthought. Most traders didn&amp;rsquo;t bother with it because liquidity was thin relative to NSE F&amp;amp;O.
But that&amp;rsquo;s changed dramatically, thanks to the spectacular rally in gold and silver. If you look at gold and silver as a percentage of total MCX trading volumes today, the numbers are kind of crazy. A lot of this increase has come at the expense of other commodities like crude.</description></item><item><title>Why a local election shuts India’s markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-a-local-election-shuts-indias-markets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-a-local-election-shuts-indias-markets/</guid><description>Indian stock exchanges are closed today for Mumbai’s municipal elections.
The fact that our exchanges, which have international linkages, are shut down for a local municipal election shows poor planning and a serious lack of appreciation for second-order effects.
As Munger said: “Show me the incentive, and I will show you the outcome.”
The holiday exists because no one who matters has any incentive to oppose the market holiday.
It also tells you how far we have to go before global investors take us seriously.</description></item><item><title>Check IPO lock-in period expiry on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-ipo-lock-in-period-expiry-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-ipo-lock-in-period-expiry-on-kite/</guid><description>When a company goes for an IPO, not all shareholders can sell their shares immediately. Certain categories of shareholders like promoters, early investors and ESOP holders have to wait anywhere between 30 days to 18 months before they can sell their shares.
Since these are large shareholders, whenever they sell, there can often be a downward move in the stock price. So if you are buying shares of companies that IPO&amp;rsquo;d recently, you should track when the lock-in period expires.</description></item><item><title>The broking business has a hard growth ceiling</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-broking-business-has-a-hard-growth-ceiling/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-broking-business-has-a-hard-growth-ceiling/</guid><description>Broking is a unique business because there&amp;rsquo;s a hard ceiling on how much we can grow and the rate at which we can grow. What most people don&amp;rsquo;t realise is that SEBI has set a 15% open interest (OI) cap at the broker level.
No single broker can hold more than 15% of the total market OI. This restriction exists to mitigate the risk of concentration from any single broker becoming too large.</description></item><item><title>A year of MTF launch and product growth</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-year-of-mtf-launch-and-product-growth/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-year-of-mtf-launch-and-product-growth/</guid><description>We launched our MTF product a year ago. Despite being one of the last brokers to offer this and without actively promoting it on the order screen or elsewhere, we captured ~5% of the market. But growth has plateaued along with the broader industry.
One surprising thing I have noticed is that customers don&amp;rsquo;t seem to care about MTF brokerage or know what they&amp;rsquo;re being charged. Our current brokerage is 0.</description></item><item><title>Volatility in silver prices shows why position sizing matters more than direction</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/volatility-in-silver-prices-shows-why-position-sizing-matters-more-than-direction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/volatility-in-silver-prices-shows-why-position-sizing-matters-more-than-direction/</guid><description>This is the chart of MCX Silver Futures. This type of move is what every trader dreams of capturing, but it can also be a nightmare to manage without a good understanding of how to size your positions. Especially when something moves ~10% intraday.
On a side note, there seems to be a sharp increase in commodity trading volumes.</description></item><item><title>Risk management lessons from Tom Basso</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-lessons-from-tom-basso/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-lessons-from-tom-basso/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been noticing many recent IPOs continue running up for 2-3 days after listing. While demand and supply factors (limited free float) are obvious reasons, there may also be technical factors at play.
One common reason why traders blow up is because of poor position sizing. In other words, how much do you bet on a trade.
You can be right on direction 60% of the time and still lose everything if you size your positions poorly.</description></item><item><title>Why some IPOs keep rising even after listing day</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-some-ipos-keep-rising-even-after-listing-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-some-ipos-keep-rising-even-after-listing-day/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been noticing many recent IPOs continue running up for 2-3 days after listing. While demand and supply factors (limited free float) are obvious reasons, there may also be technical factors at play.
Let me explain the technical factor.
Many traders attempt to short these stocks intraday, expecting a fall, but if the stock hits the upper circuit, they get trapped with no buyers to sell to. This leads to what’s called a short delivery.</description></item><item><title>Unlisted market hype is blinding people to basic risks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/unlisted-market-hype-is-blinding-people-to-basic-risks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/unlisted-market-hype-is-blinding-people-to-basic-risks/</guid><description>Given how hot the IPO market is, I&amp;rsquo;m hearing some phenomenally stupid stories from the unlisted market. People are blindly punting on so-called &amp;ldquo;pre-IPO&amp;rdquo; companies hoping they&amp;rsquo;ll make bigger gains than during the actual IPO.
The greed is causing people to ignore some hard realities: these shares already come with 100–500% markups, ridiculous commissions, and terrible pricing. The biggest risk? There have been numerous cases where the IPO price ended up lower than the price at which people bought shares in the unlisted market.</description></item><item><title>India’s $3 trillion in idle gold needs smarter financialization.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indias-3-trillion-in-idle-gold-needs-smarter-financialization/</guid><description>Indian households hold ~$3 trillion in gold (World Gold Council estimate), sitting idle in lockers. Meanwhile, equity investments fund companies that need capital to grow. We need better ways to financialize this gold beyond just gold loans.</description></item><item><title>Why comparing India’s and US options volumes misses the point</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-comparing-indias-and-us-options-volumes-misses-the-point/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-comparing-indias-and-us-options-volumes-misses-the-point/</guid><description>It’s ridiculous to see people comparing options trading volumes in India and the US and claiming that we’re overleveraged. For starters, the comparison itself is flawed. People often look at the number of contracts traded, not the premiums or the actual value involved.
If anything, India is significantly less leveraged than the US, even taking into account the fact that our markets are 15–20 years behind theirs.
Consider this: in the US, the margin funding market (the equivalent of MTF in India) recently crossed $1 trillion.</description></item><item><title>What the Jane Street probe tells us about India’s market oversight</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-the-jane-street-probe-tells-us-about-indias-market-oversight/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-the-jane-street-probe-tells-us-about-indias-market-oversight/</guid><description>You’ve got to hand it to SEBI for going after Jane Street. If the allegations are true, it’s blatant market manipulation.
The shocking part? They kept at it even after receiving warnings from the exchanges. Maybe this is what happens when you&amp;rsquo;re used to the lenient U.S. regulatory regime. Think about the structure of U.S. markets: dark pools, payment for order flow, and other loopholes that allow hedge funds to make billions off retail investors.</description></item><item><title>First real market correction after COVID</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/first-real-market-correction-after-covid/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/first-real-market-correction-after-covid/</guid><description>For investors who started investing after the pandemic, this is the first real market correction. Markets are cyclical, and given the way our markets went up from late 2020, this fall was inevitable. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how good the data is, but it seems like the number of investors stopping their SIPs has gone up. This is the wrong thing to do. What an SIP helps you do is to average your investments across different market cycles.</description></item><item><title>Markets are correcting</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/markets-are-correcting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/markets-are-correcting/</guid><description>The markets are finally correcting. Given that markets swing between extremes, they can fall more just like they rose to the peak.
I&amp;rsquo;ve no idea where the markets go from here, but I can tell you about the broking industry. We are seeing a massive drop in terms of both the number of traders and volumes.
Here is the trading volume chart. Across brokers, there&amp;rsquo;s a more than 30% drop in activity.</description></item><item><title>Nifty drawdown, is this time different?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nifty-drawdown-is-this-time-different/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nifty-drawdown-is-this-time-different/</guid><description>A 15-20% fall in a year is quite common. The question is: is this time different? 😬</description></item><item><title>Special live trading session on Budget day</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/special-live-trading-session-on-budget-day/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/special-live-trading-session-on-budget-day/</guid><description>So, the budget day is tomorrow, and yes, there is trading on a Saturday. Markets are bound to be volatile, so trade with caution.
If you are an active trader, I guess you should reduce trading size during event days. That is if you cannot stop yourself from trading.
By the way, Zerodha is probably the only broker which will allow you to do BTST (Buy today and sell tomorrow) trades on days of settlement holiday, like tomorrow.</description></item><item><title>Bear market ahead?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bear-market-ahead/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bear-market-ahead/</guid><description>Link</description></item><item><title>Looking back on 2024</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/looking-back-on-2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/looking-back-on-2024/</guid><description>Looking back, 2024 was probably the best year for the brokerage industry, and it&amp;rsquo;s starting to look like the best is behind us, at least for the foreseeable future. 😬
In terms of options turnover, we are back to 2022–23 levels. This is even before the impact of the increased lot sizes, which take effect in January 2025.
We just published a post reviewing 2024 at both Zerodha and across the broking industry.</description></item></channel></rss>