<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>markets on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/markets/</link><description>Recent content in markets on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/markets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Intraday equity trading in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/intraday-equity-trading-in-india/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/intraday-equity-trading-in-india/</guid><description>Intraday equity is the abandoned baby of Indian markets.
Since the time leverage restrictions were introduced, intraday equity volumes have stagnated, despite the mother of all bull runs. Apart from leverage, the fact that securities Transaction Tax (STT) is higher for intraday equity and futures compared to options has also hurt the volumes. The hope is STT on intraday equity and futures will reduce some day. 😬
Intraday equity trading turnover is important because it significantly reduces the impact cost for those making equity delivery trades.</description></item><item><title>Zerodha's remarkable market growth post COVID</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodhas-remarkable-market-growth-post-covid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/zerodhas-remarkable-market-growth-post-covid/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s unreal how much our markets have expanded post-COVID. Zerodha customers now hold ~ Rs 4.5 lakh crores worth of assets in their demat accounts.</description></item><item><title>Strong post-pandemic growth in Indian markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/strong-post-pandemic-growth-in-indian-markets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/strong-post-pandemic-growth-in-indian-markets/</guid><description>Indian market participation has grown more in the last 4 years than in the preceding decade. All this growth has come post-pandemic.
This chart from @theeconomist shows how Indian markets have grown. Here are a few data points.
Indian household assets.
NSE has 9 crore unique PANs, which is a reasonable estimate of total unique investors. We have about 4.39 crore unique mutual fund investors.
Link to the full article.</description></item><item><title>Advancements in capital market regulations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/advancements-in-capital-market-regulations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/advancements-in-capital-market-regulations/</guid><description>After a long time, we have had massive activity in the IPO market, with Rs 2.6lk cr blocked in bank accounts for IPOs worth Rs 7.6k cr.
If this was 2003, it would take 16 working days (or ~1 month), and the entire money would have moved to investment bankers and cost investors (an interest forego) at least 0.5% (assuming 6% pa) or Rs 1300 crores.
T+16 became T+12, T+6, and from Sep 2023 it is T+3 (~1week).</description></item><item><title>Bengaluru needs a Dalal Street</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bengaluru-maybe-needs-a-dalal-street/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/bengaluru-maybe-needs-a-dalal-street/</guid><description>Bengaluru maybe needs a &amp;ldquo;Dalal Street&amp;rdquo; as well. 😬
Symbolism to indicate that over 50% of all retail trades in India, in a way, originate from Bengaluru, either from brokers or their tech teams based out of here.
13 years ago, when we were first starting, the first question asked by many was, who starts a brokerage firm in Bengaluru?</description></item><item><title>Financialization of India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financialization-of-india/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financialization-of-india/</guid><description>NSE just announced that there are 15 crore investors registered, of which 8 crore are unique. Much of this growth has come in the last 3–4 years. The pace of financialization is crazy, and this is in no small part thanks to the exchanges, especially NSE. This is vital for India to grow.
A case in point, this year, total Sovereign Gold Bonds (SGB) issued is ~10% of total gold imports.</description></item><item><title>Discussing SEBI's consultation paper on regulating finfluencers</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/discussing-sebi-consultation-paper-on-regulating-finfluencers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/discussing-sebi-consultation-paper-on-regulating-finfluencers/</guid><description>“SEBI’s job is to remove ignorance from the markets and not stupidity,” from Sandeep; if I had to summarise this conversation in one sentence that Abid and I had with Sandeep, on SEBI&amp;rsquo;s consultation paper on regulating influencers. I guess our job as brokers is also the same, which is the reason why we launched Verified P&amp;amp;L and spend time trying to educate users on all things trading and investing through Varsity, etc.</description></item><item><title>A few thoughts on finfluencers, P&amp;L screenshots, and paying brokerage referrals.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-finfluencers-profit-and-loss-screenshots-referrals/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-finfluencers-profit-and-loss-screenshots-referrals/</guid><description>People have been asking me about Finfluencers, P&amp;amp;L screenshots, and paying brokerage referrals. I shared a few thoughts here. If you have any questions, you can post them on the same Tradingqna link, and I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to answer.</description></item><item><title>India is many countries in one</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-is-many-countries-in-one/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-is-many-countries-in-one/</guid><description>&amp;ldquo;India has 140 crore people, and if X% can become customers because of Y% in a developed country,&amp;rdquo; is a dangerous line of thinking for founders and investors.
While building for up to 3% of English-speaking affluent Indians is easier, it&amp;rsquo;s much harder and complex beyond that. Something we are pondering at Zerodha as well.
I guess the right way to think of this is, India is many countries in one.</description></item><item><title>A bull market without momentum</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-bull-market-without-momentum/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-bull-market-without-momentum/</guid><description>Markets are back at all-time highs, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t feel like a bull run because retail activity isn&amp;rsquo;t picking up. Active clients on NSE, Google &amp;amp; social media trends are way below all-time highs. Unlikely that activity will pick up given the higher interest rate environment.
I keep telling our team that our competition is really the bank&amp;rsquo;s fixed-deposit rates, not our peers. Most retail investors question whether taking the added equity risk is worthwhile when govt bonds and FDs yield 7%+.</description></item><item><title>The SEBI board meeting press conference is a masterclass on Indian markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-sebi-board-meeting-press-conference-is-a-masterclass-on-indian-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-sebi-board-meeting-press-conference-is-a-masterclass-on-indian-markets/</guid><description>The press conference post the SEBI board meets feels like being in a master class on Indian capital markets. It is a must-watch for anyone who takes an interest in the industry.
Here is how I think the outcome of yesterday&amp;rsquo;s meet will affect retail brokerage firms.
The biggest risk for almost all regulated businesses in India is regulatory change. I doubt there has ever been a time when regulations have evolved this quickly.</description></item><item><title>a few thoughts on the increase in Securities Transaction Tax (STT)</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-increase-in-stt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-increase-in-stt/</guid><description>Here are a few thoughts on the STT increase. The 25% increase in F&amp;amp;O STT will further move volumes from futures to options. The actual impact wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be much because over 80% of the volumes come from options &amp;amp; STT is on premium, not on contract value as it is in futures.
It is good that the impact will not be as much on options. But a vibrant capital market needs activity across futures and options.</description></item><item><title>The case for payments banks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-case-for-payments-banks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-case-for-payments-banks/</guid><description>With the SVB crisis, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of talk in the US about the need for a bank that holds money in government bonds without taking risks. Just a simple wallet where people keep their cash, earn a reasonable interest, &amp;amp; make payments. What RBI intended with payments banks.
Payments bank didn&amp;rsquo;t pick up in India because users didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pay monthly fees. Also, payments became highly competitive, with businesses undercutting each other.</description></item><item><title>SEBI cracks down on pump and dump scams on social media</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cracks-down-on-pump-and-dump-scams-on-social-media/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sebi-cracks-down-on-pump-and-dump-scams-on-social-media/</guid><description>SEBI is killing it with these enforcement orders 🔥
Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s against the pump &amp;amp; dump schemes peddled by selling greed &amp;amp; unrealistic returns through social media &amp;amp; YouTube should serve as a powerful deterrent. These scams had become the easiest game in town for manipulators.
These elaborate orders should hopefully put some fear amongst unauthorized tipsters and people offering unauthorized portfolio management services. Such actors damage the sanctity of capital markets in India.</description></item><item><title>The pitfalls of just looking at trading turnover figures to determine market activity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-pitfalls-of-just-looking-at-trading-turnover-figures-to-determine-market-activity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-pitfalls-of-just-looking-at-trading-turnover-figures-to-determine-market-activity/</guid><description>News headlines scream about options volumes overtaking cash volumes. But just looking at volumes &amp;amp; not unique users can be misleading.
Jump in options last 2 yrs is mostly due to intraday stock traders switching to options after intraday leverage restrictions in early 2021
~10% of active traders contribute ~90% of trading volumes, in mostly intraday cash and F&amp;amp;O.
Comparing trading volumes of traders to equity investors is like comparing apples to oranges or brinjals.</description></item><item><title>The impact of extended trading hours on traders and markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-impact-of-extended-trading-hours-on-traders-and-markets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-impact-of-extended-trading-hours-on-traders-and-markets/</guid><description>Extended trading hours for F&amp;amp;O will maybe signal the maturity of our markets. They also level the playing field for domestic traders against international traders and are also good for capital markets businesses in terms of revenues, but I&amp;rsquo;m conflicted.
I&amp;rsquo;m unsure how it will affect the mental health of active retail F&amp;amp;O traders in the long term. Tracking P&amp;amp;L for long hours is stressful &amp;amp; can affect life outside trading.</description></item><item><title>Adverse impact of budget on international investing platforms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/adverse-impact-of-the-budget-on-international-investing-platforms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/adverse-impact-of-the-budget-on-international-investing-platforms/</guid><description>For retail investors, I guess the only material change in the budget is for people who invest in international stocks. Money sent out using LRS now has a Tax Collection at Source (TCS) of 20% with no upper or lower threshold, compared to 5% over Rs 7lks earlier.
TCS can be claimed after filing income tax returns at the end of the year, but it&amp;rsquo;s unlikely that many will be okay with having 20% of capital blocked until then.</description></item><item><title>Making auction markets accessible to retail investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-auction-markets-accessible-to-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-auction-markets-accessible-to-retail-investors/</guid><description>If you actively trade, you would&amp;rsquo;ve faced a short delivery and a large auction penalty at least once. Such penalties are due to illiquid auction markets.
We are now trying to improve liquidity in auctions by allowing our customers to participate.
Short delivery happens when the seller doesn&amp;rsquo;t deliver the shares. This can happen if:
Stocks sold for intraday hit an upper circuit. Buy today, sell tomorrow (BTST) traders don&amp;rsquo;t deliver.</description></item><item><title>India becomes the first major market to move to a T+1 settlement cycle</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-becomes-the-first-major-market-to-move-to-a-t+1-settlement-cycle/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-becomes-the-first-major-market-to-move-to-a-t+1-settlement-cycle/</guid><description>Starting tomorrow, India will become the first major market to completely move to a T+1 settlement cycle (China is partly T+1). It is crazy how far ahead we are in terms of market infrastructure and safety, even when compared to the developed world.
So if you buy a stock, you get it in your demat the next day, and if you sell, you will have the funds by the next day.</description></item><item><title>Digitising onboarding to attract NRI investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/digitising-onboarding-to-attract-nri-investors/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/digitising-onboarding-to-attract-nri-investors/</guid><description>Allowing NRIs to open demat accounts online is the low-hanging fruit to attract money to India. The process today is physical and cumbersome.
With Indian markets doing well, there&amp;rsquo;s a great interest to invest here, but the tough onboard process leads to massive dropoffs.
Since NRIs send and receive funds from bank accounts with KYC, we can make onboarding fully digital and make it as easy as it is for a resident Indian to open a trading account.</description></item><item><title>Most hated all-time high?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/most-hated-all-time-high/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/most-hated-all-time-high/</guid><description>Most hated all-time high? 😬
While markets are at all-time highs, the momentum in retail participation and activity is not nearly as much as it was at all-time highs this time last year. The monthly new demat account openings are down ~40% even though markets are back to highs.</description></item><item><title>30th anniversary of NSE</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/30th-anniversary-of-nse/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/30th-anniversary-of-nse/</guid><description>Happy 30th @NSEIndia 🍾
Feels like yesterday when we first saw NSE NOW in 2009—the free platform NSE offered its brokers. This led to us questioning if tech is free, can we disrupt the pricing? An arbitrage trade. 😬
@zerodhaonline wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have happened if not for NSE &amp;amp; NOW.</description></item><item><title>The Indian capital market regulations and infrastructure are among the best in the world</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-indian-capital-market-regulations-and-infrastructure-are-among-the-best-in-the-world/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-indian-capital-market-regulations-and-infrastructure-are-among-the-best-in-the-world/</guid><description>Our capital market infrastructure &amp;amp; regulations don&amp;rsquo;t get enough credit for being among the best in the world.
It is crazy &amp;amp; scary what is happening today in the Crypto world. Crypto Brokers &amp;amp; exchanges can act as banks in most markets, exposing customers to unlimited risk.
In India, all securities are held by the customer at the depository. All unused funds are sent back monthly/qtrly and one client&amp;rsquo;s funds can&amp;rsquo;t be used to fund another.</description></item><item><title>Can the Indian broking industry continue growing at the same pace?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/can-the-indian-broking-industry-continue-growing-at-the-same-pace/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/can-the-indian-broking-industry-continue-growing-at-the-same-pace/</guid><description>Whenever I get asked if @zerodhaonline or the Indian broking industry will continue to grow at the same pace, I refer to Robinhood, which is a good proxy.
US markets are down ~30% and monthly active users are down ~50%. The activity is back to pre-pandemic levels.</description></item><item><title>Social stock exchange can making investing for the future mainstream</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/social-stock-exchange-can-make-investing-for-the-future-mainstream/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/social-stock-exchange-can-make-investing-for-the-future-mainstream/</guid><description>The second-biggest problem for the planet outside climate change is the concentration of wealth unless it helps society. Now that SEBI has put a framework on the Social stock exchange (SSE), we are excited to see how we can nudge the top 5% of India to think of the bottom 80%.
For anybody who wants to invest in the future, the biggest challenge is the trust deficit. Non-profits that list on the SSE have to adhere to regulations &amp;amp; make disclosures like listed companies.</description></item><item><title>RBI alert list of CFD and Binary trading platforms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-alert-list-of-cfd-and-binary-trading-platforms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rbi-alert-list-of-cfd-and-binary-trading-platforms/</guid><description>Despite all warnings, a lot of Indians trade on CFD and Binary trading platforms. RBI just published a list of such unauthorized trading platforms, warning Indians that trading on these platforms can be prosecuted under the FEMA act.
Hopefully, the payment gateways and businesses that take advertising money will also stop dealing with them. Read this post to know more about how these illegal CFDs and binary options platforms work.</description></item><item><title>Few thoughts on Indian markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-markets-will-perform-well-on-a-relative-basis-compared-to-the-us-markets/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-markets-will-perform-well-on-a-relative-basis-compared-to-the-us-markets/</guid><description>People keep asking about my views on the markets. I&amp;rsquo;ve been at it for ~25 years &amp;amp; I don&amp;rsquo;t have a clue. I usually say whatever the current trend will continue, as that is most probable.😃 But over the last year, I&amp;rsquo;ve been consistent that India will most likely outperform.
By outperforming, I don&amp;rsquo;t mean our markets will go up, but we will probably not fall as much as others. And if we don&amp;rsquo;t fall as much, we will probably outperform on the upside.</description></item><item><title>Demat accounts in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/decline-in-growth-of-demat-accounts/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/decline-in-growth-of-demat-accounts/</guid><description>Check the chart here.</description></item><item><title>Comparing the volatility of Indian and US markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/comparing-the-volatility-of-indian-and-us-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/comparing-the-volatility-of-indian-and-us-markets/</guid><description>There was a time when if US markets caught a cold, we&amp;rsquo;d catch a fever. But since 2010, volatility wise, we&amp;rsquo;ve been much better compared to the US. While the credit is usually given to more local participation, it has got more to do with SEBI regulations that reduced leverage.
Btw the above chart isn&amp;rsquo;t even a fair comparison, Nifty is an index of the 50 largest Indian companies &amp;amp; S&amp;amp;P 500 consists of the 500 largest US companies in the US.</description></item><item><title>MAU in Indian capital markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mau-in-indian-capital-markets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/mau-in-indian-capital-markets/</guid><description>Monthly active users (MAU) on Indian capital markets from the 2022 RBI financial stability report.
This is first time I am seeing this data in public. MAUs &amp;lt;1 crore across India, much lesser than what most people expect. My guess is the dip will be a lot more by the end of June.</description></item><item><title>Less leverage has helped Indian markets outperform global markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/less-leverage-has-helped-indian-markets-outperform-global-markets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/less-leverage-has-helped-indian-markets-outperform-global-markets/</guid><description>The silver lining for India in the current global meltdown is that we may continue to do better than other markets on a relative basis because of the low levels of leverage in our capital markets. Leverage in times like these usually accentuates the fall.
Leverage is like WMD (Weapon of mass destruction), resulting in excesses both on the way up and down. When markets fall, long leveraged positions are required to bring additional margins, failing which positions are forced to exit resulting in the markets falling even more.</description></item><item><title>Government taxes on Crypto could have been blessing in disguise</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/government-taxes-on-crypto-could-have-been-blessing-in-disguise-for-indian-crypto-investors/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/government-taxes-on-crypto-could-have-been-blessing-in-disguise-for-indian-crypto-investors/</guid><description>I think many Indian crypto investors accidentally got lucky due to TDS &amp;amp; Tax on Crypto announcement this budget in Feb. Activity &amp;amp; participation dropped significantly immediately. If not, many could have potentially been trapped trying to buy the dip &amp;amp; then averaging down.
Even when trading stocks, the biggest reason for losses is trying to make a wrong trade right by throwing good money at bad money. That is averaging down when the price moves against the trade, without considering if the portfolio is getting concentrated or not.</description></item><item><title>Indian markets are much better than the US markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-markets-are-much-better-than-the-us-markets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-markets-are-much-better-than-the-us-markets/</guid><description>In India, users see the price and liquidity on both exchanges, pick the best, and then place an order. A brokerage firm just enables this transaction. In the US, almost all platforms are exchange agnostic. The broker just shows a bid, ask, and last traded price.
The order placed is mostly sent to a market maker—typically hedge funds, that will either be the counterparty to the trade or send them to the US exchanges.</description></item><item><title>Stock market scams to move money illegally</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-market-scams-to-move-money-illegally/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/stock-market-scams-to-move-money-illegally/</guid><description>A trader was lured into sharing login credentials on a telegram group by promising high returns. Scammer created a loss &amp;amp; moved it to another account &amp;amp; disappeared. Don&amp;rsquo;t share login credentials, like a bank, there are illegal ways to move money out of a trading account.
Two ways in which money can be moved once access is compromised: Buying penny stocks which are part of a pump &amp;amp; dump scheme at high prices.</description></item><item><title>Voting on shareholder proposals at Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/voting-on-shareholder-proposals-at-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/voting-on-shareholder-proposals-at-zerodha/</guid><description>As a shareholder of a company, you are entitled to vote on important company decisions like board appointments, corporate actions, mergers &amp;amp; acquisitions, executive compensation, etc. But very few retail investors vote on shareholder proposals. One reason for this is, of course, retail investors are a small part of the Indian markets. The retail shareholding in NSE-listed companies is about ~7%.
There&amp;rsquo;s also a lack of awareness among investors that they are entitled to vote on company resolutions.</description></item><item><title>Is fractional share investing possible in India?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-fractional-investing-possible-in-india/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-fractional-investing-possible-in-india/</guid><description>Fractional investing or the ability to invest say $10 in Amazon at $3200 has been the biggest reason for stock market participation to go up in the US. We applied under SEBI regulatory sandbox to launch the same in India. Our learnings by Somnath Mukherjee. We made that application with a startup that had reached out to us Rainmatterin and was rejected.
In the US, stocks bought by customers are held in the street name of the broker, unlike in India, where stocks are held in a customer’s beneficiary account with a depository.</description></item><item><title>Why our financial year start in April</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-our-financial-year-start-in-april/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-our-financial-year-start-in-april/</guid><description>Hmm&amp;hellip;so this is why our financial year starts in April and not Jan, from my 6-year-old son&amp;rsquo;s history factbook. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how I didn&amp;rsquo;t know until now.</description></item><item><title>Can brokerage go to 0 in India?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/can-brokerage-go-to-0-in-india/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/can-brokerage-go-to-0-in-india/</guid><description>Many people ask me if brokerage rates can go to zero like in the US, and why not flat monthly brokerage plans with unlimited trades. I don&amp;rsquo;t think so. I think, if anything, brokerage rates will go up in the future. Here&amp;rsquo;s why.
Firstly, in the US, brokers can earn in ways that SEBI rightly doesn&amp;rsquo;t allow here: Payment for order flow: selling customer orders to HFT firms. Securities lending: Unlike India, stocks are held in the street name or in the name of brokers—they can lend them to earn.</description></item><item><title>Impact of 1% TDS on all Crypto trades</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-1-percent-tds-on-all-crypto-trades/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-1-percent-tds-on-all-crypto-trades/</guid><description>They say the devil is in the details. I missed the 1% TDS on all Crypto trades, similar to the TCS of 0.1% on Gold. I assumed that the TDS is only on the gains. With this 1% TDS, I think Crypto volumes in India will drop off the cliff come July 1st 2022 when it is implemented.
A 1% TDS means 1% of every trade value is blocked by the platform.</description></item><item><title>Unauthorised CFD and forex trading platforms</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/unauthorised-cfd-and-forex-trading-platforms/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/unauthorised-cfd-and-forex-trading-platforms/</guid><description>We had cautioned people about illegal CFD &amp;amp; Forex &amp;amp; Binary trading platforms a while back, but I still keep seeing those ads, which means people still losing money. Today&amp;rsquo;s RBI press release will hopefully put an end to these illegal platforms. The RBI circular also reiterates that trading derivatives on international exchanges with funds sent through LRS is not permitted.</description></item><item><title>My reading of crypto post the budget</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-reading-of-crypto-post-budget/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-reading-of-crypto-post-budget/</guid><description>The good news for crypto is that it was finally acknowledged in the budget. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean it&amp;rsquo;s legal—it will only be after the crypto bill. Until then, regulated entities in India can&amp;rsquo;t offer trading in crypto. Here&amp;rsquo;s my reading of crypto post the budget.
The 30% tax without the option to set-off of losses against other tokens or deductions can lead to a drop in turnover. Market markers &amp;amp; active traders are usually 80%+ of turnover in most trading businesses.</description></item><item><title>Impact of STT on traders, exchanges and brokerages</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-stt-on-traders-exchanges-brokers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/impact-of-stt-on-traders-exchanges-brokers/</guid><description>Every budget day for the last 15+ years, I&amp;rsquo;ve woken up hoping that STT is reduced. Zerodha customers alone pay ~₹2500 cores in STT, stamp duty, &amp;amp; GST annually. Overall, traders lose more money in transaction costs &amp;amp; impact costs than to the markets.
Lower txn costs improve liquidity, hence decrease impact costs. But on flip side, you could argue that people may speculate more, which isn&amp;rsquo;t good—one reason for Nudges on Kite.</description></item><item><title>History of F&amp;O margin requirements in India</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/history-of-fo-margin-requirements-in-india/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/history-of-fo-margin-requirements-in-india/</guid><description>NSE introduced F&amp;amp;O in 2000 &amp;amp; today NSE is the largest derivatives exchange in the world by volume. Trading activity was mostly in futures until 2008. Options only became popular once contract sizes &amp;amp; margins went up. A brief history of F&amp;amp;O margins.
A key impetus for us starting Zerodha in 2010 was that there were discussions in the markets on SEBI introducing margin reporting and short margin penalty for not collecting sufficient margins for overnight F&amp;amp;O positions after the market collapse in 2008.</description></item><item><title>Advisory is one the biggest Indian fintech opportunity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-biggest-fintech-opportunity/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-biggest-fintech-opportunity/</guid><description>One of the biggest Indian fintech opportunities is advisory to help Indians manage their personal finances better—investments, insurance etc. For this to happen, Account aggregator will have to do what UPI did for payments. Hoping all banks, depositories, &amp;amp; RTAs will be on AA.</description></item><item><title>India is addicted to gold</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indians-and-gold/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indians-and-gold/</guid><description>Over $400billion went out of India to import gold vs $600 billion+ that came in through FPI, FDI &amp;amp; VC. Imagine, instead of gold, some of that money was invested in Indian startups &amp;amp; listed companies. There could&amp;rsquo;ve been immense and inclusive local wealth creation.
I think the goal of every Indian fintech firm focusing on savings and investing should be to nudge people to back Indian entrepreneurs and think long term.</description></item><item><title>Irresponsible influencers</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/influencers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/influencers/</guid><description>Watching famous personalities with huge fan followings trying to trigger their fans or retail investors to invest in super risky asset classes without talking about the risks, or caring about the risk profile of those who follow them is quite disgusting.
Thanks to Crypto, it&amp;rsquo;s been a case of &amp;ldquo;never meet your heroes,” with so many people I admired for peddling crypto, NFTs, etc. as safe &amp;amp; guaranteed. Nothing against Crypto, it would have been the same if stocks or even AAA-rated debt was peddled as being safe &amp;amp; guaranteed.</description></item><item><title>Why only 1% of traders make money</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-only-one-percent-traders-make-money/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-only-one-percent-traders-make-money/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m surprised that, so many are surprised that just 1% of active traders make more than bank fixed deposits over 3 years timeframe. Active trading is like running a business, only a small % succeed. The only easy bit about trading is starting trading.
Traders with an alternate source of income tend to do better or have higher odds of winning than those who rely only on trading for a living.</description></item><item><title>Physical delivery of stock F&amp;O &amp; their risks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/physical-delivery-risks-for-stock-futures-and-options/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/physical-delivery-risks-for-stock-futures-and-options/</guid><description>With mandatory physical delivery for stock options and the removal of the Do Not Exercise (DNE) facility for options (Especially buy options), the risk of huge losses has gone up significantly if OTM options become ITM &amp;amp; there&amp;rsquo;s no liquidity to exit.</description></item><item><title>Fixing the tax audit requirement anomaly for trades</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fixing-the-tax-audit-requirement-anomaly-for-traders/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/fixing-the-tax-audit-requirement-anomaly-for-traders/</guid><description>You need to get a CA to validate IT returns (ITR) or get a tax audit if profit when trading is&amp;lt; than 6% of turnover or if the turnover is&amp;gt; Rs 10 crores. This is an anomaly that needs to be fixed as the markets grow. Here is why it should be fixed. It may be easy too.
If you trade stocks intraday, F&amp;amp;O, or trade equity delivery very actively, you need to declare any P&amp;amp;L as business income using ITR3.</description></item><item><title>What moves the markets?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-moves-the-markets/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-moves-the-markets/</guid><description>We keep hearing stuff like Nifty looks like it wants to go lower or it&amp;rsquo;ll bounce back. We make market moves sound almost human. What really moves markets? It’s traders &amp;amp; investors making informed &amp;amp; uninformed decisions. Everything else is hocus pocus.</description></item><item><title>Permissions asked by finance apps</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/permissions-asked-by-finance-apps/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/permissions-asked-by-finance-apps/</guid><description>Report by Kotak on various finance apps &amp;amp; permissions they ask for. Btw Kite, Coin, &amp;amp; Zerodha Varsity don&amp;rsquo;t ask for any permissions to run. The apps ask for access to photos in case a user wants to set a profile picture. Hopefully, we never have to get into lending.</description></item><item><title>Buy Now, Pay Later for stocks</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/buy-now-pay-later-for-stocks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/buy-now-pay-later-for-stocks/</guid><description>Unlike the previous bull runs, there isn&amp;rsquo;t a lot of leverage in the system this time. Stocks are mostly bought with full money upfront. So when there are drawdowns in the market on days like today, retail investors are forced to liquidate, which also increases volatility.
Credit goes to SEBI &amp;amp; also all of us new-age online brokers who haven&amp;rsquo;t pushed customers to borrow and buy while placing orders. If platforms enabled greed by nudging users to borrow to buy more quantities, customers would ignore the risks of margin funding (MTF).</description></item><item><title>Crypto and forex ads need to be regulated</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/crypto-and-forex-ads/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/crypto-and-forex-ads/</guid><description>If financial services businesses are allowed to mis-sell greed &amp;amp; easy + guaranteed returns from risky financial products, it not only harms consumers but it creates a systemic risk. The Govt should put in checks not just for crypto ads, but also unregulated CFD/Forex platforms.</description></item><item><title>Nature Shows How This All Works</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-things-work/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-things-work/</guid><description>Nature shows how this all works (markets too) Extreme events in one direction increase the odds of extreme events in the other Small changes compounded for long periods of time are indistinguishable from magic A beautiful read by Morgan Housel</description></item><item><title>Nudging users to help them avoid mistakes</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-users-to-help-them-avoid-mistakes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudging-users-to-help-them-avoid-mistakes/</guid><description>Most people don&amp;rsquo;t spend time learning trading or forget what they&amp;rsquo;ve learnt when placing an order. The order placement step is also when users pay maximum attention. With &amp;ldquo;Nudge&amp;rdquo; we are now able to leverage that fraction of a second to educate users &amp;amp; help them avoid mistakes.
This Nudge on DHFL warning customers that the investment may go to 0 discouraged over 50% of our users from taking a trade.</description></item><item><title>The biggest wealth destroyer when investing</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/biggest-wealth-destroyer-when-investing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/biggest-wealth-destroyer-when-investing/</guid><description>What is the biggest wealth destroyer when investing?
Averaging down or buying more of an asset, be it stock or crypto, as the price keeps going down and hoping that the price bounces to recover losses or make profits faster. Common behaviour among retail investors.
While it is tempting to average down, the odds of this strategy working are significantly low in the long run. All it takes is one large move on the other side for things to go wrong.</description></item><item><title>The risk of offering high leverages</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-of-offering-high-leverages/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-of-offering-high-leverages/</guid><description>When a platform offers leverage or funds the customer to buy for more than the money in the account, the platform takes a credit risk. With Crypto exchanges offering 10 to 100x leverage (futures), on days like today, I wonder who monitors liquidity position of these platforms.
In regulated space, even with all checks &amp;amp; balances, brokerage firms once in a while on days of extreme volatility go bust. If exchange offers 50x leverage &amp;amp; say Bitcoin goes down 4% in one tick, a customer with $1K, can lose $2K.</description></item><item><title>On the Panic With Friends podcast with Howard Lindzon</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/panic-with-friends-podcast/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/panic-with-friends-podcast/</guid><description>This was a really fun conversation with Howard.</description></item><item><title>The pandemic has shown us it's the right time to move away from cities</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/moving-away-from-large-cities/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/moving-away-from-large-cities/</guid><description>While we all work together to figure out what we can do to help in the current situation, I think the only long-term fix is for as many of us to move away from large cities. This is the answer to many of India’s problems. And now is probably the right time to work towards it.
Large cities are choking &amp;amp; will continue to break down every time we&amp;rsquo;re tested, COVID today, could be water shortages, pollution, floods, etc.</description></item><item><title>Mis-selling is a systemic issue.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/misselling-is-a-systemic-issues/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/misselling-is-a-systemic-issues/</guid><description>This is a more systemic issue, not with one bank but across the board, banks to ed-tech to fintech. As long as you give revenue targets &amp;amp; push employees to get there, products that generate more revenue for the business over what is right for the customer will be mis-sold.
Easier for employees of banks, brokerages, wealth management firms to mis-sell as relationships are already established &amp;amp; there is trust with the brand, which is why the customer has allowed them to be custodians of their assets.</description></item><item><title>A nudge to stop people from losing money in Rights Entitlements</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudge-to-stop-people-from-losing-money-in-rights-entitlements/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nudge-to-stop-people-from-losing-money-in-rights-entitlements/</guid><description>Many retail investors buy Rights Entitlements (REs) without knowing that the value of REs will be zero if they don&amp;rsquo;t apply. Since May 2020 our clients have lost ~Rs 10cr by buying Rights entitlements &amp;amp; not applying. We now have a nudge to warn customers. Read about it here.</description></item><item><title>My view on reduction of intraday leverages</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-view-on-reduction-of-intraday-leverages/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/my-view-on-reduction-of-intraday-leverages/</guid><description>My view on the reduction of intraday leverages is that there will be near-term pain (for Zerodha too). We&amp;rsquo;ll see a drop in trading volumes and an increase in impact cost. But in the long term, more traders will survive &amp;amp; hopefully make up for the dip.
There is an argument to be made for lesser intraday margins. VAR+ELM or SPAN+Exposure margin calculation is based on risk/volatility. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t differentiate between intraday &amp;amp; overnight risk, or that intraday is less risky and hence ideally requires lesser margins.</description></item><item><title>Trading with other people’s money</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trading-with-other-peoples-money/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/trading-with-other-peoples-money/</guid><description>Managing other people&amp;rsquo;s money in ways that aren&amp;rsquo;t allowed leads to the most complaints with the regulators. There are ways to do it legally, and those that can incur significant penalties. Here&amp;rsquo;s all that you need to know about managing money. https://zerodha.com/z-connect/traders-zone/trading-with-other-peoples-money</description></item><item><title>Enabling women to start making financial decisions</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/enabling-women-to-start-making-financial-decisions/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/enabling-women-to-start-making-financial-decisions/</guid><description>This video from Paytm captures what we need to do most as a country - educate &amp;amp; enable as many women as possible to start making financial decisions. In my personal experience, women manage risk better than men, so they&amp;rsquo;ll probably take better financial decisions #womensday2021</description></item><item><title>Yearly demat account growth for the last 20 years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/yearly-demat-account-growth-for-20-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/yearly-demat-account-growth-for-20-years/</guid><description>Consider the yearly demat addition for the last 20yrs. Stockbroking is as high beta as it can get. When someone asks for my view on the future, I usually ask them for their view on Nifty. The last boom &amp;amp; bust was in 2007-08, took 10 yrs to get back to those numbers. A high beta business is one that has a higher sensitivity to the market (Nifty). If Nifty does well, business outperforms the market by a fair bit, and if Nifty doesn&amp;rsquo;t, it underperforms the market by a fair bit.</description></item><item><title>How big was Jan 2021 for the broking industry?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-big-was-jan-2021-for-broking/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/how-big-was-jan-2021-for-broking/</guid><description>How big was Jan 2021 for the broking industry? The best year for the markets since 2010 was by far 2014. Nifty was up more than 30% and the industry added 13 lakh new Demat accounts in 1 year. And, Jan 2021, just in 1 month 17 lakh new Demat accounts were added. Water buffaloGrimacing face</description></item><item><title>Podcast - Nikhil Kamath on The Ranveer Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nik-on-the-ranveer-show/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nik-on-the-ranveer-show/</guid><description>Keeping your emotions in check is the most important skill as a trader. The Bro @nikhilkamathcio is a master at this. He&amp;rsquo;s never missed a trading day in last 15 yrs &amp;amp; I&amp;rsquo;ve never seen him react to P&amp;amp;L. Nik on his journey with the very sharp @BeerBicepsGuy</description></item><item><title>The Gamestop saga and lessons for retail investors</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/gamestop-saga-and-lessons-for-retail-investors/</guid><description>In the Gamestop saga, the media has loved telling the story of how Retail made a lot of money from Hedge funds. The reality is entirely different, almost everyone apart from retail has probably made money or benefited from this.
Firstly, yes, a couple of Hedge funds were sitting on large losses on Gamestop shorts. Now that stock is at $50, the losses also would be a fraction, if the shorts still held.</description></item><item><title>Rising financial awareness among Indians</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sing-financial-awareness-among-indians/</guid><description>Financial awareness about the importance of saving and investing in India is increasing at the fastest rate ever, especially among millennials. Of course, stock markets doing well and lower bank FD rates are helping. But there are also a few structural changes afoot here. Historically financial products have been sold hard &amp;amp; mostly in person. Products mostly sold based on promises of high returns (sales pitches in person leave no audit trail).</description></item><item><title>Shorting and Indian Capital Markets</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/shorting-and-indian-capital-markets/</guid><description>Can retail traders are cause a “short squeeze” in India like they did in stocks like GameStop and AMC entertainment in the US? It cannot, and I explain why in this post. Join the discussion here.</description></item><item><title>Beyond misleading trading turnover numbers — the actual size of Indian capital markets?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beyond-misleading-trading-turnover-numbers-the-actual-size-of-indian-capital-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/beyond-misleading-trading-turnover-numbers-the-actual-size-of-indian-capital-markets/</guid><description>Looking at trading turnover to estimate capital market size is misleading. Most trades are leveraged &amp;amp; ideally we should look at the margins being traded, not the trade value. Turnover this way will be less than 10% of the trading turnover declared.
The best way to estimate the size of the Indian capital markets is by checking the revenue pool. This I think, is less than Rs 50k crores across 1500+ brokers, exchanges, &amp;amp; depositories.</description></item><item><title>The fallacy of predictions</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-fallacy-of-predictions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-fallacy-of-predictions/</guid><description>Even after all my years of experience, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have been more wrong in predicting the direction of our business in 2020. These expert predictions should be taken with a pinch of salt, most of times the odds are equal to tossing a coin.</description></item><item><title>The twisted world of illegal CFDs &amp; binary options</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-twisted-world-of-illegal-cfds-binary-options/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Total addressable market for brokers</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/total-addressable-market-for-brokers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/total-addressable-market-for-brokers/</guid><description>Since broking is hot post-COVID, inspite of all the spike in trading volumes and activity, the total addressable market is just ~1.5 million users. I had shared this pre-Covid. Broking is super hot now, but this TAM (Total addressable market) hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed, if anything it has reduced. Btw, the revenue-generating active day traders + F&amp;amp;O crowd is not more than ~1.5mil in spite of the spike in trading activity/volumes. This active crowd is unlikely to go up because most day and F&amp;amp;O traders stop within 6 months.</description></item><item><title>Robinhood pays $65M to settle SEC charges on payment for order flow disclosures</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-pays-65m-to-settle-sec-charges-on-for/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/robinhood-pays-65m-to-settle-sec-charges-on-for/</guid><description>The Robinhood SEC settlement over order flow disclosures grabbed some headlines even in India. Since people might be wondering if this happens here, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t. Unlike the US, all order in India are matched and executed on the exchanges. We have no concept of order flow here.</description></item><item><title>Podcast: Sandeep Parekh on the evolution of the Indian market and securities regulations</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-sandeep-parekh-on-the-evolution-of-the-and/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/podcast-sandeep-parekh-on-the-evolution-of-the-and/</guid><description>https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EihRbTTLLy0&amp;amp;feature=youtu.be This is a must-watch for those interested in the Indian securities market. @SandeepParekh we need to find a way to get you to do more of this. :)</description></item><item><title>A product to get more Indians to save and invest</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-product-to-get-more-indians-to-save-and-invest/</guid><description>To get the next 10 crore Indians, the traditional financial product might not work. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I think is needed to get these people to start saving and investing.</description></item><item><title>Evolution of the Indian stock broking industry since the Harshad Mehta scam - Scam92 TV Show</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/evolution-of-the-indian-stock-broking-industry-the/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/evolution-of-the-indian-stock-broking-industry-the/</guid><description>#Scam1992TheHarshadMehtaStory - a thread on everything that has changed since then in the world of Indian stockbroking.
Today the settlement cycle is 2 days &amp;amp; SEBI is hinting at a 1-day cycle soon (first few countries in the world). Back then, it was 14 days (the time within which you have to pay full money and take delivery of stocks or deliver stocks if sold).
Today, a customer can’t buy stocks without the minimum money in the account or sell without stocks in Demat.</description></item><item><title>Direct Market Access (DMA) for retail investors?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/direct-market-access-dma-for-retail-investors/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/direct-market-access-dma-for-retail-investors/</guid><description/></item><item><title>What does it take to win at trading?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</guid><description>Learnings from interactions with thousands of traders and my own successes and failures.</description></item><item><title>Introducing ‘Innerworth – Mind over markets’</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</guid><description/></item><item><title>The race to Zero – Can the Indian brokerage industry survive?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-race-to-zero-can-the-indian-brokerage-industry/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-race-to-zero-can-the-indian-brokerage-industry/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>