<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>psychology on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/psychology/</link><description>Recent content in psychology on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Words from the wise, Tom Basso</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/words-from-the-wise-tom-basso/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/words-from-the-wise-tom-basso/</guid><description>In the 20+ years in this business, I haven’t seen anyone who has kept profits from trading without good risk management. I know many who&amp;rsquo;ve lost quickly. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a plan to manage risk and size your bets, it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to keep the money you make.
Here are a few wonderful tips from a couple of Tom Basso&amp;rsquo;s recent podcasts:
On the secret to his longevity:
&amp;ldquo;I would say it’s sort of two things.</description></item><item><title>The downsides of social media</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-downsides-of-social-media/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-downsides-of-social-media/</guid><description>This desire to build large social media followings can be a slippery slope.
People are generally curious about successful &amp;amp; famous people, so it&amp;rsquo;s easier for celebs from movies, sports, etc., maybe even some businessmen 😀, to build a social media presence quickly.
For everyone else, there is always an incentive to be loud, controversial or oversell because that&amp;rsquo;s what gets the attention. The exception to this is people who write and share high-quality things, but this is very hard.</description></item><item><title>Not letting social media consume you</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/not-letting-social-media-consume-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/not-letting-social-media-consume-you/</guid><description>Not getting consumed by social media while trying to build an audience has been one of the toughest things I have done in my life. The dopamine hit from likes &amp;amp; shares is extremely addictive. Social media platforms have done an amazing job of engineering us to feel this way.
I keep reminding myself that if the quality of content goes down, so will that of the audience. To keep in check the need to say something even when there isn&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>Does Illiquidty like in private markets lead to good investor behavior?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-illiquidty-like-in-private-markets-lead-to/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-illiquidty-like-in-private-markets-lead-to/</guid><description>A question I have been asking institutional investors in both private and public markets is - if they could enter and exit their holdings at will like retail investors(which they cannot today), would they have actually sat through the ride of their best-performing holdings? The answer usually is no. As counterintuitive as it sounds, maybe the inability to easily enter/exit large public or illiquid private holdings forces fund managers to sit tight, which is also why they can outperform retail investors who are always trying to time the market.</description></item><item><title>What does it take to win at trading?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</guid><description>Learnings from interactions with thousands of traders and my own successes and failures.</description></item><item><title>Introducing ‘Innerworth – Mind over markets’</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>