<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>psychology on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/psychology/</link><description>Recent content in psychology on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Risk management lessons from Tom Basso</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-lessons-from-tom-basso/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-lessons-from-tom-basso/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been noticing many recent IPOs continue running up for 2-3 days after listing. While demand and supply factors (limited free float) are obvious reasons, there may also be technical factors at play.
One common reason why traders blow up is because of poor position sizing. In other words, how much do you bet on a trade.
You can be right on direction 60% of the time and still lose everything if you size your positions poorly.</description></item><item><title>Why encouraging less trading leads to better outcomes for everyone</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-encouraging-less-trading-leads-to-better-outcomes-for-everyone/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/why-encouraging-less-trading-leads-to-better-outcomes-for-everyone/</guid><description>As a % of client funds, our brokerage revenue is 20-25% of our listed peers. That means our clients trade a lot less (75% lesser) as a proportion of their capital.
Here&amp;rsquo;s something counterintuitive but true: With few exceptions, the more frequently people trade, the lower their odds of being profitable. More activity doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean better returns; it usually means a higher chance of blowing out your account.
So it&amp;rsquo;s actually in a platform&amp;rsquo;s best interest to get customers to trade less, not more.</description></item><item><title>Take break from trading using Kill Switch</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-break-from-trading-using-kill-switch/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-break-from-trading-using-kill-switch/</guid><description>The other common trading mistake I have seen over and over again in all my years of being a trader and running a brokerage is over-trading and revenge trading.
Sometimes, the best trade is the one you don&amp;rsquo;t take.
This is why we launched Kill Switch. If you get the urge to keep trading, you can enable it, and you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to place trades for the rest of the day.</description></item><item><title>Risk management is the real secret behind trading success</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-is-the-real-secret-behind-trading-success/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/risk-management-is-the-real-secret-behind-trading-success/</guid><description>Interesting experiment by Elm Wealth: 118 finance students were given tomorrow’s WSJ front page 24 hours before the news broke. You’d expect easy profits. Instead, half lost money and 16% went completely bust.
It wasn’t because their predictions were wrong. They called market direction correctly 51.5% of the time. That’s better than chance.
The problem? Position sizing.
Many students bet huge portions of their portfolio on a single trade. Some used 20x, even 60x leverage.</description></item><item><title>Dark patterns in finance apps</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dark-patterns-in-finance-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/dark-patterns-in-finance-apps/</guid><description>One of the biggest challenges in building a financial services business is that the incentives are often skewed toward doing what’s good for the business and not for the customer. It’s very hard to consistently put customers first.
This is one of the main reasons why finance apps are full of dark patterns, more than almost any other category. Dark patterns are design tricks used in apps and websites to make you do things that are not in your best interest.</description></item><item><title>Take a break from trading</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-a-break-from-trading/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/take-a-break-from-trading/</guid><description>Good time to follow this advice. Over the next 10 days, there are only 4 trading days. It’s not a bad idea to take a break from trading and recharge. Judging by what’s happening, you’re going to need it. 😬
&amp;ldquo;Trading profitably requires that you monitor the market moods and your psychological moods. When either one is not conducive to trading, it’s best to stand aside and wait for the situation to change.</description></item><item><title>Words from the wise, Jerry Parker</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/words-from-the-wise-jerry-parker/</link><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/words-from-the-wise-jerry-parker/</guid><description>In all my time as a trader and a broker, I&amp;rsquo;ve interacted with hundreds of successful traders, both large and small. The one common element to their success and longevity is risk management. This has become all the more important in markets like these when fear takes over and having an objective mindset becomes harder.
I wanted to share a few insightful tips from an old Jerry Parker podcast:
On living to play another day.</description></item><item><title>Words from the wise, Tom Basso</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/words-from-the-wise-tom-basso/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/words-from-the-wise-tom-basso/</guid><description>In the 20+ years in this business, I haven’t seen anyone who has kept profits from trading without good risk management. I know many who&amp;rsquo;ve lost quickly. If you don&amp;rsquo;t have a plan to manage risk and size your bets, it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to keep the money you make.
Here are a few wonderful tips from a couple of Tom Basso&amp;rsquo;s recent podcasts:
On the secret to his longevity:
&amp;ldquo;I would say it’s sort of two things.</description></item><item><title>The downsides of social media</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-downsides-of-social-media/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-downsides-of-social-media/</guid><description>This desire to build large social media followings can be a slippery slope.
People are generally curious about successful &amp;amp; famous people, so it&amp;rsquo;s easier for celebs from movies, sports, etc., maybe even some businessmen 😀, to build a social media presence quickly.
For everyone else, there is always an incentive to be loud, controversial or oversell because that&amp;rsquo;s what gets the attention. The exception to this is people who write and share high-quality things, but this is very hard.</description></item><item><title>Not letting social media consume you</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/not-letting-social-media-consume-you/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/not-letting-social-media-consume-you/</guid><description>Not getting consumed by social media while trying to build an audience has been one of the toughest things I have done in my life. The dopamine hit from likes &amp;amp; shares is extremely addictive. Social media platforms have done an amazing job of engineering us to feel this way.
I keep reminding myself that if the quality of content goes down, so will that of the audience. To keep in check the need to say something even when there isn&amp;rsquo;t.</description></item><item><title>Does Illiquidty like in private markets lead to good investor behavior?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-illiquidty-like-in-private-markets-lead-to/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/does-illiquidty-like-in-private-markets-lead-to/</guid><description>A question I have been asking institutional investors in both private and public markets is - if they could enter and exit their holdings at will like retail investors(which they cannot today), would they have actually sat through the ride of their best-performing holdings? The answer usually is no. As counterintuitive as it sounds, maybe the inability to easily enter/exit large public or illiquid private holdings forces fund managers to sit tight, which is also why they can outperform retail investors who are always trying to time the market.</description></item><item><title>What does it take to win at trading?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/what-does-it-take-to-win-at-trading/</guid><description>Learnings from interactions with thousands of traders and my own successes and failures.</description></item><item><title>Introducing ‘Innerworth – Mind over markets’</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-innerworth-mind-over-markets/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>