<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rainmatter on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter/</link><description>Recent content in rainmatter on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Indian VC ecosystem has changed quite a bit in 15 years</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-vc-ecosystem-has-changed-quite-a-bit-in-15-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/indian-vc-ecosystem-has-changed-quite-a-bit-in-15-years/</guid><description>The Indian VC ecosystem has changed quite a bit in 15 years. When we started Zerodha in 2010, &amp;ldquo;VC&amp;rdquo; was an exotic term, and there was barely any startup activity. The most popular VCs were dads, uncles and aunts.
Starting around 2010, we began seeing interest driven by India&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;opportunity size.&amp;rdquo; India&amp;rsquo;s population has done more to attract VC money than anything else 😛 &amp;ldquo;India has 120 crore people, and even if 1% buy X&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Ditto rebuilding trust in insurance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ditto-rebuilding-trust-in-insurance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/ditto-rebuilding-trust-in-insurance/</guid><description>Historically, people haven&amp;rsquo;t bought life and health insurance because of all the scams and spam. The trust deficit in insurance is way too high. People simply don&amp;rsquo;t trust people who sell insurance.
I&amp;rsquo;m really happy that Ditto is doing whatever it can to fix this.</description></item><item><title>Rebuilding soil health with Akshayakalpa</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rebuilding-soil-health-with-akshayakalpa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rebuilding-soil-health-with-akshayakalpa/</guid><description>Soil Organic Content (SOC) is critical in farming. It determines how well soil holds water, delivers nutrients to plants, maintains structure, and supports the millions of microbes that make soil alive. When SOC drops below 0.5%, you&amp;rsquo;re looking at desert-like conditions where nothing grows without the farmer pumping in fertilisers. India&amp;rsquo;s farmland averages a shocking 0.3% SOC. Compare that to European Union cropland at 1.8%—that&amp;rsquo;s the gold standard.
A few weeks ago, Shashi Kumar, the founder of Akshayakalpa, shared something incredible from AK Farms.</description></item><item><title>Insights from our interaction with Social Alpha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/insights-from-our-interaction-with-social-alpha/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/insights-from-our-interaction-with-social-alpha/</guid><description>We at Rainmatter finally met the Social Alpha team, and I am still thinking about everything Manoj Malgharia shared.
Set up as a non-profit, they’re solving some of the toughest social, economic, and environmental challenges by bridging the gap between science and society.
What stood out is not just the funding or grants they make, but more importantly, the way they support ideas — from testing in their labs to taking them to market, derisking for scale, and much more.</description></item><item><title>Creating safe spaces in sexual health discussions through Rainmatter</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/creating-safe-spaces-in-sexual-health-discussions-through-rainmatter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/creating-safe-spaces-in-sexual-health-discussions-through-rainmatter/</guid><description>The one important type of health we don&amp;rsquo;t talk about is sexual health for obvious reasons. But the numbers are scary:
Male infertility now accounts for 50% of infertility cases in India.
1 in 10 Indian men experience erectile dysfunction. India has one of the highest rates of untreated STIs globally, especially among youth and migrant populations. 56% of Indian women report some form of sexual dysfunction.
Over the last few years, we&amp;rsquo;ve realised that health issues among Indians have increased and will continue to increase because of poor quality food, air, water, and lifestyles in general.</description></item><item><title>In her Interest, an initiative by Zerodha</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/in-her-interest-an-initiative-by-zerodha/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/in-her-interest-an-initiative-by-zerodha/</guid><description>I still remember that around 2014–15, only 2–3% of our customers were women. Today, that number is about 30%. When I saw this spike, I was surprised and wanted to understand what had changed. So we ran a small survey among a couple of hundred customers.
Roughly 50% of the women use their accounts on their own, while the other 50% have their accounts managed by someone else, such as their husbands, brothers, or children.</description></item><item><title>Appreciating Rainmatter-backed start-ups on National Space Day</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/appreciating-rainmatter-backed-start-ups-on-national-space-day/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/appreciating-rainmatter-backed-start-ups-on-national-space-day/</guid><description>Happy National Space Day! 🇮🇳
Proud of two Rainmatter-backed teams pushing India’s space frontiers:
🚀 Agnikul Cosmos – Fired India’s 1st electric motor-driven semi-cryogenic engine, enabling ultra-precise rocket navigation.
🛰 GalaxEye – Building one of India’s largest private satellites (launch Feb ’26) for all-weather, day/night earth imagery, aiding defence &amp;amp; agriculture.
Cheering for all our space startups! 🚀✨</description></item><item><title>Rainmatter investment in Capitalmind</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-capitalmind/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Aug 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-capitalmind/</guid><description>It is sometimes surreal how life comes full circle.
Deepak Shenoy was among the first people I spoke to about the idea of Zerodha. When we started, he agreed to lend his credibility by having his name on our website as an advisor. 😬
We&amp;rsquo;re happy to be backing him through Rainmatter, as Capitalmind continues its journey of now being an AMC.</description></item><item><title>Prayoga students contribute to Global Science</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/prayoga-students-contribute-to-global-science/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/prayoga-students-contribute-to-global-science/</guid><description>Here&amp;rsquo;s something awesome 😍
Reshma, Lakshmi, Kirat, and Yamini are four young 8th- and 9th-standard girls from rural and socially disadvantaged communities in Karnataka. They published a scientific research paper in a peer-reviewed international journal on an innovative method for synthesizing copper oxide nanoparticles for water purification, with the help of three researchers from Prayoga. What&amp;rsquo;s even more impressive is that these girls are the first in their families to go to school.</description></item><item><title>Sport startups we're proud to support</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sport-startups-were-proud-to-support/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/sport-startups-were-proud-to-support/</guid><description>One of the issues with fitness is that gyms and similar facilities feel boring for a lot of people. I&amp;rsquo;ve always said that a better way to stay fit is to play a sport you enjoy because it won&amp;rsquo;t feel like a chore. Sports are also more accessible for a lot of people.
With this in mind, we&amp;rsquo;ve supported many sports-focused startups that are trying to get more Indians to pick up a sport through Rainmatter.</description></item><item><title>SCRA rules clarified</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scra-rules-clarified/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/scra-rules-clarified/</guid><description>Finally, after clarification of SCRA rules by Ministry of Finance and NSE, brokers can now invest their own funds without exchange approvals or restrictions.
This is huge for Rainmatter. We can now allocate more capital to support Indian startups directly from the brokerage entity.</description></item><item><title>India must bet on research and innovation</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-must-bet-on-research-and-innovation/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/india-must-bet-on-research-and-innovation/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s amazing that despite all the challenges, we&amp;rsquo;re now the 4th largest economy in the world. Having said that, at the risk of sounding like a spoilsport, GDP comparisons only tell you so much.
When you look at important metrics like productivity, labor force participation, and perhaps most importantly, R&amp;amp;D spending, we have a long way to go. India spends just 0.7% of GDP on R&amp;amp;D, while China spends 2.4%, South Korea 4.</description></item><item><title>Rainmatter investment in Zerodor</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-zerodor/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-zerodor/</guid><description>We have been using Zerodor @EkamEco for the men’s urinals at our offices for the last six months or so. Our water bills are down 50%—we did not expect it to be this much.
It seems like a no-brainer for offices, restaurants, etc., where we have managed washrooms.
They were on @sharktankindia around a year back. Here is how it works.
We liked the product because they are doing whatever is necessary to preserve water, which has become supercritical.</description></item><item><title>IISc x Rainmatter</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/iisc-x-rainmatter/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/iisc-x-rainmatter/</guid><description>We recently partnered with the Indian Institute of Science (IISc) to create India’s first Entrepreneur-in-Residence (EIR) Program for longevity.
Longevity isn’t just about living longer—it’s about living better. This program provides an opportunity for scientists, technologists, and aspiring entrepreneurs to build solutions at the intersection of deep science and technology.
India needs accessible and affordable healthcare solutions, and this program serves as a platform to encourage such innovation. The selected teams will work closely with IISc faculty at Longevity and our team at Rainmatter .</description></item><item><title>Nine years of Rainmatter</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nine-years-of-rainmatter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/nine-years-of-rainmatter/</guid><description>At Rainmatter we invested about Rs 275 crores in 47 startups last year. It may seem like we&amp;rsquo;re investing in too many startups, but we aren&amp;rsquo;t a typical VC and don&amp;rsquo;t function like one. We don&amp;rsquo;t take board seats, have no exit clauses, and have a perennial structure (patient capital)—that is, we are in it for the long term.
We may be early, but our thesis right now is that climate and health will be megatrends of the future.</description></item><item><title>Three years of climate action - Rainmatter reflections</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/three-years-of-climate-action-rainmtter-reflections/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/three-years-of-climate-action-rainmtter-reflections/</guid><description>The prelude to starting @RainmatterOrg in 2021, was that we decided to first get our hands dirty and took on a restoration project in 2020. As luck would have it, @zenx was running a campsite on the land, and that&amp;rsquo;s where we met. We hit it off almost immediately, and the Foundation was born.
Three years since we have a solid theme: chasing various intersections of things that impact the climate and the people and lives that it has an effect on.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Money Mindful series</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-money-mindful-series/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-money-mindful-series/</guid><description>Despite all the interest in the stock market after COVID, there are still only 5 crore unique mutual fund investors. I&amp;rsquo;ve said this earlier as well—one of the biggest challenges for the Indian markets is the lack of an advisory ecosystem with just about 900 RIAs.
If you consider mutual fund distributors, there are about 2.7 lakh+ plus, but still not enough. For a broad comparison, there are over 27 lakh+ insurance agents.</description></item><item><title>Rainmatter investment in LWL</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-lwl/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-lwl/</guid><description>I was surprised to learn from Adityaghosh, the former head of IndiGo, that the percentage of women working at IndiGo went from 18% to 43% under his leadership. They also have the highest percentage of women pilots and airport managers worldwide. For pilots, it is 18% for IndiGo, while the global average is just 4%!
This is a problem that even we face in our business, especially in tech, product, and leadership roles.</description></item><item><title>Helping nurture the next generation of Indian athletes</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/helping-nurture-the-next-generation-of-indian-athletes/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/helping-nurture-the-next-generation-of-indian-athletes/</guid><description>I think one of the easiest ways to be healthy is to pick up a sport you like. The one thing that helps people pick up a sport is seeing someone inspiring. Imagine how many Indians play cricket because of Sachin, etc.
Sadly, while there are countless talented athletes in India, not all of them have the resources and ongoing support to make India proud. Is there something that we can do to support more young athletes is something we had been asking ourselves at @Rainmatterin health.</description></item><item><title>Rainmatter investment in SundayGrids</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-sundaygrids/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-investment-in-sundaygrids/</guid><description>Today, if you are interested in installing some solar panels but don&amp;rsquo;t have the roof space necessary because you live in an apartment or a rented house, there&amp;rsquo;s no solution. Despite the subsidies, only about 10% of urban households have rooftop solar. That means many people are conscious about being sustainable but can&amp;rsquo;t do anything. SundayGrids is taking an interesting approach to solve this problem. They setup solar power plants in other locations and allow people to reserve a part of the capacity in the plant.</description></item></channel></rss>