<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rainmatter on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter/</link><description>Recent content in rainmatter on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Partnership with Organic Mandya</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/partnership-with-organic-mandya/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/partnership-with-organic-mandya/</guid><description>Our focus at Rainmatter foundation is to help create green jobs, livelihoods &amp;amp; help preserve the environment using sustainable agri practices. In that journey, we&amp;rsquo;re super delighted to join Madhu Chandan &amp;amp; Organic Mandya on their mission to change farming &amp;amp; improve lives of farmers.
Organic Mandya has helped create kitchen gardens with fruit tree saplings in 5,000+ homes. Through Sunday Santhes in Mandya, they&amp;rsquo;re creating direct farmer to consumer relationships.</description></item><item><title>Podcast with vasanth, Rohan and Anugrah of smallcase.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-podcast-smallcase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-podcast-smallcase/</guid><description>It was in 2016 when Vasanth, Anugrah, and Rohan pitched smallcase. We were quickly sold on their idea of getting users to invest in diversified baskets of stocks or ideas they understood vs single stocks, which reduced their risk.
We had just opened up Kite APIs. The idea was to enable startups to build platforms that could grow the shallow Indian capital market ecosystem.
Today, they&amp;rsquo;ve built an amazing ecosystem of products.</description></item><item><title>A few thoughts on the Zerodha journey so far</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-zerodha-journey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-zerodha-journey/</guid><description>Last 2 years have been spectacular for Zerodha . Lucky to be at right place right time, ready with products &amp;amp; initiatives when there was a surge in retail participation. With success, what I say gets valued more Grimacing faceHere are a few questions that we get asked frequently.
Why haven’t we raised any external capital, especially at times like these when we could get some crazy valuation? I had talked about it earlier</description></item><item><title>Making taxes easy with Vishvajit Sonagara of Quicko</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-taxes-easy-with-vishvajit-sonagara-of-quicko/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-taxes-easy-with-vishvajit-sonagara-of-quicko/</guid><description>A misconception among traders is that you need to file ITR only if you make a profit. Many also don&amp;rsquo;t file since it&amp;rsquo;s quite complex, but Quicko has simplified it drastically. In our new Rainmatter podcast I talk to Vishvajit on their journey.</description></item></channel></rss>