<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rainmatter on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter/</link><description>Recent content in rainmatter on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/rainmatter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Benefits of playing a sport</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/benefits-of-playing-a-sport/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/benefits-of-playing-a-sport/</guid><description>The one thing that has helped me remain sane and deal with the volatility of life is playing a sport regularly. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t just helped me reduce stress and anxiety, but I think it has also improved my cognitive abilities. Also, I&amp;rsquo;m almost forced to make healthier lifestyle choices when playing a sport regularly.
Given the benefits of playing a sport, picking up one If you can is a no-brainer, especially for kids.</description></item><item><title>Rainmatter – Perennial investments</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-perennial-investments/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-perennial-investments/</guid><description>We started Rainmatter in 2016 to support fintech startups working on helping people do better with their money. So far, we have invested ~ Rs 400 crores in 80 startups. In this journey, we realized that having patient Indian investors backing Indian founders is helpful. We&amp;rsquo;re now allocating Rs 1000 crores more to back entrepreneurs building for India.
Good businesses cannot be built overnight, something we learned in our journey. So we are perennial investors and stick with the founders for as long as it takes the founders to build a sustainable business.</description></item><item><title>The importance of long-term support for philanthropy in the social sector</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-long-term-support-for-philanthropy-in-the-social-sector/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/the-importance-of-long-term-support-for-philanthropy-in-the-social-sector/</guid><description>As part of Rainmatter, I get to be in meetings &amp;amp; learn from the smartest people in the social sector, like #ClimateRISE today. The thing I still don&amp;rsquo;t understand is why Philanthropy/CSR is oriented toward funding projects &amp;amp; not supporting organizations over the long-term.
In both profit and non-profit organizations, the odds of creating returns or impact are highest when you find the right founders and give them enough runway to experiment.</description></item><item><title>Using stock market data feeds in gaming apps</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/using-stock-market-data-feeds-in-gaming-apps/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/using-stock-market-data-feeds-in-gaming-apps/</guid><description>Today, YourStory shared that NSE issued a cease and desist letter to all stock gaming apps. We had written about this issue on the Rainmatter blog that using exchange data feeds for gaming involving money is an issue, since regulations don&amp;rsquo;t allow it.
When regulations aren&amp;rsquo;t explicit or clear, it&amp;rsquo;s always better to do things in a regulatorily appropriate way, or always better to assume that you are regulated and do things that regulators would expect.</description></item><item><title>Is fractional share investing possible in India?</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-fractional-investing-possible-in-india/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/is-fractional-investing-possible-in-india/</guid><description>Fractional investing or the ability to invest say $10 in Amazon at $3200 has been the biggest reason for stock market participation to go up in the US. We applied under SEBI regulatory sandbox to launch the same in India. Our learnings by Somnath Mukherjee. We made that application with a startup that had reached out to us Rainmatterin and was rejected.
In the US, stocks bought by customers are held in the street name of the broker, unlike in India, where stocks are held in a customer’s beneficiary account with a depository.</description></item><item><title>Making insurance simple</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-insurance-simple/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-insurance-simple/</guid><description>Insurance unfortunately needs to be hard sold today. The issue is that most don’t understand why they need insurance. Even if they do, it&amp;rsquo;s tough to find unbiased advice. There&amp;rsquo;s just too much choice, complexity, mis-selling, &amp;amp; not to mention spam. Scares away most people.
Even at home, dad has bought a lot of horrible policies as investments vs insurance over the years. We have always wanted to do something about this problem.</description></item><item><title>Tax arbitrage between dividends and selling a stake and startup profitability</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/tax-arbitrage-between-dividends-and-selling-stake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/tax-arbitrage-between-dividends-and-selling-stake/</guid><description>Can the tax arbitrage that exists between earning through dividends(~52%) vs earning through selling a stake (~24%) be the reason why most new-age businesses are not profitable? I think so. Money is like a river, it flows where the conditions are conducive to its flow.
The Govt capping the surcharge on LTCG when investing in unlisted companies to encourage investments in startups in the budget is a welcome move. But maybe the tax arbitrage shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be so large that everyone just focuses on valuations and not on profits &amp;amp; sustainability.</description></item><item><title>Adoption of organic farming</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/organic-farming/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/organic-farming/</guid><description>I keep asking everyone who’s adopted organic farming if yields drop after they stopped using chemicals. In a world where short term gains trump long term improvements, it&amp;rsquo;s tough to see how the shift to organic — even if good for the planet, would happen if yields are lower.
In May, Sri Lanka banned chemical fertiliser and pesticides &amp;amp; went fully organic. There&amp;rsquo;s been an uproar over this move. Some people and groups have even blamed this move for the food crisis there.</description></item><item><title>Organic farming</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/adoption-of-organic-farming/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/adoption-of-organic-farming/</guid><description>I keep asking everyone who’s adopted organic farming if yields drop after they stopped using chemicals. In a world where short term gains trump long term improvements, it&amp;rsquo;s tough to see how the shift to organic — even if good for the planet, would happen if yields are lower
In May, Sri Lanka banned chemical fertiliser and pesticides &amp;amp; went fully organic. There&amp;rsquo;s been an uproar over this move. Some people and groups have even blamed this move for the food crisis there.</description></item><item><title>Partnership with Organic Mandya</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/partnership-with-organic-mandya/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/partnership-with-organic-mandya/</guid><description>Our focus at Rainmatter foundation is to help create green jobs, livelihoods &amp;amp; help preserve the environment using sustainable agri practices. In that journey, we&amp;rsquo;re super delighted to join Madhu Chandan &amp;amp; Organic Mandya on their mission to change farming &amp;amp; improve lives of farmers.
Organic Mandya has helped create kitchen gardens with fruit tree saplings in 5,000+ homes. Through Sunday Santhes in Mandya, they&amp;rsquo;re creating direct farmer to consumer relationships.</description></item><item><title>Podcast with vasanth, Rohan and Anugrah of smallcase.</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-podcast-smallcase/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/rainmatter-podcast-smallcase/</guid><description>It was in 2016 when Vasanth, Anugrah, and Rohan pitched smallcase. We were quickly sold on their idea of getting users to invest in diversified baskets of stocks or ideas they understood vs single stocks, which reduced their risk.
We had just opened up Kite APIs. The idea was to enable startups to build platforms that could grow the shallow Indian capital market ecosystem.
Today, they&amp;rsquo;ve built an amazing ecosystem of products.</description></item><item><title>A few thoughts on the Zerodha journey so far</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-zerodha-journey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/a-few-thoughts-on-the-zerodha-journey/</guid><description>Last 2 years have been spectacular for Zerodha . Lucky to be at right place right time, ready with products &amp;amp; initiatives when there was a surge in retail participation. With success, what I say gets valued more Grimacing faceHere are a few questions that we get asked frequently.
Why haven’t we raised any external capital, especially at times like these when we could get some crazy valuation? I had talked about it earlier</description></item><item><title>Making taxes easy with Vishvajit Sonagara of Quicko</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-taxes-easy-with-vishvajit-sonagara-of-quicko/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/making-taxes-easy-with-vishvajit-sonagara-of-quicko/</guid><description>A misconception among traders is that you need to file ITR only if you make a profit. Many also don&amp;rsquo;t file since it&amp;rsquo;s quite complex, but Quicko has simplified it drastically. In our new Rainmatter podcast I talk to Vishvajit on their journey.</description></item></channel></rss>