<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>varsity on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/varsity/</link><description>Recent content in varsity on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/varsity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Interactive learning with Varsity Live</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/interactive-learning-with-varsity-live/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/interactive-learning-with-varsity-live/</guid><description>We started @ZerodhaVarsity almost a decade ago to simplify how the stock market worked in English and Hindi for free. For people who preferred video, we turned all the modules into video. Today, Varsity is easily one of the most read and watched resources for all things financial markets.
But until now it was self-directed—you had to read, watch, and then learn about things. We had always wanted to introduce an interactive mode of learning about markets, and we finally got around to launching Varsity Live in collaboration with @LearnappHQ.</description></item><item><title>At the Varsity counter at</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/at-the-varsity-counter-at-gff2024/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/at-the-varsity-counter-at-gff2024/</guid><description>At the @ZerodhaVarsity counter at #GFF2024.
No agenda, and only objective of financial education.
Just how we have been running Varsity for 10+ years. 😬</description></item><item><title>Introducing Varsity Live</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-varsity-live/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-varsity-live/</guid><description>If you want to learn anything about trading, investing, and personal finance, I don&amp;rsquo;t think there&amp;rsquo;s a better place than @ZerodhaVarsity. The idea of Varsity began with a random email I sent to @karthikrangappa in 2014, and today, it&amp;rsquo;s one of the most popular free and open resources for all things stock markets, not just in India but maybe globally.
The website has over 15 comprehensive modules and gets millions of hits.</description></item><item><title>Letters from Warren Buffett</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/letters-from-warren-buffet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/letters-from-warren-buffet/</guid><description>Warren Buffett and Charlie Munger are arguably the greatest investors ever. Their track record over 50–60 years is just insane.
Warren Buffett has been writing letters to shareholders since 1965. These letters contain a wealth of wisdom, not just for stockpickers but for all investors as well.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t have the time to read all the letters, we&amp;rsquo;re starting a new series on Varsity to summarize all the letters. Check out the first episode, in which the team discusses the first 5 letters.</description></item><item><title>Varsity junior videos from Tungi</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/varsity-junior-videos-from-tungi/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/varsity-junior-videos-from-tungi/</guid><description>Someone sent me this heartwarming video of kids watching Varsity Junior videos from Tungi, a small village in Bihar with just about 6,000 people 😀</description></item><item><title>Financial Literacy for Rural Women-A film by Zerodha Varsity</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-literacy-for-rural-women-a-film-by-zerodha-varsity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/financial-literacy-for-rural-women-a-film-by-zerodha-varsity/</guid><description>For India to do well, people must know how to manage their money—not just in metros but in smaller towns and villages. One way to ensure people in smaller towns learn a little about money is to teach people there. People naturally share knowledge given the closer bonds there, especially among women.
So @karthikrangappa, through our education initiative, @ZerodhaVarsity ran a two-day workshop in a small town called Chikkodi near the Karnataka-Mahrashtra border in association with Pankh India and Svatah.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Varsity Certified</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-varsity-certified/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-varsity-certified/</guid><description>India can only do well if people are financially literate, &amp;amp; knowing about money is also a life skill. This is why we started @ZerodhaVarsity. The best time to learn is before people learn the wrong things. Why we are excited about Varsity certification.</description></item><item><title>Varsity Bytes</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/varsity-bytes/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/varsity-bytes/</guid><description>Starting a new playlist on Zerodha Varsity Youtube channel to answer some of the frequently asked queries on Varsity. Here is the 1st video about buying a CE vs. selling a PE when you are bullish (talk about lousy timing🙄 )
PS: Watch at 1.5x 😬</description></item></channel></rss>