<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>features on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/features/</link><description>Recent content in features on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Introducing the Stock research platform powered by Tijori</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-stock-research-platform-powered-by-tijori/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-stock-research-platform-powered-by-tijori/</guid><description>We just launched fundamental stock pages powered by Tijori. If you are tracking a stock and want to get a quick snapshot of the financials, news, peer comparisons, and any potential red flags, then this will help.
To dive deeper, you can always go to Tijori&amp;rsquo;s site.</description></item><item><title>Introducing fundamentals widget by Tijori Finance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-fundamentals-widget-by-tijori-finance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-fundamentals-widget-by-tijori-finance/</guid><description>The fundamentals widget on Zerodha is now powered by Tijori. It now has much more financial data about the company to help you make informed decisions.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Timeline and Stock Insights by Tijori Finance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-timeline-and-stock-insights-by-tijori-finance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-timeline-and-stock-insights-by-tijori-finance/</guid><description>We just introduced two new cool features on Zerodhaonline Console: Timeline and Stock Insights, both powered by Tijori.
Timeline
If you invest in stocks, tracking all the events that can affect your investments and developments in one place is hard. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to switch between multiple websites and apps to figure out what happened. This is where the Timeline comes in.
Think of your Timeline on Console as a social media feed, but only with updates about the stocks in your portfolio.</description></item></channel></rss>