<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>features on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/tags/features/</link><description>Recent content in features on Nithin Kamath's personal homepage</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nithinkamath.me/tags/features/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Check IPO lock-in period expiry on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-ipo-lock-in-period-expiry-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/check-ipo-lock-in-period-expiry-on-kite/</guid><description>When a company goes for an IPO, not all shareholders can sell their shares immediately. Certain categories of shareholders like promoters, early investors and ESOP holders have to wait anywhere between 30 days to 18 months before they can sell their shares.
Since these are large shareholders, whenever they sell, there can often be a downward move in the stock price. So if you are buying shares of companies that IPO&amp;rsquo;d recently, you should track when the lock-in period expires.</description></item><item><title>Interoperability on Kite</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/interoperability-on-kite/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/interoperability-on-kite/</guid><description>A feature that many people are unaware of.
You can buy a stock for intraday on NSE and sell it on BSE (or vice versa) to capture arbitrage opportunities if you spot any. Just select the exit exchange from your positions page. Margins get released immediately.
And it can be done regardless of whether you are trading for intraday or holding a stock.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the all-new Kite Marketwatch</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-all-new-kite-marketwatch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-all-new-kite-marketwatch/</guid><description>We just revamped the Kite MarketWatch and made it much cooler.
You can now create custom groups for instruments in your MarketWatch. You can group them based on strategies, themes, sectors, etc. For example, you can have a custom group with all the contracts required for an options strategy like an Iron Condor.
We&amp;rsquo;ve also added pre-built watchlists with all the stocks of broader indices, sector indices, and thematic indices like Bank Nifty.</description></item><item><title>Introducing the Stock pages powered by Tijori</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-stock-pages-powered-by-tijori/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-the-stock-pages-powered-by-tijori/</guid><description>We just launched fundamental stock pages powered by Tijori. If you are tracking a stock and want to get a quick snapshot of the financials, news, peer comparisons, and any potential red flags, then this will help.
To dive deeper, you can always go to Tijori&amp;rsquo;s site.</description></item><item><title>Introducing fundamentals widget by Tijori Finance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-fundamentals-widget-by-tijori-finance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-fundamentals-widget-by-tijori-finance/</guid><description>The fundamentals widget on Zerodha is now powered by Tijori. It now has much more financial data about the company to help you make informed decisions.</description></item><item><title>Introducing Timeline and Stock Insights by Tijori Finance</title><link>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-timeline-and-stock-insights-by-tijori-finance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nithinkamath.me/blog/introducing-timeline-and-stock-insights-by-tijori-finance/</guid><description>We just introduced two new cool features on Zerodhaonline Console: Timeline and Stock Insights, both powered by Tijori.
Timeline
If you invest in stocks, tracking all the events that can affect your investments and developments in one place is hard. You&amp;rsquo;ll have to switch between multiple websites and apps to figure out what happened. This is where the Timeline comes in.
Think of your Timeline on Console as a social media feed, but only with updates about the stocks in your portfolio.</description></item></channel></rss>